<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Beau Bremer&#39;s | Blog</title>
  <subtitle>A collection of articles and thoughts on technology and project management.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/"/>
  <updated>2025-06-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Beau Bremer</name>
    <email>support&amp;#64;beaubremer&amp;#46;com</email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>From Ping to Fix: A Practical Guide to Basic Network Troubleshooting</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/From%20Ping%20to%20Fix/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/From%20Ping%20to%20Fix/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve all been there. An application suddenly can&#39;t reach its server, your connection feels sluggish, or the internet cuts out. Before you spend hours searching forums or calling for help, you can often find the root of the problem yourself with just a few tools and a clear strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide will walk you through a practical approach to network troubleshooting. You&#39;ll learn about three essential commands, a five-step framework for thinking through any problem, and how a conceptual model can make your guesswork much smarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Your Core Troubleshooting Toolkit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of these three commands as your first line of defense. They are simple, powerful, and give you a quick snapshot of the network&#39;s health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. &lt;code&gt;ping&lt;/code&gt;: Is Anyone Home?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;ping&lt;/code&gt; command is the simplest way to check if a remote device is online and reachable. It sends a small packet of data and waits for a reply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to use it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pinging a well-known Google server&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ping 8.8.8.8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you get replies:&lt;/strong&gt; Great! It means there&#39;s a live connection between you and the server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If it times out:&lt;/strong&gt; There&#39;s a problem somewhere between you and the destination. It could be your local network, the server itself, or something in between.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. traceroute: What&#39;s the Path?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If ping fails, traceroute (or tracert on Windows) is your next step. It shows you the specific path, or &amp;quot;hops,&amp;quot; your data takes to get to a destination. This is perfect for spotting exactly where the connection breaks.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How to use it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bash&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tracing the route to Google&#39;s server&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;traceroute 8.8.8.8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll see a list of all the routers your connection passes through. If it stops or shows high latency times at a certain hop, you&#39;ve found a major clue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Port Checking: Is the Service Available?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the server is online (ping works), but the specific service you need (like a database or a web server) isn&#39;t responding. You need to check if the port for that service is open. The command for this varies depending on the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Windows (using PowerShell):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PowerShell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Checks if Google&#39;s web server is responding on the standard HTTPS port (443)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test-NetConnection google.com -Port 443&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On macOS or Linux:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bash&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The -z flag tells nc to scan without sending data, v is for verbose&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nc -zv google.com 443&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &amp;quot;success&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;open&amp;quot; message indicates that the service is active and listening. A failure could indicate that a firewall is blocking the connection or the service is down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Framework for Sanity: The 5-Step &amp;quot;Fixit&amp;quot; Process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commands give you data, but a framework gives you a plan. The Fixit Framework is a systematic approach to diagnosing and solving problems without getting overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Step&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Action&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Goal&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find the Problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Clearly define what&#39;s actually failing. &amp;quot;Users can&#39;t log in&amp;quot; is better than &amp;quot;the network is down.&amp;quot;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inspect the Symptoms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Look for patterns. Does it only happen at 9 AM? Is it only affecting one person or everyone?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclude Possibilities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Rule out what&#39;s working. If you can ping the server, you can probably exclude a full network outage.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement a Hypothesis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Form a theory and test it. &amp;quot;I think the firewall is blocking the port.&amp;quot; Now, run a port check to prove or disprove it.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Track the Fix&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Once you find the solution, write down what you did. This saves you (and your team) from solving the same problem twice.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key thing to remember is that this is a loop, not a straight line. If one hypothesis fails, you just form and test a new one until you find the root cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thinking in Layers: The OSI Model Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make your troubleshooting hypotheses even smarter, you can use a map of how networks function: the &lt;strong&gt;OSI model&lt;/strong&gt;. It organizes networking into seven layers, from the physical wires to the software you use.&lt;br /&gt;
Here are three common ways to use it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Approach&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Starting Layer&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Best For...&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top-Down&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;7 (Application)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;When a single program is failing (e.g., your email client). You start by checking the app&#39;s settings.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom-Up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;1 (Physical)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;When everything is down. You start by checking if the cables are plugged in and the lights on the router are on.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hybrid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;3 (Network/IP)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;A great middle-ground. Start with ping. If it works, the problem is likely in a higher layer (4-7). If it fails, the problem is in a lower layer (1-2).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Network specialists often start from the bottom, while developers might start from the top. The hybrid approach, pivoting from Layer 3, is a powerful strategy for almost everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tying It All Together&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Troubleshooting doesn&#39;t have to be a mystery. By combining the &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; (your core commands), the &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; (the Fixit framework), and the &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt; (the OSI model), you have a complete system for tackling almost any network issue that comes your way. You&#39;re now equipped to diagnose problems methodically and know exactly when it&#39;s the right time to call for backup.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Definitive Guide to a Stable Sonos and Eero Network</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Eero_Sonos/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Eero_Sonos/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve invested in a Sonos sound system and an Eero mesh Wi-Fi network, you were probably expecting a seamless, high-end experience. Instead, you might be pulling your hair out dealing with intermittent audio dropouts, speakers that randomly disappear from the app, or music that refuses to play in grouped rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re not alone, and the good news is your gear isn&#39;t faulty. While Sonos and Eero are officially compatible, they don&#39;t always play nicely without some specific configuration. The problem isn&#39;t a fundamental flaw, but a conflict between two sophisticated mesh systems that can be solved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide will walk you through the solutions, from foundational fixes that address 90% of issues to advanced tweaks for complex setups. Let&#39;s get your system running reliably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start Here: The 4 Non-Negotiable Rules for Stability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you do anything else, you need to establish a solid network foundation. These four steps address the most common and disruptive sources of conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eliminate Double NAT (The #1 Culprit):&lt;/strong&gt; Most issues where the Sonos app can&#39;t find your system are caused by &amp;quot;Double NAT.&amp;quot; This happens when your ISP&#39;s modem/router and your Eero system are both trying to manage your network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fix:&lt;/strong&gt; Log into your ISP&#39;s modem/router and enable &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;Bridge Mode.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; This turns off its routing functions and lets your Eero act as the single, true router for your home. This creates a &amp;quot;flat&amp;quot; network where all your devices can see each other properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reserve IP Addresses:&lt;/strong&gt; Your router assigns temporary (&amp;quot;dynamic&amp;quot;) IP addresses to your devices. If these change, your Sonos app can lose track of a speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fix:&lt;/strong&gt; In the Eero app, go to each of your Sonos devices and set a &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;DHCP Reservation&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;Reserve IP.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; This makes its IP address permanent, eliminating a common cause of disappearing speakers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disable Eero Labs:&lt;/strong&gt; The experimental features in &amp;quot;Eero Labs&amp;quot; can be unstable and are a known source of conflicts with Sonos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fix:&lt;/strong&gt; In the Eero app, navigate to &lt;code&gt;Discover &amp;gt; Eero Labs&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;turn off everything&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obey the &amp;quot;Golden Rule&amp;quot; of Wiring:&lt;/strong&gt; If you connect more than one Sonos product to your network with an Ethernet cable, they &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; all connect back to the &lt;em&gt;same&lt;/em&gt; Eero node or the &lt;em&gt;same&lt;/em&gt; network switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning:&lt;/strong&gt; Never wire Sonos products into different satellite Eero nodes. This can create a &amp;quot;broadcast storm&amp;quot; that crashes your entire network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Great Debate: Eero Wi-Fi (WM:1) vs. SonosNet (WM:0)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After setting the foundation, you face a core choice: should your Sonos speakers connect directly to your Eero Wi-Fi, or should they use Sonos&#39;s own mesh network, SonosNet? You can see which mode your system is in by checking the &amp;quot;About My System&amp;quot; section of the Sonos app. &lt;code&gt;WM:1&lt;/code&gt; is Wi-Fi, &lt;code&gt;WM:0&lt;/code&gt; is SonosNet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case for Eero Wi-Fi (WM:1 - The Modern Approach)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the default, all-wireless setup, where every Sonos speaker connects to your Eero network, just like a laptop or phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why use it?&lt;/strong&gt; Modern Eero systems (especially Wi-Fi 6/6E) are incredibly fast and efficient, potentially offering better performance than the older SonosNet protocol. This is also the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; way to connect modern speakers like the Roam, Move, and the Era series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best for:&lt;/strong&gt; Users with new Eero and Sonos hardware in homes with low Wi-Fi congestion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case for SonosNet (WM:0 - The Classic Fix)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This setup is created by connecting &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; Sonos product (a speaker or a Sonos Boost) to your gateway Eero with an Ethernet cable. This device then creates a separate, private 2.4GHz wireless network exclusively for your other Sonos speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why use it?&lt;/strong&gt; SonosNet isolates your sensitive audio traffic from all the other Wi-Fi noise in your house. It&#39;s the most proven and effective fix for dropouts and issues with grouped speakers, especially in busy network environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best for:&lt;/strong&gt; Users with older hardware, high Wi-Fi interference, or anyone experiencing stubborn dropouts and stereo pair failures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;SonosNet (Wired Setup - WM:0)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Eero Wi-Fi (Wireless Setup - WM:1)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How it Works&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;One Sonos product is wired to the network, creating a dedicated, private mesh for other Sonos speakers.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;All Sonos speakers connect to the Eero mesh network as individual clients.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primary Advantage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Isolates audio traffic from general network congestion, dramatically improving stability in most cases.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Leverages the superior speed and features of the modern Eero mesh.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primary Disadvantage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Slower, legacy protocol. It can cause network loops if wired incorrectly.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Performance is susceptible to general Wi-Fi interference and router settings.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Consideration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Incompatible with Sonos Move, Roam, and Era speakers, forcing a &amp;quot;mixed mode.&amp;quot;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Requires a robust and healthy Eero network to work reliably.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation:&lt;/strong&gt; Start with the modern Eero Wi-Fi (WM:1) setup. If you experience any instability, switching to SonosNet (WM:0) is the most reliable next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Quick Troubleshooting Guide&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve followed the rules above and still have issues, here’s how to tackle specific symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptom: Intermittent Audio Dropouts or Disappearing Speakers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cause:&lt;/strong&gt; Usually Wi-Fi interference, IP conflicts, or incorrect wiring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Solution:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Double-check the &amp;quot;Golden Rule&amp;quot; of wiring.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure you&#39;ve reserved IP addresses for all Sonos devices.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Switch your setup.&lt;/strong&gt; If you&#39;re on Wi-Fi (WM:1), switch to SonosNet (WM:0) by wiring one speaker to your main Eero. If you&#39;re already on an unstable SonosNet, try going fully wireless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a test,&lt;/strong&gt; temporarily disable &amp;quot;Client Steering&amp;quot; in your Eero&#39;s advanced settings. This can sometimes help older 2.4GHz-only Sonos devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptom: Sonos App Cannot Find the System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cause:&lt;/strong&gt; Almost always Double NAT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Solution:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Put your ISP modem/router in Bridge Mode.&lt;/strong&gt; This is the definitive fix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure your phone is on your main Eero Wi-Fi, not a guest network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On iOS, check that the Sonos app has &amp;quot;Local Network&amp;quot; permission and that &amp;quot;Private Wi-Fi Address&amp;quot; is disabled for your Eero network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptom: Grouped Rooms or Stereo Pairs Fail&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cause:&lt;/strong&gt; Speakers in a group need to talk to each other directly. On a mesh network, Eero might place them on different Wi-Fi bands or nodes, breaking this link.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Solution:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Switch to SonosNet (WM:0).&lt;/strong&gt; This is the most reliable fix for this specific problem. It consolidates all your speakers onto a single, dedicated network layer, ensuring they can communicate seamlessly for perfect synchronization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting Eero and Sonos to work in perfect harmony is less about luck and more about deliberate, informed configuration. By establishing a clean network foundation and making a conscious choice between a pure Wi-Fi or SonosNet setup, you can build a system that&#39;s powerful, stable, and delivers the premium experience you paid for.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The  Unknown  Art Of  Freestyle  Mic  Checking</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/the%20Unknown%20Art%20of%20Freestyle%20Mic%20Checking/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/the%20Unknown%20Art%20of%20Freestyle%20Mic%20Checking/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h3&gt;The Unknown Art of Freestyle Mic Checking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ve heard it a million times at events: &amp;quot;Check, one, two... check, one, two...&amp;quot; It&#39;s the universal signal that sound is being tested, a little sonic ritual before the show kicks off. For those of us behind the mixer, that simple phrase is often just the opening act for an elaborate, unscripted performance known as the &amp;quot;freestyle mic check.&amp;quot; And let me tell you, it&#39;s an unknown art form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Beyond &amp;quot;One, Two&amp;quot;: The Creative Pressure Cooker&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, we could say &amp;quot;check, check&amp;quot; repeatedly. But where&#39;s the fun in that? And more importantly, how do you really &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; a microphone sounds good until someone says something a little more, well, human? This is where the magic (and sometimes mild panic) happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine this: The venue is quiet. The client is milling about. Maybe the band is watching. The pressure is on to make sure that the mic sounds perfect. And you, the intrepid sound engineer, have to conjure something – anything – to say into it. It’s not just about level and clarity; it&#39;s about making sure it sounds good when someone is actually &lt;em&gt;talking&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, you start. &amp;quot;Testing, testing, one, two, three, testing.&amp;quot; kOay, standard. However, you then need to stretch it out. You need to hit different vocal ranges, project a little, maybe even whisper. This is where the improv kicks in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Unwritten Rules of Mic Check Improv&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no official classes for this, no textbooks on &amp;quot;Advanced Mic Check Banter.&amp;quot; It’s learned on the job, a quiet rite of passage. Here&#39;s a peek into the unwritten rules and common tactics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Weather Report:&lt;/strong&gt; A classic for a reason. &amp;quot;Looks like it&#39;s going to be a beautiful day here in Chicago, folks. A little humidity, but nothing we can&#39;t handle.&amp;quot; Reliable, relatable, and gets enough varied sounds out of your voice. * * &lt;em&gt;Counting Past Ten (Creatively):&lt;/em&gt;* Beyond the basics, you might hear things like, &amp;quot;One thousand one, one thousand two... are we sure this thing is on?&amp;quot; Or counting in another language if you&#39;re feeling fancy. * &lt;strong&gt;Reciting Nonsense:&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes, sheer desperation leads to poetry. Or, you know, just listing off groceries. &amp;quot;Milk, bread, eggs, slightly bruised bananas for the crew...&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fake Announcements:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;quot;Ladies and gentlemen, please remember to silence your cell phones, unless, of course, you&#39;re expecting an incredibly important call about a winning lottery ticket.&amp;quot; * &lt;strong&gt;The Existential Question:&lt;/strong&gt; For the more philosophical engineer. &amp;quot;What &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; sound, really? Is it just vibrations? Or is it a feeling... a connection?&amp;quot; (Best delivered with a straight face.) * &lt;strong&gt;Self-Commentary:&lt;/strong&gt; This is where the tongue-in-cheek really shines. &amp;quot;Man, I really need some coffee. Is this thing making my voice sound deeper, or is that just me?&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key is to keep it going without drawing too much attention. You&#39;re trying to make the mic sound good, not launch a stand-up comedy career. It’s a delicate balance of projecting confidence while subtly making up words on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Payoff: Seamless Sound&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this impromptu chattering, this vocal gymnastics, serves a crucial purpose: it helps us fine-tune the audio system. We listen for feedback, adjust equalization for different voices, and ensure that when the actual presenter steps up, their message comes through crystal clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the next time you hear that &amp;quot;check, one, two,&amp;quot; remember the unsung heroes of the sound world. We’re not just plugging things in; we&#39;re also quietly, creatively, and sometimes awkwardly, ensuring every word sounds perfect. It&#39;s truly an unknown art.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Stop Worrying and Start Branching: A Guide to Safer Development</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Stop%20Worrying%20and%20Start%20Branching/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Stop%20Worrying%20and%20Start%20Branching/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re deep in concentration, adding a new feature to your website, when you suddenly realize... you&#39;ve broken everything. The page won&#39;t load, styles are a mess, and that familiar panic sets in. I&#39;ve definitely been there. For too long, I did all my work directly on the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch—the one my live site was built from. Every change was a high-stakes gamble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I embraced a professional workflow that brought a new level of safety and confidence to my work: &lt;strong&gt;Git branching&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of your &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch as the &amp;quot;golden copy&amp;quot; of your project. It&#39;s the version that is live, working, and stable. A branch is a parallel copy of your project where you can experiment freely. If your new idea works, you merge it into the golden copy. If it&#39;s a disaster, you delete the branch, and &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; remains untouched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It brings peace of mind to the development process. Here’s why you should be using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why Bother with Branches?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might seem like a few extra steps, but the benefits are enormous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protect Your Live Site:&lt;/strong&gt; Your &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch is always protected. You can be confident that it&#39;s in a deployable, working state at all times. No more &amp;quot;I just broke the live site!&amp;quot; panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experiment Freely:&lt;/strong&gt; Want to try a new layout or a wild idea? Create a branch! You can make a mess, try things out, and break whatever you want without any risk to your core project. If it doesn&#39;t work out, there&#39;s no harm done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay Organized:&lt;/strong&gt; Create a separate branch for each new feature or bug fix. This keeps your work isolated and easy to track. For example, &lt;code&gt;feature/new-contact-form&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;fix/mobile-menu-bug&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easier Collaboration and Code Reviews:&lt;/strong&gt; If you work on a team, branches are essential for facilitating easier collaboration and code reviews. Even for solo developers, they allow you to use Pull Requests on GitHub to review your work before merging. It&#39;s a great way to catch your own mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;My 5-Step Branching Workflow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make this concrete, let me walk you through a real-world example. I recently wanted to change the main header link on my blog. On the homepage, it should point to my main portfolio, but on individual posts, it should point back to the blog&#39;s index. This was a perfect use case for a feature branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the exact workflow I followed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1: Start from a Clean Slate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before starting anything new, I always make sure my local project is in sync with the latest version on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# First, switch to your main branch
git checkout main

# Then, pull the latest changes from GitHub (your remote &#39;origin&#39;)
git pull origin main

Step 2: Create Your New Branch

Next, I created a new branch and immediately switched to it. I gave it a descriptive name so I&#39;d know its purpose.

# Create a new branch and immediately switch to it (-b does both!)
git checkout -b feature/contextual-header-link

Step 3: Do the Work

On this new, safe branch, I edited my layout file (_includes/layouts/base.njk) to add the logic for the contextual link. I made a few small, focused commits along the way to save my progress.

# Stage all modified files for the commit
git add .

# Commit your changes with a clear, descriptive message
git commit -m &amp;quot;feat: Make header link contextual&amp;quot;

Step 4: Open a Pull Request

Once I was happy with how it worked on my local machine, I pushed the new branch up to my GitHub repository.

# The -u flag sets the upstream branch, so you can just use `git push` next time
git push -u origin feature/contextual-header-link

Then, I went to my project on the GitHub website and opened a Pull Request (PR). A PR is a formal way of proposing your changes. It’s a request to pull your new code from the feature/contextual-header-link branch into the main branch.

Step 5: Merge and Clean Up

The Pull Request page on GitHub showed me a summary of all my changes, which I could review one last time. Everything looked good, so I clicked the &amp;quot;Merge pull request&amp;quot; button. This safely merged my work into the main and, in my case, automatically triggered a new deployment to Netlify.

After merging, I deleted the feature branch to keep my repository tidy and signal that the work on that specific feature was complete. The work is now safely part of the main branch.

This whole process might seem like extra work at first, but it&#39;ll quickly become a natural part of your routine. It provides a structure for safer, more organized development. Give it a try on your very next task, no matter how small!&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>More Than Just Plugging In</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/More%20Than%20Just%20Plugging%20In/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/More%20Than%20Just%20Plugging%20In/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h3&gt;More Than Just Plugging In: What a Live Production Team Really Does Before the Doors Open&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you attend a fantastic gala or a smooth corporate event, everything just seems to flow. The lighting perfectly sets the mood, the sound is crystal clear whether it&#39;s a keynote speaker or a band, and the visuals on screen are sharp and engaging. It all looks effortless, almost like magic. But here&#39;s a little secret: that &amp;quot;magic&amp;quot; isn&#39;t accidental. It&#39;s the meticulous result of a dedicated live production team working tirelessly behind the scenes, long before the first guest even steps through the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people only see the polished final product, unaware of the weeks, sometimes months, of intricate planning and the intense hours of setup and programming behind it. Ever wonder how that seamless experience truly comes to life? Let&#39;s pull back the curtain and show you what really goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Blueprint: Pre-Production Planning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before a single piece of equipment is even loaded onto a truck, the groundwork is laid. This is the strategic phase where visions turn into detailed plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial Consultations &amp;amp; Needs Assessment:&lt;/strong&gt; Our first step is always to understand the client&#39;s vision thoroughly. What&#39;s the core message of the event? What&#39;s the desired mood? Who is the audience? What are the key goals, and, of course, what&#39;s the budget we&#39;re working with?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Site Visits &amp;amp; Venue Scouting:&lt;/strong&gt; We physically visit the venue to assess everything from power availability and rigging points for lights and speakers, to room acoustics, sightlines for screens, and even the logistics of getting gear in and out via loading docks. This helps us identify and plan around any potential challenges, like low ceilings or strict venue rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Design &amp;amp; System Architecture:&lt;/strong&gt; This is where the engineers get to work. We create detailed blueprints – including CAD drawings that show equipment placement and signal flow diagrams that map out every cable connection for audio, video, and lighting. We specify the exact equipment needed, from the type of microphones and projectors to the specific lighting fixtures and camera packages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content Development &amp;amp; Integration:&lt;/strong&gt; We often work closely with clients to ensure all their video playback, presentation slides, and custom graphics are ready. This means making sure everything from speaker slides to custom intro videos is in the correct format, resolution, and aspect ratio for the chosen display systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Permitting &amp;amp; Logistics:&lt;/strong&gt; There&#39;s a lot of paperwork involved, too! We manage venue regulations, ensure compliance with fire marshal requirements, and navigate union rules if applicable. We also coordinate precise loading and unloading schedules to minimize disruptions and ensure seamless operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Build: Load-in &amp;amp; Setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the planning is locked, it&#39;s time for the physical transformation of the space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Early Birds: Rigging &amp;amp; Power:&lt;/strong&gt; Often, the rigging team is the first on site, safely hanging speaker arrays and lighting trusses from the ceiling. Simultaneously, the power team is running heavy-duty cables to establish the main power distribution for all the equipment. Safety is paramount here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equipment Unload &amp;amp; Prep:&lt;/strong&gt; Hundreds, often thousands, of pounds of gear arrive in meticulously packed cases. Each piece is carefully unloaded, unpacked, inventoried, and double-checked to ensure it&#39;s in perfect working order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System Deployment &amp;amp; Cabling:&lt;/strong&gt; This is where the space begins to take shape, coming together like a puzzle. Miles of cables for audio, video, data, and power are meticulously run – always neatly, safely, and out of sight, transforming an empty space into a functional event environment. Speakers are hoisted, screens are built, projectors are mounted, cameras are positioned, and the complex control consoles are set up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stage &amp;amp; Set Construction:&lt;/strong&gt; While the tech goes in, the physical environment of the show also takes shape. Staging is built, backdrops are put into place, and scenic elements that define the event&#39;s look are assembled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Polish: Programming &amp;amp; Testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where the artistry and the technical precision truly merge, often for hours on end, refining every detail before the doors open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lighting Programming:&lt;/strong&gt; Lighting designers spend hours, sometimes days, programming cues for every moment of the event. They craft looks for guest arrival, dramatic entrances, awards presentations, musical performances, and speeches, using light to set the mood, highlight key individuals, and create immersive environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audio Tuning &amp;amp; Sound Checks: The Unseen Foundation of Clarity&lt;/strong&gt; This is far more than just turning on a microphone and hoping for the best. It&#39;s about meticulously shaping the sound to suit the room&#39;s unique acoustics and the specific needs of the event.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker Optimization:&lt;/strong&gt; Our audio engineers use specialized software and measurement microphones to analyze how the speakers interact with the room. This helps eliminate harsh frequencies and prevents echoes, ensuring even sound distribution so every guest hears clearly, regardless of their seating position. It’s about making sure the sound system itself is performing optimally in that space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microphone Management:&lt;/strong&gt; Each microphone – whether for a CEO, a panelist, or a singer – undergoes individual testing. We set appropriate gain levels, check for potential feedback (that dreaded squeal!), and apply equalization (EQ) to ensure voices are warm, clear, and cut through any background noise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System Integrity:&lt;/strong&gt; This critical phase also catches any loose cables, faulty equipment, or unexpected hums and buzzes that could completely derail a presentation or a musical act. It&#39;s about creating a robust and pristine sonic environment where every sound element can shine without distraction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video Playback &amp;amp; Switching Tests:&lt;/strong&gt; We thoroughly test all video sources, including pre-recorded content, live camera feeds, and speaker presentations. Every transition is practiced, ensuring seamless switching between different inputs during the show.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Show File Creation &amp;amp; Backup:&lt;/strong&gt; All the painstaking programming for lighting, audio, and video is saved as &amp;quot;show files.&amp;quot; Crucially, multiple redundant backups are created to protect against any unforeseen technical glitches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rehearsals with Talent/Presenters: The Critical Dry Run&lt;/strong&gt;
This is perhaps the most underestimated phase, and yet, it&#39;s absolutely crucial for a smooth show. Many outside of production might see it as an unnecessary added step, but it&#39;s where theoretical planning meets real-world execution.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cue-to-Cue (C2C):&lt;/strong&gt; This is where the entire technical team practices every single lighting change, video playback, sound cue, and camera shot in precise sequence. It&#39;s about perfecting the timing and flow of the show, ensuring everyone on the team is perfectly synchronized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working with Presenters:&lt;/strong&gt; For speakers, performers, and hosts, rehearsals are vital. They get comfortable with the stage layout, the lectern, the microphone technique, and how to advance their slides. This practice helps them feel confident and allows the production team to anticipate their needs – like when they might move to a different part of the stage or need a specific video cued up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Troubleshooting Live:&lt;/strong&gt; Crucially, rehearsals are the ideal time to identify and address potential issues before the audience arrives. A speaker might realize their remote isn&#39;t working from where they stand, or a video might not play correctly – all these potential pitfalls can be identified and fixed in a rehearsal, preventing awkward pauses, technical glitches, or embarrassing moments during the actual event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building Confidence:&lt;/strong&gt; For both the production team and the talent on stage, rehearsals build immense confidence. Everyone knows their role, the timing is locked in, and the performance can be delivered flawlessly, allowing the presenters to focus on their message and the audience to enjoy the experience without interruption.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ready for Showtime!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the goal of a live production team is simple yet profound: to seamlessly transform a client&#39;s vision into an unforgettable reality for every single attendee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the next time you&#39;re at an event and find yourself marveling at how perfectly everything runs, take a moment to remember the dedicated team behind the scenes. They’re the ones who made that &amp;quot;magic&amp;quot; happen, meticulously planning and executing long before you ever took your seat. It truly is &amp;quot;more than just plugging in.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keep  Calm And  Troubleshoot  On</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Keep%20Calm%20and%20Troubleshoot%20On/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Keep%20Calm%20and%20Troubleshoot%20On/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Keep Calm and Troubleshoot On: A Guide to Not Panicking When the Servers Are on Fire&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s 3:17 A.M., and an alert just shattered your peaceful sleep. A critical system is down, and you can already feel the panic starting to bubble up. In these moments, it’s easy to think that the solution lies in typing faster or knowing more obscure commands. But hwat if the most powerful tool you have is simply a calm, focused mind?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that staying cool under pressure isn&#39;t just a personality trait; it&#39;s a skill you can learn. Let&#39;s break down how to handle the heat without getting burned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Why Your Brain Shuts Down When the Server Does&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever notice how it’s suddenly impossible to remember a simple command when your boss is standing over oyur shoulder? That&#39;s not a personal failure; it&#39;s biology. When you get stressed, your body oges into &amp;quot;fight or flight&amp;quot; mode, flooding your system with hormones like cortisol and adrenaline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This response is fantastic if you need to outrun a saber-toothed tiger, but it&#39;s terrible for debugging a complex system. These stress hormones actively sabotage the parts of your brain responsible for problem-solving, memory, and decision-making. In other words, the pressure that&#39;s meant to speed you up actually makes you less effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Your Mental Emergency Brake: The STOP Skill&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how do you fight back against your biology? You can start with a simple but powerful tool called the DBT STOP skill. The next time you feel overwhelmed, just run through these four steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S - Stop:&lt;/strong&gt; Seriously, just stop. Don&#39;t type another command. Don’t say another word. Just freeze for a second to break the cycle of panic. * &lt;strong&gt;T - Take a Breath:&lt;/strong&gt; Take one deliberate, deep breath. This is a direct physioolgical intervention that tells your nervous system it’s time to chill out by activating the parasympathetic nervous system. * &lt;strong&gt;O - Observe:&lt;/strong&gt; Take a quick, non-judgmental look at what’s going on. What are you thinking? What are you feeling? What&#39;s the reality of the situation? * &lt;strong&gt;P - Proceed Mindfully:&lt;/strong&gt; Now that you&#39;ve interrupted the panic, you can choose your next move intentionally instead of just reacting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Find the &amp;quot;Why&amp;quot; with a Simple Method&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panic loves chaos, but a structured process brings order. One of the simplest and most effective methods for getting to the heart of an issue is the &amp;quot;5 Whys&amp;quot; tehcnique. It’s exactly what it sounds like: you just ekep asking &amp;quot;Why?&amp;quot; until you move past the symptoms and find the real source of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a website is down:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Why is it down? ** Because the web servers are unhealthy. &amp;gt; 2. **Why are they unhealthy? ** Because the web server process crashed. &amp;gt; 3. **Why did it crash? ** Because the server ran out of memory. &amp;gt; 4. **Why did it run out of memory? ** Because a log file grew until it filled up all the disk space. &amp;gt; 5. &lt;strong&gt;Why did the log file get so big?&lt;/strong&gt; Because a recent code change accidentally left vebrose debugging on in the live environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without this process, you might have just restarted the server at step #2, only for it to crash again. The &amp;quot;5 Whys&amp;quot; guides you straight to the root cause, which was actually a procedural failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Managing the Humans&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technical problems always nivolve people, and people have anxieties. A huge part of your job during a crisis is managing their stress so you can focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key is proactive communication. Send out regular updates, even if the update is just, &amp;quot;We&#39;re still investigating&amp;quot;. This fills the information vacuum and shows you&#39;re in control. When someone demands a time for the fix, it’s better to explain your process than to give a deadline you can&#39;t guarantee. Try something like, &amp;quot;Right now, our focus is on analyzing the logs to find the source. I&#39;ll have another update in 15 minutes&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mastering these skills—managing your panic, sticking to a method, and communicating clearly—is what separates the pros from the rest. It helps you not only survive the fire but also emerge as a more resilient and respected professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you can&#39;t figure it out after all that? Well, how many programmers does it take to change a light bulb? * None*, taht&#39;s a hardware problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dive into QLab</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/dive_Qlab/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/dive_Qlab/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Dive into QLab: Your New Best Friend for Show Control!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone! Ever wondered how those amazing live shows, plays, or even presentations manage to switch between music, video, and lights flawlessly? Often, the seamless magic behind the scenes is all thanks to a fantastic piece of software called QLab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QLab is a powerful tool for show control, used by professionals and hobbyists alike to create incredibly precise and complex cue lists. But don&#39;t let &amp;quot;powerful&amp;quot; scare you off – especially since you can download a feature-rich free version! It&#39;s also incredibly intuitive once you get the hang of it, and it can elevate your projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we&#39;re going to take a super quick look at QLab and then dive into one of its most common uses: adding music cues. Get ready to make your audio playback smooth as silk!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Getting Started with QLab&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First things first, if you don&#39;t have QLab, you can download it for free from the Figure 53 website. The free version, called QLab Free, offers a wide range of features, particularly for audio playback, making it ideal for getting started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you open QLab, you&#39;ll see a clean workspace. This is where you&#39;ll build your &amp;quot;cue list,&amp;quot; which is essentially a chronological list of everything you want to happen during your show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Quick Tutorial: Adding Music Cues in QLab&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s get straight to it and add some music!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Open Your Workspace&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you open QLab, you&#39;ll usually be presented with a new, blank workspace. This is your canvas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Drag and Drop Your Audio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to get music into QLab is to drag an audio file (like an MP3, WAV, or AIFF) directly from your computer&#39;s folders into the QLab window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip:&lt;/strong&gt; Use uncompressed audio files with Qlab (like WAV or AIFF) for the best quality and performance, but MP3s work just fine for many applications, especially for getting started.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Meet Your First Cue&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you drag in an audio file, QLab automatically creates an &amp;quot;Audio Cue&amp;quot; for it. You&#39;ll see it appear in your cue list. Each cue has a &amp;quot;Q Number&amp;quot; (its position in the list) and a &amp;quot;Q Name&amp;quot; (usually the file name by default).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. The Inspector – Your Control Panel&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below your cue list, you&#39;ll see the &amp;quot;Inspector&amp;quot; panel. This is your control hub, where all the magic happens! When you select a cue, the Inspector dynamically updates to show you all the properties and settings for that specific cue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For an audio cue, you&#39;ll see tabs like &amp;quot;Levels&amp;quot; (for volume), &amp;quot;Time &amp;amp; Loops&amp;quot; (for start/end times and looping), and &amp;quot;Audio&amp;quot; (for routing to different outputs).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Setting Playback&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; Go to the &amp;quot;Levels&amp;quot; tab in the Inspector. You can adjust the overall volume of your music cue here using the fader. (And yes, you can create smooth fades in and out later, but for now, just set a static level!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start and End Times:&lt;/strong&gt; In the &amp;quot;Time &amp;amp; Loops&amp;quot; tab, you can set exactly when your audio starts and ends within the file. This is super handy if you only want to play a specific section of a song. Just drag the start and end markers on the waveform, or type in specific times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;6. Playing Your Cue&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;Go&amp;quot; Button:&lt;/strong&gt; The big &amp;quot;Go&amp;quot; button at the bottom of the QLab window is your best friend. Click it (or press the Spacebar, which is the default hotkey) to trigger the selected cue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop Button:&lt;/strong&gt; Need to stop a cue? Click the &amp;quot;Stop&amp;quot; button next to &amp;quot;Go.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What&#39;s Next?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just the tip of the iceberg with QLab, but understanding how to add and control basic audio cues is a huge first step. From here, you can explore:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fades:&lt;/strong&gt; Make your music fade in and out smoothly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cue Triggers:&lt;/strong&gt; How to automatically trigger cues, or link them to other cues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hotkeys:&lt;/strong&gt; Assigning keyboard shortcuts for quick playback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Groups:&lt;/strong&gt; Organizing multiple cues together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While QLab might seem a little intimidating at first glance, I promise you, once you start playing around with it, you&#39;ll quickly discover how powerful and genuinely &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt; it is. It truly opens up a world of possibilities for controlling your live events with precision and creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy cueing!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Essential Git: Part 2: Safely Undoing Changes with git revert</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Essential_Git_Revert/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Essential_Git_Revert/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Working with Git is fantastic for managing your code, but sometimes, you push changes you later realize aren&#39;t quite right.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe a feature introduced a bug, or a configuration change is causing problems. When this happens, &lt;code&gt;git revert&lt;/code&gt; comes to the rescue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a super important tool, especially when you&#39;ve already shared your work (like pushing to a remote repository or deploying to a service like Vercel).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;git revert&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, &lt;code&gt;git revert&lt;/code&gt; creates new commits that undo the changes from previous commits. It&#39;s like writing an &amp;quot;undo&amp;quot; commit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key difference from other Git commands like &lt;code&gt;git reset&lt;/code&gt; is that &lt;code&gt;git revert&lt;/code&gt; does not rewrite your project&#39;s history. Instead, it adds new history that cancels out the old. This makes it a much safer option when:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&#39;ve already pushed your commits to a shared remote repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&#39;re working on a public branch (like &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to maintain a clear, linear history of changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When to Use &lt;code&gt;git revert&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of &lt;code&gt;git revert&lt;/code&gt; as your go-to for &amp;quot;undoing&amp;quot; when:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&#39;ve pushed a bad commit:&lt;/strong&gt; This is exactly what we just experienced. If you have a commit causing issues on your live Vercel site, reverting it safely brings you back without erasing the fact that the commit ever existed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You want to undo specific commits in your history:&lt;/strong&gt; You can pick and choose which commits to undo, even if they&#39;re not the very last ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You need to collaborate:&lt;/strong&gt; Since it doesn&#39;t rewrite history, &lt;code&gt;git revert&lt;/code&gt; is polite to your teammates&#39; repositories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step-by-Step Tutorial: Reverting a Commit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s walk through how to use &lt;code&gt;git revert&lt;/code&gt; to undo a specific commit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 1: Identify the Commit to Revert&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, you need to find the commit hash (the unique ID) of the commit you want to undo. This should be the commit that introduced the changes you want to reverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open your terminal or Git Bash in your project&#39;s root directory and run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;git log


This command shows you your project&#39;s commit history, with the most recent commits at the top. Scroll down until you find the commit you want to undo. The commit hash is the long string of characters next to commit (e.g., 71a224ee41eec4599329bb65c893de855d441f62).
Once you&#39;ve found it, copy its full hash.



```markdown
#### Step 2: Perform the Revert

Now, use the `git revert` command with the commit hash you copied.

```bash
git revert &amp;lt;commit-hash&amp;gt;


Replace &amp;lt;commit-hash&amp;gt; with the actual hash.
What happens next?
Git will attempt to reverse the changes introduced by that commit.
If the revert is straightforward (no conflicts), Git will automatically prepare a new commit for you.
Step 3: Handle the Commit Message
When git revert prepares a new commit, it will automatically open your default Git editor (like Vim or Nano in the terminal, or potentially VS Code if configured) with a pre-filled commit message. This message typically starts with &amp;quot;Revert&amp;quot; and includes information about the commit you&#39;re undoing.
You can accept the default message as is.
You can add your own notes to explain why you&#39;re reverting.
To save and exit the commit message:
If it&#39;s Vim: Press the Esc key, then type :wq and press Enter.
If it&#39;s Nano, press Ctrl+X, then Y to confirm saving, and then press Enter.
Once you save and exit, Git will create the new &amp;quot;revert&amp;quot; commit.
Step 4: Push Your Reverted Changes
Finally, push your new revert commit to your remote repository (e.g., GitHub, GitLab, or Vercel).

Bash


git push


This will update your remote branch, and if you&#39;re using Vercel, it will trigger a new deployment with the reverted code.
Troubleshooting Common git revert Issues
Sometimes, git revert isn&#39;t a smooth ride. Here are the most common bumps you might hit and how to fix them:
Issue 1: Merge Conflicts (CONFLICT (content): Merge conflict in &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;)
This is what we faced! It means Git found changes in the commit you&#39;re reverting that overlap with other changes made since that commit. Git doesn&#39;t know which version to keep, so it asks you to decide.
How to fix it:
Identify the Conflict: Git will tell you which files have conflicts (e.g., script.js). Open these files in your code editor.
Look for Conflict Markers: Inside the conflicted file, you&#39;ll see special markers like this:
&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; HEAD
// Code from your current branch (your latest work)
=======
// Code from the commit you are trying to revert (the older version)
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;commit-hash-of-reverted-commit&amp;gt;





```markdown
    * **Manually Resolve:**
        * Delete the Git conflict markers (`&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;`, `=======`, `&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;`).
        * Edit the code within that section. Since you&#39;re trying to undo, you&#39;ll typically want to delete the code that was introduced by the commit you&#39;re reverting (the part between `=======` and `&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;`) and keep the `HEAD` version, or combine them as needed to achieve the desired state of the file without the problematic changes.
        * Save the file.

    * **Stage the Resolved File:** After fixing the file and saving it, you must tell Git that you&#39;ve resolved the conflict:

        ```bash
        git add &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;
        ```
        Example: `git add script.js`

    * **Complete the Revert Commit:** Now that the conflict is staged, you can finalize the revert:

        ```bash
        git commit
        ```
        This will open the commit message editor. Save and exit as in Step 3 of the main tutorial.



Markdown


#### Issue 2: &amp;quot;Nothing to commit&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;empty revert&amp;quot;

This message appears if the commit you&#39;re trying to revert doesn&#39;t actually introduce any new changes, or if those changes have already been undone by a subsequent commit. Git determines there&#39;s nothing to revert.

* **What to do:**
    * If you&#39;re sure there were changes, double-check your `git log` to ensure you picked the correct commit hash.
    * If the changes truly vanished or were undone, you might not need to do anything.

#### Issue 3: Reverting a Range of Commits

If you want to undo several commits in a sequence, you can specify a range:

```bash
git revert &amp;lt;FIRST_COMMIT_HASH&amp;gt;..&amp;lt;LAST_COMMIT_HASH&amp;gt;


This will revert each commit one by one. You might be prompted for a commit message for each revert, or you might hit merge conflicts for each.
You can add --no-edit to use the default message for each revert without opening the editor:
Bash
git revert --no-edit &amp;lt;FIRST_COMMIT_HASH&amp;gt;..&amp;lt;LAST_COMMIT_HASH&amp;gt;


Or --no-commit to stage all reverts as one single new commit, which is often cleaner:
Bash
git revert --no-commit &amp;lt;FIRST_COMMIT_HASH&amp;gt;..&amp;lt;LAST_COMMIT_HASH&amp;gt;
followed by a single git commit.



```markdown
#### Issue 4: You Need to Go Back to an Exact Past State, Not Just Undo Specific Commits

Sometimes, you don&#39;t just want to undo specific commits, but instead completely reset your branch to how it looked at a previous point in history, discarding everything that came after. This is where `git reset --hard` comes in.

**WARNING:** `git reset --hard` rewrites history. If you&#39;ve pushed these commits, using `git reset --hard` followed by `git push --force` will cause problems for collaborators who have the older history. Only use this if you are absolutely sure you are the sole contributor or can coordinate with your team.

* **How to do it (use with extreme caution):**
    * **Find the desired commit hash:** Use `git log` to find the commit hash of the exact state you want your branch to be in.
    * **Reset locally:**
        ```bash
        git reset --hard &amp;lt;commit-hash&amp;gt;
        ```
    * **Force Push:**
        ```bash
        git push --force
        ```

`git revert` is a powerful and safe way to manage your project&#39;s history. Understanding how to use it, especially for handling conflicts, will save you a lot of headaches in your development journey!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Essential Git: Part 1</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Essential_Git%20part_1/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Essential_Git%20part_1/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Your Essential Git Toolkit: A Friendly Guide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git can seem a bit intimidating at first, but it&#39;s just a system to help you keep track of changes in your code (or any files, for that matter) and collaborate smoothly. Think of it as a super-powered save button with a memory of every single change you&#39;ve ever made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s dive into the commands you&#39;ll use most often:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. &lt;code&gt;git status&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you use it:&lt;/strong&gt; Before you do anything else, you&#39;ll want to know what&#39;s going on. &lt;code&gt;git status&lt;/code&gt; tells you which files you&#39;ve changed, which ones are new, and whether anything is ready to be saved. It&#39;s your quick check-in to see the current state of your working directory compared to your last saved version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How you use it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# Check the current status of your Git repository
git status
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
This command will give you a clear rundown of your changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. &lt;code&gt;git add .&lt;/code&gt; (or &lt;code&gt;git add &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you use it:&lt;/strong&gt; When you make changes to your files, Git doesn&#39;t automatically track them for your next save. You need to explicitly tell Git which changes you want to include in your next &amp;quot;snapshot&amp;quot; (called a commit). Using &lt;code&gt;git add .&lt;/code&gt; is a common shortcut to add all modified and new files in your current directory and its subdirectories to the &amp;quot;staging area.&amp;quot; If you only want to add a specific file, you&#39;d use &lt;code&gt;git add &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How you use it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# To stage all modified and new files in the current directory and subdirectories
git add .

# To stage only a specific file
git add my-new-feature.js
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
You&#39;ll often run &lt;code&gt;git status&lt;/code&gt; right after this to confirm what you&#39;ve staged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. &lt;code&gt;git commit -m &amp;quot;Your descriptive message here&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you use it:&lt;/strong&gt; A commit is a snapshot of your project at a specific point in time. It&#39;s like taking a picture of your entire project&#39;s state. The &lt;code&gt;-m&lt;/code&gt; flag lets you add a short, descriptive message about what changes you made in that commit. Good commit messages are essential – they help you (and others) understand the history of your project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How you use it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# Create a new commit with a descriptive message
git commit -m &amp;quot;Add user login functionality and fix button styling&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Make sure your message is clear and concise!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. &lt;code&gt;git push origin main&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you use it:&lt;/strong&gt; After you&#39;ve committed your changes locally, they&#39;re only on your computer. To share them with others or to back them up on a remote server (like GitHub, GitLab, or Bitbucket), you use &lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code&gt;origin&lt;/code&gt; typically refers to the default remote repository where your project lives online, and &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; is the name of the branch you&#39;re pushing to (it used to be called &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;, but &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; is the new standard).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How you use it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# Push your committed changes from your local &#39;main&#39; branch to the &#39;origin&#39; remote
git push origin main
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
If you&#39;re working on a different branch, you&#39;d replace &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; with your branch name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Few Extra Tips!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Branches are your friends:&lt;/strong&gt; While we focused on the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch today, Git is fantastic because you can create &amp;quot;branches&amp;quot; for new features or bug fixes. This lets you work on something new without messing up the main, stable version of your project. Once your work is ready, you can merge it back into the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&#39;t be afraid to experiment:&lt;/strong&gt; Git is designed to be undo-friendly. If you make a mistake, there&#39;s usually a way to fix it. That&#39;s why it&#39;s so great!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practice makes perfect:&lt;/strong&gt; The more you use these commands, the more natural they&#39;ll feel. Try creating a small test project and just playing around with making changes, adding, committing, and pushing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps you feel more comfortable jumping into the world of Git! It&#39;s an incredibly valuable tool for anyone working with code. Happy coding!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love Git Branches</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/2025-06-12-a-guide-to-git-branches/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/2025-06-12-a-guide-to-git-branches/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been deep in concentration, adding a new feature to your website, and you suddenly realize... you&#39;ve broken everything? The page won&#39;t load, styles are a mess, and panic sets in. I&#39;ve certainly been there. For a long time, I did all my work directly on my &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch—the one that my live site was built from. Every change was a high-stakes gamble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I embraced a professional workflow that completely changed the game: &lt;strong&gt;Git branching&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of your &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch as the &amp;quot;golden copy&amp;quot; of your project. It&#39;s the version that is live, working, and stable. A branch is like making a safe, parallel copy of your project where you can experiment freely. If your new idea works, you merge it into the main copy. If it&#39;s a disaster, you simply delete the branch, and the golden copy remains untouched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It brings peace of mind to the development process, and here’s why you should be using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why Bother with Branches?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might seem like a few extra steps, but the benefits are huge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Safety:&lt;/strong&gt; Your &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch is always protected. You can be confident that it&#39;s in a deployable, working state at all times. No more &amp;quot;I broke the live site!&amp;quot; panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freedom to Experiment:&lt;/strong&gt; Want to try a completely new layout or a wild idea? Create a branch! You can make a mess, try things out, and break whatever you want. If it doesn&#39;t work out, there&#39;s no harm done. Just delete the branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization:&lt;/strong&gt; You can create a specific branch for every new feature or bug fix. This keeps your work isolated and easy to track. For example, &lt;code&gt;feature/new-contact-form&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;fix/mobile-menu-bug&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaboration &amp;amp; Review:&lt;/strong&gt; If you work on a team, branches are essential. But even for solo developers, they allow you to use Pull Requests on GitHub to review your own work before merging it, which is a great way to catch mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;My Simple 5-Step Branching Workflow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I wanted to improve the navigation on my blog. On my homepage, I wanted the header link to point back to my main portfolio, but on individual posts, I wanted it to point back to the blog&#39;s homepage. This was a perfect use case for a feature branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the exact workflow I followed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 1: Start Clean&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before starting anything new, I made sure my local project was in sync with the live version on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# Switch to the main branch
git checkout main&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Welcome to the Blog</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/my-first-post/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/my-first-post/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Welcome! I&#39;m New Here (And I Have No Idea What I&#39;m Doing)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I did it. I finally have a new online home. Welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, this space is a bit like me on a Monday morning: a work in progress, slightly confused, but full of potential. I&#39;m busy behind the scenes, untangling the technical knots and figuring out how all this stuff works. (If you hear faint screaming, it&#39;s just me trying to center an image.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be adding all my previously posted articles here soon, they will show up eventually. More importantly, I&#39;ve got some new ideas I&#39;m excited to share with you once I&#39;m sure I won&#39;t accidentally delete the entire internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, have a look around, don&#39;t mind the occasional digital pothole, and thanks for being here at the very beginning. Let&#39;s get this show on the road!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why I Chose Eleventy for My Blog (And How I Secured It)</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Eleventy_for_My_Blog/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Eleventy_for_My_Blog/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;###After getting my main portfolio site into a stable, secure state, I decided it was time to add a blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My core requirements were simple but non-negotiable: it had to be modern, straightforward to maintain, and—most importantly—built in a way that couldn&#39;t possibly break my main portfolio site during development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This led me dwon the apth of creating a completely separate, standalone blog site. Here’s a look at the &amp;quot;why&amp;quot; behind the tools I chose and the security precautions we took along the way. Why Eleventy? The &amp;quot;Keep It Simple&amp;quot; Philosophy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today&#39;s landscape of complex JavaScript frameworks, I was looking for something simpler. After some research, I landed on Eleventy (11ty), a modern Static Site Generator (SSG).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the perfect choice for a few key reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simplicity and Flexibility: Eleventy doesn&#39;t lock you into a heavy framework like React or Vue. It&#39;s incredibly flexible and un-opinionated, letting you work with simple templates and data. This felt perfect for a straightforward, content-focused blog. JavaScript-Based: The entire configuration is done in plain JavaScript (.eleventy.js), which felt comfortable and accessible. There was no need to learn a new programming language just to build a blog. Peak Performance &amp;amp; Security: By default, Eleventy generates pre-built, static HTML files. This means there&#39;s no database to ahck and no complex server-side code running on every page view. The result is a site that is incredibly fast and secure right out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Security-First Approach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A static site is secure by default, but I wanted to go further and ensure it was hardened against modern web vulnerabilities. The main tool for this was a netlify.toml file placed at the root of the project, which allowed me to define custom HTTP security headers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the key security layers we implemented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content Security Policy (CSP): The Digital Bouncer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important header we added was a strong Content Security Policy. Think of a CSP as a bouncer for your website—it maintains a strict guest list of all the resources (scripts, styles, fonts, etc.) that are allowed to load on the page. Anything not on the list gets blcoked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My policy explicitly whitelists trusted sources for each type of content:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;script-src: Only allows scripts from my own domain and the trusted Tailwind CSS CDN.
style-src: Only allows stylesheets from my domain and Google Fonts.
font-src: Only allows fonts to be downloaded from Google&#39;s font servers (fonts.gstatic.com).
object-src &#39;none&#39;: Completely blocks older, insecure plugins like Flash from ever running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &#39;unsafe-inline&#39; Caveat: The one necessary compromise was allowing &#39;unsafe-inline&#39; for styles. This was required for the Tailwind CSS CDN script to work, as it dynamically injects styles into the page. However, the risk is heavily mitigated because the overall source of any scripts is still locked down by the rest of the policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other Essential Headers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the CSP, we added several other headers for a layered defense:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strict-Transport-Security (HSTS): Ensures that browsers only ever communicate with my site over a secure HTTPS connection. X-Frame-Options: Set to DENY, this completely prevents my site from being embedded in an &lt;iframe&gt; on another website, which is the primary defense against &amp;quot;clickjacking&amp;quot; attacks. Permissions-Policy: This is a modern header that lets me lock down browser features that my blog has no reason to use, like the microphone, camera, USB devices, and payment APIs.&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Result&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The outcome is exactly what I was hoping for: a fast, modern blog with an A+ security rating that is completely decoupled from my main portfolio. The workflow is simple—I write a post in a Markdown file, push it to GitHub, and Netlify handles the rest. It’s a setup I can trust while I focus on writing content and my job search.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Smartest Person in the Room is Quoting a Movie</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Are%20You%20Playing%20Chess/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Are%20You%20Playing%20Chess/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;You know the moment. You’re in a meeting, a debate, or just scrolling through Twitter, and someone drops the line. They lean back, maybe with a self-satisfied little smirk, and say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m playing chess, not checkers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s meant to be the ultimate mic drop, a casual announcement that they&#39;re operating on a strategic level far beyond our lowly mortal comprehension. The issue? It&#39;s among the most loaned, overused, and confused lines out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Humblebrag&#39;s Family Tree&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come on, the person who said this didn&#39;t invent the phrase. They’re channeling Denzel Washington’s iconic delivery in &lt;em&gt;Training Day&lt;/em&gt;. They&#39;re picturing themselves as Kobe Bryant schooling a rookie. They might even be referencing a business book—a real one is titled &lt;em&gt;Chess Not Checkers&lt;/em&gt;—as if that makes them a grandmaster of business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term has been kicking around for decades. Samuel L. Jackson uttered a variation of it all the way back in 1994. Since then, it&#39;s been the go-to catchphrase for anyone who wants to sound intelligent without actually doing the work of, you know, being intelligent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;But Here&#39;s the Twist: You&#39;re Insulting the Wrong Game&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s the real stinger in this whole comparison: Checkers is not really a &amp;quot;simple&amp;quot; game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While chess is complex, the number of possible board positions in checkers is estimated at around &lt;strong&gt;500 billion billion&lt;/strong&gt;. That&#39;s 5 x 10^20, a number so huge it&#39;s hard to wrap my head around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is no hypothetical number. It&#39;s the domain of legends like &lt;strong&gt;Dr. Marion Tinsley&lt;/strong&gt;, a math professor and very possibly the greatest checkers player who ever lived. Over 45 years, Tinsley lost a grand total of seven games—&lt;em&gt;seven&lt;/em&gt;. A shy genius who could look dozens of moves ahead, he once notably defeated a top computer program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone was &amp;quot;playing chess,&amp;quot; it was the man who achieved near perfection in a game of cosmic complexity. And he did it with checkers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Irony of a Borrowed Boast&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when somebody invokes the &amp;quot;chess, not checkers&amp;quot; phrase to declare their superior intelligence, it falls flat on two important levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&#39;re using a hand-me-down line to make a claim for originality. It&#39;s the equivalent of going to a design contest in a fast-fashion suit and proclaiming yourself an innovator. If your strategic brain is so genius, shouldn&#39;t your observations stand on their own? Why use a cliché to do the lifting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&#39;re accidentally insulting something, and they&#39;re accidentally disrespecting a game of incredible depth. They&#39;re trying to sound smart by punching down at something they don&#39;t understand—a dead giveaway of someone not as smart as they think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;True Strategy Doesn&#39;t Need a Catchphrase&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Real strategic thinking is understated, deliberate, and demonstrated through action, not announcement. It&#39;s being able to manage complexity, anticipate consequences, and articulate ideas with clarity and creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most intelligent people don&#39;t need to tell you they&#39;re playing a different game. You see it in their result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let your work, ideas, and unique voice do the talking. Play your own game, and let the stale cliches be for the parrots.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Case of the Persistent Contact Form: A Debugging Odyssey</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/2025-06-11-contact-form/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/2025-06-11-contact-form/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h3&gt;The Case of the Persistent Contact Form: A Debugging Odyssey&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey tech enthusiasts and fellow web wranglers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever stared at a seemingly simple feature – like a contact ofrm – and wondered why it&#39;s putting up such a fight? Well, I recently went on an epic debugging adventure with my own website&#39;s contact form, and let me tell you, it was a journey filled with unexpected twists, a few head-scratching moments, and ultimately, a satisfying victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re currently wrestling with a stubborn form, a missing CAPTCHA,. Email notifications that just won&#39;t trigger, you might find some solace (and hopefully some solutions!) in my tale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**The Initial Setup (Seemed Simple Enough!) **&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal was straightforward: a clean, effective contact form on my personal site, protected by a CAPTCHA to ward off those pesky bots, and set up to send me an email whenever someone reached out. I opted for Netlify to host my static site, Cloudflare Turnstile for a user-friendly CAPTCHA, and Resend for reliable email delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial setup involved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crafting the HTML form. * Writing a Netlify serverless function in JavaScript to handle the form submission, CAPTCHA verification, and email sending via Resend. * Adding a sprinkle of client-side JavaScript for form validation and submission handling. * Configuring environment variables in Netlify for API keys and secrets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds reasonable, right? That&#39;s what I thought too...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Signs of Trouble (and the Rabbit Hole)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, the site looked great (thanks to Tailwind CSS. A cool three.js background animation – another story for another time!). But the contact form? Radio silence. No CAPTCHA widget, and definitely no emails landing in my inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where the debugging adventure truly began. What followed was a deep idve into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Browser Developer Tools (My Best Friend!) **: Console logs became my daily bread, and network requests my guiding stars. We meticulously checked for JavaScript errors, failed API calls, and Content Security Policy violations. * &lt;strong&gt;Netlify Deployment Logs&lt;/strong&gt;: Scrutinizing every stage of the build and deployment process became crucial to ensure our serverless function was being included correctly. * &lt;strong&gt;Cloudflare Turnstile Dashboard&lt;/strong&gt;: Double-checking site keys, secret kyes, and even experimenting with different settings. * &lt;strong&gt;Resend Logs&lt;/strong&gt;: Monitoring email sending attempts to see if the requests were even reaching the service. What the responses were. * &lt;strong&gt;HTTP Headers (The Silent Guardians)&lt;/strong&gt;: We spent a surprising amount of time wrestling with the &lt;code&gt;netlify.toml&lt;/code&gt; file and its security headers, learning firsthand how a misconfigured policy can block essential resources. * &lt;strong&gt;Environment Variables (The Keepers of Secrets)&lt;/strong&gt;: Ensuring API keys were correctly stored and accessed by our Netlify function. * &lt;strong&gt;Branching and Deployment Contexts&lt;/strong&gt;: Briefly suspected we might be working on the wrong version of the site!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Learnings and Aha! Moments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this process, several key learnings emerged:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Order Matters&lt;/strong&gt;: In our &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt;, the order in which scripts were loaded (especially Three.js and our main &lt;code&gt;script.js&lt;/code&gt;) had a significant impact on whether the page rendered correctly. * **Security is Paramount (and Tricky!) **: Content Security Policy is a powerful tool, but it requires careful configuration to avoid unintentionally blocking legitimate resources like third-party CAPTCHA scripts and analytics. * &lt;strong&gt;Serverless Functions Can Be Elusive&lt;/strong&gt;: Debugging server-side code running in a cloud environment requires a different mindset than local development. Netlify&#39;s function logs and the ability to download deployed functions became invaluable. * &lt;strong&gt;Deployment Consistency is Key&lt;/strong&gt;: We encountered situations where local code wasn&#39;t making its way to the deployed site as expected, highlighting the importance of proper Git practices. * &lt;strong&gt;Every Error Message is a Breadcrumb&lt;/strong&gt;: Even cryptic error messages in the browser console or network logs provide valuable clues if you know where to look and how to interpret them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**The Sweet Taste of Success (Finally!) **&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After what felt like countless iterations, meticulous log analysis, and a few moments of pure frustration, we finally cracked the code! The issues ranged from a missing Three.js script tag, overly restrictive security policies, and even ensuring the correct version of our Netlify function was being deployed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moment the CAPTCHA widget appeared, the form started submitting correctly, and those email notifications began landing in my inbox was incredibly rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tips for Your Own Debugging Adventures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re facing similar challenges with your contact form or website features, here are a few takeaways from my experience:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be Patient and Systematic&lt;/strong&gt;: Debugging often involves trial and error, but a systematic approach of checking logs, isolating variables, and making small, incremental changes is crucial. * &lt;strong&gt;Leverage Your Browser&#39;s Developer Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Become comfortable with the Console, Network, and Security tabs. They provide a wealth of information. * **Read the Documentation (Carefully!) **: The documentation for services like Netlify, Cloudflare Turnstile, and Resend is your best friend. Pay close attention to configuration instructions and common troubleshooting steps. * &lt;strong&gt;Don&#39;t Be Afraid to Ask for Help&lt;/strong&gt;: Online communities and forums can be incredibly valuable resources when you&#39;re stuck. Clearly explaining your problem and what you&#39;ve tried so far will help others assist you. * &lt;strong&gt;Celebrate the Small Victories&lt;/strong&gt;: Debugging can be mentally taxing. Acknowldege and celberate each step forward, no matter how small.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Journey Continues...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this particular debugging odyssey has reached its conclusion, the world of web development is constantly evolving. There will always be new challenges to overcome and new things to learn. And that, in itself, is part of the adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>