<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Beau Bremer&#39;s | Blog</title>
  <subtitle>A collection of articles and thoughts on technology and project management.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/"/>
  <updated>2025-09-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Beau Bremer</name>
    <email>support&amp;#64;beaubremer&amp;#46;com</email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>When a Service Plays Dead: A Sysadmin&#39;s Debugging Guide</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/debugging_a_service_that_won&#39;t_start/"/>
    <updated>2025-09-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/debugging_a_service_that_won&#39;t_start/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;A Sysadmin&#39;s Tale: Debugging a Service That Won&#39;t Start&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every so often in server administration, you run into a problem that defies the usual solutions. A service that should be running simply isn&#39;t, and the quick fixes don&#39;t work. A recent troubleshooting session with a self-hosted Tor Onion Service served as a great reminder of some valuable lessons in persistence and diagnostics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the context here is a Tor service, the step-by-step process of elimination is a universal guide to debugging almost any misbehaving service on a Linux server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Problem: A Service Playing Dead&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial symptom was simple: the onion site was down. After connecting to the server, the first command in any admin&#39;s toolkit is &lt;code&gt;systemctl status&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;sudo systemctl status tor
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The output holds the first major clue: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;Active: active (exited)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. For a service that&#39;s supposed to run continuously, this is a red flag. It means the service started, did something, and then immediately shut down without an obvious error. This is far trickier to debug than a simple crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Diagnostic Journey: Peeling the Onion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the main status is unhelpful, it&#39;s time to dig deeper. Here&#39;s a reliable path to follow, moving from the most general to the most specific tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Check the System Logs (&lt;code&gt;journalctl&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next logical step is to check the system&#39;s journal for the service. The &lt;code&gt;-e&lt;/code&gt; flag jumps you to the end of the log, which is where the most recent events are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;sudo journalctl -u tor -e
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the logs were as unhelpful as the status. They only confirmed that the service was starting and stopping, without providing any application-specific errors. This tells us the problem likely isn&#39;t with &lt;code&gt;systemd&lt;/code&gt; itself, but with the Tor application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Check the Application Logs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most applications write their own, more detailed logs. For Tor, this is usually &lt;code&gt;/var/log/tor/notices.log&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;sudo cat /var/log/tor/notices.log
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The output here provides another huge clue: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;No such file or directory&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. A service that can&#39;t create its own log file is a strong sign of a &lt;strong&gt;file permissions problem&lt;/strong&gt;. Even after trying to fix ownership with &lt;code&gt;chown&lt;/code&gt;, the issue persisted, suggesting the problem was somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Inspect the Service File&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the investigation leads to a surprising discovery. After reinstalling the &lt;code&gt;tor&lt;/code&gt; package didn&#39;t help, the next place to look was the &lt;code&gt;systemd&lt;/code&gt; service file itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;cat /lib/systemd/system/tor.service
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow, the file had been replaced with a generic placeholder. A critical line, &lt;code&gt;ExecStart=/bin/true&lt;/code&gt;, was telling the service to run a command that does nothing and immediately exits successfully. After replacing the file&#39;s contents with the correct, default configuration, a real error message finally appeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Verify the Configuration&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the service file fixed, &lt;code&gt;systemctl restart tor&lt;/code&gt; now failed with a proper error. This allows us to move on to verifying Tor&#39;s own configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;sudo -u debian-tor tor --verify-config
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This command passed, indicating that &lt;code&gt;/etc/tor/torrc&lt;/code&gt; was syntactically correct. This is a classic troubleshooting moment: the config file is valid, but the service still won&#39;t run. The problem isn&#39;t the file&#39;s syntax, but &lt;em&gt;what the file is telling the service to do&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Run the Service Manually (The Breakthrough)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is often the final and most critical step. Bypassing &lt;code&gt;systemd&lt;/code&gt; and running the Tor startup command directly, as the correct user, lets you see the live output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;sudo -u debian-tor /usr/bin/tor --defaults-torrc /usr/share/tor/tor-service-defaults-torrc -f /etc/tor/torrc --RunAsDaemon 0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there it was, in plain text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;[warn] Failed to parse/validate config: Problem with User value. See logs for details.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;systemd&lt;/code&gt; service was already starting the process as the &lt;code&gt;debian-tor&lt;/code&gt; user, but a default Tor configuration file was &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; trying to switch to the &lt;code&gt;debian-tor&lt;/code&gt; user. This redundant user-switching conflict caused the service to crash instantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fix was to edit &lt;code&gt;/usr/share/tor/tor-service-defaults-torrc&lt;/code&gt; and comment out the &lt;code&gt;User debian-tor&lt;/code&gt; line. After that, the service started perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This deep dive highlights a few core principles of system administration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trust the Process:&lt;/strong&gt; Start broad (&lt;code&gt;systemctl status&lt;/code&gt;) and get progressively more specific. Don&#39;t jump to conclusions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Permissions Are a Common Culprit:&lt;/strong&gt; When in doubt, check file and directory ownership and permissions (&lt;code&gt;chown&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;chmod&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find the Right Logs:&lt;/strong&gt; If the main system log is unhelpful, find the application&#39;s own log file. If it doesn&#39;t exist, that itself is a clue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Run It Manually:&lt;/strong&gt; If a service fails via &lt;code&gt;systemd&lt;/code&gt;, run its startup command directly in the terminal. The live output is often the most valuable diagnostic information you can get.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the context was specific to a Tor service, this methodical approach of checking services, logs, permissions, and configurations—and finally running the process manually—is a playbook that can solve almost any &amp;quot;service that won&#39;t start&amp;quot; mystery.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Building a Privacy-First Image Cleaner on a Tor Onion Service</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/iimage_cleaner_on_a_tor_onion_service/"/>
    <updated>2025-08-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/iimage_cleaner_on_a_tor_onion_service/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Building a Privacy-First Image Cleaner&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today&#39;s digital world, privacy is paramount. Every photo we take with our smartphones or digital cameras often contains hidden data—known as EXIF metadata—that can reveal sensitive information like our location, the device model, and even the exact time a picture was taken. Sharing these images online without cleaning them can inadvertently expose personal details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post details how I built a privacy-focused web service to solve this problem: a &lt;strong&gt;Secure Image Cleaner&lt;/strong&gt; hosted entirely on a Tor Onion Service. You can try it out here (requires Tor Browser): &lt;a href=&quot;http://32fd3d4gq3u4qqpofstaiq3sf3h6tnyrdpqdcgdszbrhovv25yfxzhqd.onion/cleaner.html&quot;&gt;http://32fd3d4gq3u4qqpofstaiq3sf3h6tnyrdpqdcgdszbrhovv25yfxzhqd.onion/cleaner.html&lt;/a&gt;. This project was a great way to dive deep into Tor, server administration, and secure web development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why a Secure Image Cleaner on Tor?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A privacy-focused version of my personal website is also hosted as a Tor Onion Service, primarily as a project to explore privacy-first web development. The goal is to strip away all unnecessary JavaScript, tracking, and external resources for a truly minimalist and secure browsing experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building an image cleaner on this foundation felt like a natural extension of that mission:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Privacy:&lt;/strong&gt; For users concerned about their digital footprint, cleaning metadata locally is good, but doing it through a trusted, anonymous Tor service adds another layer of protection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Demonstrating Expertise:&lt;/strong&gt; This project allowed me to showcase practical skills in several key areas:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linux Server Administration:&lt;/strong&gt; Configuring and managing an Ubuntu VM on Google Cloud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Networking:&lt;/strong&gt; Understanding and implementing Tor hidden services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Development:&lt;/strong&gt; Building a minimalist, functional web application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backend Engineering:&lt;/strong&gt; Developing a Python Flask application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Server Configuration:&lt;/strong&gt; Setting up Nginx as a reverse proxy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System Services:&lt;/strong&gt; Managing applications with &lt;code&gt;systemd&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-World Utility:&lt;/strong&gt; It&#39;s not just a demo; it&#39;s a genuinely useful tool for anyone looking to share images more privately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Architecture: A Full Stack Journey&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating this service involved a stack chosen specifically for functionality and privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a breakdown of the core components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tor Onion Service:&lt;/strong&gt; The entry point for users, providing anonymity and encryption.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Cloud Platform (GCP) e2-micro VM:&lt;/strong&gt; The hosting environment, leveraging the &amp;quot;Always Free&amp;quot; tier for cost-effectiveness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ubuntu Server:&lt;/strong&gt; A robust and flexible operating system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nginx:&lt;/strong&gt; Acts as the web server for static files and as a &lt;strong&gt;reverse proxy&lt;/strong&gt; to forward dynamic requests to the Python application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gunicorn:&lt;/strong&gt; A production-ready Python WSGI HTTP Server that interfaces between Nginx and our Flask application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flask Application (&lt;code&gt;image_cleaner.py&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/strong&gt; The Python backend that handles receiving image uploads, stripping metadata, and returning the cleaned image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pillow Library:&lt;/strong&gt; A powerful image processing library for Python, used to manipulate image data and remove EXIF tags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python Virtual Environments:&lt;/strong&gt; Essential for isolating project dependencies and maintaining a clean system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;systemd&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Manages the Gunicorn service, ensuring it runs reliably in the background and starts automatically on boot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How It Works: A Step-by-Step Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process for a user is simple, but the backend is a finely tuned orchestration of services:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Accesses the Page:&lt;/strong&gt; A user visits the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://32fd3d4gq3u4qqpofstaiq3sf3h6tnyrdpqdcgdszbrhovv25yfxzhqd.onion/cleaner.html&quot;&gt;Image Cleaner page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on the Tor Onion Service using a Tor Browser. The page contains a minimalist HTML form to upload an image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image Upload &amp;amp; Nginx Interception:&lt;/strong&gt; When the user selects an image (up to 10MB) and clicks &amp;quot;Clean and Download,&amp;quot; the browser sends a POST request to the &lt;code&gt;/upload&lt;/code&gt; endpoint. Nginx receives this request first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nginx Proxies to Gunicorn:&lt;/strong&gt; Based on its configuration, Nginx recognizes the /upload path and proxies the request to the Gunicorn server, which is listening on a local Unix socket (image_cleaner.sock).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the exact Nginx location block that handles the magic. It forwards the request to the Gunicorn socket and adds several important headers so our Flask application knows about the original user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-Nginx&quot;&gt;
location /upload {
    proxy_pass http://unix:/home/userx/image_cleaner_app/image_cleaner.sock;
    proxy_set_header Host $host;
    proxy_set_header X-Real-IP $remote_addr;
    proxy_set_header X-Forwarded-For $proxy_add_x_forwarded_for;
    proxy_set_header X-Forwarded-Proto $scheme;
}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gunicorn Hands Off to Flask:&lt;/strong&gt; Gunicorn receives the request and passes it to our Flask application (&lt;code&gt;image_cleaner.py&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flask Processes the Image:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Flask app securely saves the uploaded image to a temporary folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It uses the Pillow library to open the image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crucially, it reads only the raw pixel data, leaving all EXIF metadata behind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new image is created from this clean pixel data and saved temporarily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure Download &amp;amp; Cleanup:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Flask app sends the cleaned image back to the user&#39;s browser for download.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immediately after the file is sent, &lt;strong&gt;both the original and the cleaned temporary files are deleted.&lt;/strong&gt; This ensures no user data persists on the server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;systemd&lt;/code&gt; Reliability:&lt;/strong&gt; The entire Python application, managed by Gunicorn, runs as a &lt;code&gt;systemd&lt;/code&gt; service. If the server reboots or the application crashes, &lt;code&gt;systemd&lt;/code&gt; automatically restarts it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Key Learnings &amp;amp; Takeaways&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project provided invaluable insights into a few areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virtual Environments are Non-Negotiable:&lt;/strong&gt; Managing Python dependencies with &lt;code&gt;venv&lt;/code&gt; is critical for clean, reproducible deployments. It&#39;s the best way to avoid using &lt;code&gt;sudo pip install&lt;/code&gt; on system-managed Python environments (a lesson I learned firsthand!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nginx as a Powerful Gateway:&lt;/strong&gt; Beyond serving static files, Nginx&#39;s role as a reverse proxy is fundamental for robust web services. Understanding &lt;code&gt;location&lt;/code&gt; blocks and &lt;code&gt;proxy_pass&lt;/code&gt; is key.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;systemd&lt;/code&gt; for Production Readiness:&lt;/strong&gt; Turning a simple Python script into a reliable, self-starting service with &lt;code&gt;systemd&lt;/code&gt; is a crucial skill for server administration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security by Design:&lt;/strong&gt; From ephemeral file storage to an intentionally minimalist design (no JavaScript, no tracking), every aspect of this project emphasized privacy and security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Troubleshooting is King:&lt;/strong&gt; Reading error messages carefully (like &amp;quot;413 Request Entity Too Large&amp;quot;) and knowing how to debug Nginx or &lt;code&gt;systemd&lt;/code&gt; logs is an essential skill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;See the Code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those interested in the technical details, the source code for this project is available on GitHub. You can find it in the &lt;code&gt;onion-version&lt;/code&gt; branch of my website&#39;s repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/KnowOneActual/BB_Website/tree/onion-version&quot;&gt;View the project on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Looking Ahead&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Secure Image Cleaner is a proof-of-concept, but it could easily be expanded. Future enhancements might include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for more image formats (e.g., WebP).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A cleaner user interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An option to simply view metadata before removal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was an journey into building a privacy-conscious online tool. It&#39;s a testament to the power of open-source technologies like Tor, Nginx, and Flask to create secure and useful applications. Give the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://32fd3d4gq3u4qqpofstaiq3sf3h6tnyrdpqdcgdszbrhovv25yfxzhqd.onion/cleaner.html&quot;&gt;Image Cleaner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Note: Open in a Tor Browser) a try and let me know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekend Project: Turning My Personal Site into a Tor Onion Service</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/site_into_a_tor_onion_service/"/>
    <updated>2025-08-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/site_into_a_tor_onion_service/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;Maybe you&#39;re looking for a weekend project that&#39;s a little different, something that teaches you about the hidden corners of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If so, I&#39;ve got the perfect project for you: creating a Tor onion service for your existing website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may sound complex and mysterious, but it&#39;s actually surprisingly straightforward. At its core, it&#39;s a fantastic exercise in basic server administration and networking. We&#39;re not doing anything shady; we&#39;re just experimenting with technology to see how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;First, What Is an Onion Service?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An onion service (you&#39;ve probably seen their long, nonsensical addresses ending in &lt;code&gt;.onion&lt;/code&gt;) is a website that&#39;s only accessible through the Tor network. The &amp;quot;onion&amp;quot; name comes from the layers of encryption that protect both the person visiting the site and the server hosting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you visit a normal website, your computer connects directly to its server. With an onion service, your connection is bounced through several random computers (called relays) in the Tor network before it reaches the server. The server&#39;s location is also hidden. This provides a powerful layer of privacy and anonymity that you just don&#39;t get on the regular internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why Bother?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this wasn&#39;t about hiding from anyone. It was about curiosity and learning. Here&#39;s why I think it&#39;s a great project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&#39;s a fantastic learning experience.&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll get hands-on with a Linux server, a web server like Nginx, and the Tor software itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&#39;s a great story.&lt;/strong&gt; Let&#39;s be honest, it&#39;s a neat trick. Being able to say you have your site running as an onion service just to see if you could is a fun talking point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&#39;s basically free.&lt;/strong&gt; We can do this entire project using the &amp;quot;Always Free&amp;quot; tier from a cloud provider like Google Cloud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The How-To: A Step-by-Step Guide&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal is simple: get a small, free virtual server online, put our website files on it, and then install and configure Tor to act as the gateway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 1: Get a Free Server on Google Cloud&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll use Google Cloud&#39;s &amp;quot;Always Free&amp;quot; tier, which gives you one tiny &lt;code&gt;e2-micro&lt;/code&gt; virtual machine (VM) forever, at no cost. This is more than enough for a simple static website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for Google Cloud&lt;/strong&gt; and create a new project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigate to &lt;strong&gt;Compute Engine&lt;/strong&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;VM instances&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;Create Instance&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; and use these exact settings to stay in the free tier:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Region:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;us-west1&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;us-central1&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;us-east1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Machine type:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;e2-micro&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boot disk:&lt;/strong&gt; Ubuntu or Debian, 30 GB or less.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Firewall:&lt;/strong&gt; Check the box to &amp;quot;Allow HTTP traffic.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 2: Connect to Your Server&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the VM is running, connect to it using a command-line terminal. The easiest way is with Google&#39;s own command-line tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/sdk/docs/install&quot;&gt;Install the gcloud CLI&lt;/a&gt; on your local computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open your terminal and run &lt;code&gt;gcloud init&lt;/code&gt; to log in and select your project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect to your VM with this command (replace with your VM&#39;s name and zone):&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;gcloud compute ssh your-vm-name --zone its-zone
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 3: Install the Software&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&#39;re connected, run these commands to install everything you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# Update the server and install Nginx (web server), Tor, and Git
sudo apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt upgrade -y
sudo apt install git nginx tor -y
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 4: Add Your Website Files&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, pull your website&#39;s code from its repository and place it where Nginx can find it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# Clone your site (use your own repo URL)
git clone [https://github.com/your-username/your-repo.git](https://github.com/your-username/your-repo.git)

# Move the files to the web server&#39;s public directory
sudo cp -r ~/your-repo/* /var/www/html/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 5: Configure Tor and Get Your Address!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the magic step. You just need to add two lines to Tor&#39;s configuration file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# This command adds the necessary lines to the end of the config file
echo -e &amp;quot;HiddenServiceDir /var/lib/tor/hidden_service/&#92;nHiddenServicePort 80 127.0.0.1:80&amp;quot; | sudo tee -a /etc/tor/torrc

# Restart the services to apply the changes
sudo systemctl restart nginx
sudo systemctl restart tor
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait about a minute, then run this command to see your new address:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;sudo cat /var/lib/tor/hidden_service/hostname
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copy that long &lt;code&gt;.onion&lt;/code&gt; address, paste it into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/download/&quot;&gt;Tor Browser&lt;/a&gt;, and you should see your site!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Pitfalls: A Warning for the Weary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let&#39;s be honest. The process above looks simple, but getting there was a journey. Here&#39;s what I learned the hard way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Onboarding is Confusing.&lt;/strong&gt; Getting started with a Google cloud as an individual can be a bit of a maze. The menus are built for giant corporations, not for someone doing a weekend project. Be prepared to feel like you&#39;re doing everything wrong. You&#39;re not—the design is the problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;Free&amp;quot; Requires a Billing Account.&lt;/strong&gt; You will have to link a credit card to a billing account, even for the &amp;quot;Always Free&amp;quot; tier. This is for verification, and you won&#39;t be charged as long as you stay within the free limits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cost Estimate is Misleading.&lt;/strong&gt; When you create your free &lt;code&gt;e2-micro&lt;/code&gt; VM, the console will show you a monthly cost estimate (around $7). &lt;strong&gt;Ignore it.&lt;/strong&gt; This is the list price. The &amp;quot;Always Free&amp;quot; discount is applied at the end of the month, making your bill zero. It&#39;s confusing, but you just have to trust the process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The In-Browser SSH is Terrible.&lt;/strong&gt; Don&#39;t even bother with it. It&#39;s laggy and unresponsive. Take the five minutes to install the &lt;code&gt;gcloud&lt;/code&gt; CLI and connect with your local terminal. It will save you a world of frustration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I got it working, and you can too. This project is a perfect example of something that is technically simple but is wrapped in layers of corporate administrative nonsense. Pushing through that is a victory in itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So go ahead, give it a try. It&#39;s a fun challenge, a great story to tell, and a fantastic way to prove that you can figure things out, no matter how poorly they&#39;re designed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can access the live site using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://32fd3d4gq3u4qqpofstaiq3sf3h6tnyrdpqdcgdszbrhovv25yfxzhqd.onion/&quot;&gt;Tor Browser via this link&lt;/a&gt;. Please note that this link will only resolve if you are using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/download/&quot;&gt;Tor Browser&lt;/a&gt;. (32fd3d4gq3u4qqpofstaiq3sf3h6tnyrdpqdcgdszbrhovv25yfxzhqd.onion)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What&#39;s in a Name? A Guide to DNS Troubleshooting with nslookup</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/A_Guide_to_DNS_Troubleshooting_with_nslookup/"/>
    <updated>2025-08-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/A_Guide_to_DNS_Troubleshooting_with_nslookup/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ve run a &lt;code&gt;ping&lt;/code&gt; to a server, and it fails. Or maybe a website suddenly won&#39;t load, even though the rest of your internet seems fine. Is the server down, or is something else going on? Often, the problem isn&#39;t with the connection itself but with the internet&#39;s address book: the &lt;strong&gt;Domain Name System (DNS)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where &lt;code&gt;nslookup&lt;/code&gt; comes in. While &lt;code&gt;ping&lt;/code&gt; tells you &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; a server is reachable, &lt;code&gt;nslookup&lt;/code&gt; tells you how your computer finds it in the first place. It&#39;s the perfect next step in your troubleshooting toolkit, helping you diagnose a whole new class of network problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;nslookup&lt;/code&gt; and Why Use It?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time you type a domain like &lt;code&gt;google.com&lt;/code&gt; into your browser, your computer needs to translate that human-friendly name into a machine-friendly IP address (like &lt;code&gt;142.250.217.78&lt;/code&gt;). DNS is the global system that handles this translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;nslookup&lt;/code&gt; (short for &amp;quot;name server lookup&amp;quot;) is a command-line tool that lets you directly ask the DNS system for information.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of DNS as the internet&#39;s phonebook. &lt;code&gt;nslookup&lt;/code&gt; is the tool you use to look up a person&#39;s name to find their phone number. It&#39;s essential for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finding a domain&#39;s IP address:&lt;/strong&gt; The most basic and common use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Troubleshooting website access:&lt;/strong&gt; See if a domain is pointing to the correct server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verifying DNS changes:&lt;/strong&gt; Check if your new DNS records have gone live.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diagnosing email problems:&lt;/strong&gt; Find the mail servers responsible for a domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Basic Lookups: The First Step&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s start with the simplest query: finding the IP address for a domain. This is known as an &lt;strong&gt;A record&lt;/strong&gt; lookup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to use it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;nslookup google.com 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What to look for:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The output gives you two key pieces of information. First, it tells you which DNS server answered your request. Then, it provides the answer itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example of a successful lookup:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Server:		192.168.1.1
Address:	192.168.1.1#53&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-authoritative answer:
Name:	google.com
Address: 142.250.217.78&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;Non-authoritative answer&amp;quot; just means your local DNS server gave you a cached answer rather than asking Google&#39;s official servers directly. The important part is the &lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Address&lt;/strong&gt;, which confirms the lookup was successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Advanced Queries: Digging Deeper&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you need more than just an IP address. nslookup can ask for different types of DNS records to get more specific information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Finding Mail Servers (MX Records)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re having trouble with email, you can check the &lt;strong&gt;Mail Exchanger (MX)&lt;/strong&gt; records to see where email for a domain is supposed to be sent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to use it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-Bash&quot;&gt;
# You can also use &amp;quot;set type=mx&amp;quot; in interactive mode 
nslookup -query=mx google.com 

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What to look for:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll get a list of servers, each with a priority number. The lower the number, the higher the priority. Mail will always try to be delivered to the highest-priority server first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;google.com	mail exchanger = 10 smtp.google.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Finding a Domain&#39;s Official Name Servers (NS Records)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Name Server (NS)&lt;/strong&gt; records tell you which servers are the official source of DNS information for a domain. This is useful for checking if a domain is configured correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to use it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-Bash&quot;&gt;
nslookup -query=ns google.com 

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will return a list of the authoritative name servers for that domain, like ns1.google.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Reverse DNS Lookup (Finding the Name for an IP)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you have an IP address and want to know what domain name is associated with it? That&#39;s a &lt;strong&gt;reverse lookup (PTR record)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to use it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just give nslookup the IP address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-Bash&quot;&gt;
nslookup 8.8.8.8 

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What to look for:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The output will show you the name associated with that IP. In this case, you&#39;ll see it resolves to dns.google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.8.8.8.in-addr.arpa	name = dns.google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Using a Specific DNS Server for Your Query&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, nslookup uses your system&#39;s configured DNS server. But what if you want to see if your DNS changes have propagated to a public server like Cloudflare (1.1.1.1) or Google (8.8.8.8)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can tell nslookup to ask a specific server by adding it to the end of the command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to use it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-Bash&quot;&gt;
# Ask Cloudflare&#39;s server for the IP of google.com 
nslookup google.com 1.1.1.1 

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is incredibly useful for confirming that a DNS change is visible to the rest of the world, not just on your own network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Putting It All Together&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nslookup bridges the gap between a connection working and not working. It shifts your thinking from &amp;quot;Can I reach this server?&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;Does the internet even know how to find this server?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By learning to ask for different record types, you can diagnose not just web traffic issues but problems with email and other services, too. It’s a simple command that gives you a direct line to the fundamental address book of the internet, making it an indispensable tool for any troubleshooter.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Forget 5D Chess, Just Play the Board in Front of You</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Forget_5D_Chess_Just_Play/"/>
    <updated>2025-08-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Forget_5D_Chess_Just_Play/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve all seen it online or heard it in a meeting. Just when you thought the &amp;quot;chess, not checkers&amp;quot; cliché had finally retired, its over-the-top successor arrives: the person claiming to play &amp;quot;5D chess.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The boast is that they&#39;re not just thinking a few moves ahead; they&#39;re operating on a level that involves time travel and alternate realities. They want you to believe their strategy is so advanced, it&#39;s unfolding across dimensions we can&#39;t even see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a fun, sci-fi concept, but let&#39;s be honest: it&#39;s a meaningless escalation. It takes the flawed logic of the original phrase and pushes it into absurdity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Complexity for Its Own Sake&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a previous post &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/are_you_playing_chess_v2/&quot;&gt;The Tell-Tale Cliché: Why Chess, Not Checkers Misses the Mark&lt;/a&gt;, I made the case for checkers, a game whose simple rules hide a staggering amount of strategic depth. The beauty of a game like that, or real chess, is in mastering the complexity within a clear, defined system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;5D chess&amp;quot; boast does the opposite. It suggests that real genius isn&#39;t found in mastering a system, but in making it so convoluted that it becomes incomprehensible. The goal seems to be complexity for its own sake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But here’s the thing: adding more dimensions doesn&#39;t make you a better strategist. It just makes the game impossible to play. Real-world strategy isn&#39;t about inventing fictional timelines to navigate. It&#39;s about making smart decisions in the one, messy reality we all share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Tell-Tale Sign of a Non-Strategist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what does this tell us? When someone boasts about playing 5D chess, they&#39;re often doing the exact opposite of what a genuine strategist does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A true strategist seeks clarity. They cut through the noise to find the best path forward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;quot;5D chess&amp;quot; player creates noise. They wrap their ideas in jargon to seem more profound than they are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a clever smokescreen, really. It’s a way to avoid defending a plan by retreating into a fog of nonsense. After all, how can you question a strategy that&#39;s happening in another dimension?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, it&#39;s the same move as looking down on checkers. It&#39;s using a catchphrase to claim a level of genius without having to demonstrate it. It&#39;s an attempt to win by declaring you&#39;re playing a superior game that no one else can see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look, real strategic thinking is hard enough right here in our own dimension. It takes focus, discipline, and a deep understanding of the actual rules of the game. The most effective people aren&#39;t the ones inventing new realities; they&#39;re the ones who master the one we&#39;re in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let others have their multiverses. The best way to win is to simply play the board that&#39;s right in front of you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I Gave My Blog a Robot Assistant with GitHub Actions</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Robot_Assistant_with_GitHub_Actions/"/>
    <updated>2025-07-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Robot_Assistant_with_GitHub_Actions/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;My personal blog has been just that—personal. It&#39;s a project I work on when I have time, which means small mistakes can slip through. A typo in a CSS class, a broken link in an old post, or inconsistent code formatting. None of these are critical, but they add up. I always figured keeping things tidy required a lot of manual effort, but it turns out I just needed a robot assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That robot is &lt;strong&gt;GitHub Actions&lt;/strong&gt;. This post is about my first dive into this powerful tool: what it is, how I used it to automate quality control for my blog, and the lessons I learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Exactly Are GitHub Actions?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its core, GitHub Actions is an automation tool built right into GitHub. Think of it as a set of programmable recipes that can run whenever something happens in your repository. You can tell it to run tests, deploy your website, or, in my case, check for errors every time I push new code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole system is based on a few simple concepts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workflows&lt;/strong&gt;: These are the main recipes. You define them in a &lt;code&gt;.yml&lt;/code&gt; file that lives in a specific folder in your repository: &lt;code&gt;.github/workflows/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Events&lt;/strong&gt;: These are the triggers that start a workflow. The most common one is &lt;code&gt;push&lt;/code&gt;, which runs whenever you push code to a branch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actions&lt;/strong&gt;: These are the individual steps in your recipe. They are pre-built, shareable apps that perform a specific task, like checking out your code or running a linter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find actions for almost anything in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/marketplace?type=actions&quot;&gt;GitHub Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;, most of them free to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My Mission: Getting a Handle on Code Quality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal was straightforward: I wanted an automated way to check my blog&#39;s files for errors. This includes checking for broken links in my Markdown posts, validating my HTML, and ensuring my CSS is clean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing this manually would be tedious. Instead, I used a single, powerful action called &lt;strong&gt;MegaLinter&lt;/strong&gt;. It&#39;s an all-in-one tool that bundles over a hundred different linters for dozens of languages. It was the perfect tool for the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the process I followed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Created a Workflow&lt;/strong&gt;: I started by creating a file at &lt;code&gt;.github/workflows/mega-linter.yml&lt;/code&gt;. This file tells GitHub Actions to run MegaLinter every time I push code to my &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Run (and the Wall of Errors)&lt;/strong&gt;: The first time the action ran, it came back with over 500 errors! It was overwhelming but also helpful. It showed me all the little things, like spelling mistakes, that had accumulated over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refining the Process&lt;/strong&gt;: The default setup was too noisy. To fix this, I created a &lt;code&gt;.mega-linter.yml&lt;/code&gt; file in the root of my repository. This is a dedicated configuration file where I could fine-tune MegaLinter&#39;s behavior. I configured it to:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignore the generated &lt;code&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Temporarily disable the noisy spell-checkers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only check files that have changed in a pull request to speed things up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stop flagging warnings as build failures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few adjustments, the output became much more manageable and, more importantly, useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What GitHub Actions &lt;em&gt;Aren&#39;t&lt;/em&gt; For&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While they are incredibly versatile, Actions aren&#39;t the solution for every problem. Here are a few things they don&#39;t do well or aren&#39;t designed for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Running Your Live Application&lt;/strong&gt;: Actions are for automation &lt;em&gt;related&lt;/em&gt; to your code (testing, building, deploying). They are not a server for hosting a live, 24/7 application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long, Intensive Tasks&lt;/strong&gt;: The free runners are general-purpose virtual machines. They aren&#39;t ideal for tasks that require hours of computation or specialized hardware like GPUs, although you can get runners with more power.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complex, Interdependent Pipelines&lt;/strong&gt;: For massive enterprise projects with complex build chains, a dedicated CI/CD tool like Jenkins or CircleCI might offer more granular control. GitHub Actions is designed for ease of use and integration, making it perfect for most individual and team projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting up GitHub Actions was surprisingly simple. In just a short time, I went from not knowing what it was to having an automated system that helps me maintain my blog&#39;s quality. It’s like having a meticulous teammate who reviews every change I make. If you have a personal project on GitHub, I highly recommend giving it a try. You might be surprised by what your new robot assistant can do for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>From Joke to Playground: The Story of profitandego.com</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Joke_to_Playground/"/>
    <updated>2025-07-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Joke_to_Playground/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;It all started with a domain name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of friends and I came up with &lt;code&gt;profitandego.com&lt;/code&gt; years ago on a Lake Michigan beach. It perfectly captured the strange, satirical dance of modern ambition. I&#39;d been sitting on this domain for years, and while I wanted to do something with it, I just didn&#39;t know what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Spark: Ego as a Service (EaaS)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While reading an article about SaaS, it hit me out of nowhere. The idea stuck out for its simplicity and humor: an &amp;quot;Ego as a Service&amp;quot; (EaaS) page. The concept was simple: a single button that, when clicked, serves up a dose of over-the-top corporate praise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put together a single-page site using HTML, Tailwind CSS for styling, and vanilla JavaScript. The goal was to make it look sleek and modern, a fun contrast to the absurdity of the content. Within a day, the first version was live, complete with affirmations like, &amp;quot;Your strategic vision is so clear, it&#39;s practically a premonition.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Expanding the Joke&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site was fun, but it felt like the joke could go further. That&#39;s when I came up with the idea for satirical pricing tiers. I fleshed out three plans: &amp;quot;The Intern,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;The Manager,&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;The CEO,&amp;quot; each offering increasingly ridiculous services, from a &amp;quot;Like Bot&amp;quot; to a &amp;quot;Rival Roast Report.&amp;quot; This added a new layer to the satire, mimicking the SaaS world we&#39;ve become so familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Logo Saga&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every good (or in this case, fake) company needs a logo, and this turned into a surprisingly tricky part of the project. After a few initial designs didn&#39;t quite fit the site&#39;s aesthetic, I decided to create something new. The &amp;quot;Ascending Bar Chart&amp;quot; felt like the perfect visual gag for &amp;quot;profit.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, getting it to look right on the page was a challenge. After struggling with image padding and alignment, I landed on a much better solution: embedding the logo directly into the HTML as an SVG. I&#39;d never done this before, but I remembered read about it a couple of months back. With a little help from Google, I figured it out. This meant it would load instantly, scale perfectly, and I&#39;d never have to worry about broken image links. It was a great reminder that sometimes the most robust solution is also the simplest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Dose of Reality: Securing the Site&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the site up and running, I decided to run it through a security scanner out of curiosity. The result? A failing grade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the site is just for fun, it was a perfect learning opportunity. The report from &lt;a href=&quot;https://securityheaders.com/&quot;&gt;securityheaders.com&lt;/a&gt; showed I was missing key instructions that tell browsers how to handle my site&#39;s content securely. Since the site is hosted with Cloudflare, the fix was elegant and simple: I created a &lt;code&gt;_headers&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This single file allowed me to define all the necessary security headers, like Content-Security-Policy and X-Frame-Options, keeping the configuration right alongside my code. After pushing the file, a new scan confirmed the fix: an &amp;quot;A+&amp;quot; rating!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;An Unexpected Side Effect&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implementing a strong Content-Security-Policy (CSP) had one immediate side effect: the &amp;quot;Validate Me&amp;quot; button stopped working. This wasn&#39;t a bug, but rather the CSP doing its job perfectly. It blocked the &amp;quot;inline&amp;quot; JavaScript I had originally written directly in my &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution was to refactor the code. I moved the JavaScript from the &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; file into its own &lt;code&gt;script.js&lt;/code&gt; file. After updating the HTML to reference the new external script, the button was back in business, and the site was more secure and better organized for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why Bother?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the site&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/KnowOneActual/profitandego_website/blob/main/README.md&quot;&gt;README file on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; says, this project is a playground. It&#39;s a low-stakes environment where I can try out new ideas, test Cloudflare features, and just have fun building something. It&#39;s a reminder that not every project needs to be a serious venture. Sometimes, the best way to learn is by building something for the joy of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>That Flash Drive Isn&#39;t Broken, It&#39;s Just Full of Mac &#39;Crumbs&#39;</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/That_Flash_Drive%20_Isn&#39;t_Broken/"/>
    <updated>2025-07-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/That_Flash_Drive%20_Isn&#39;t_Broken/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever loaded a USB flash drive with music or movies, plugged it into your media player (like a Micca), TV, or car stereo, and been met with a complete mess? You can see your files, but they&#39;re surrounded by weird, unplayable &amp;quot;ghost&amp;quot; files, many starting with &lt;code&gt;._&lt;/code&gt; or named &lt;code&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a super common problem, and the good news is your drive isn&#39;t broken! It&#39;s just cluttered with hidden helper files that macOS leaves behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;So, What Are These Mystery Files?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever you use a Mac, it creates small files to remember things like custom icon positions, folder view settings (&lt;code&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt;), and other metadata (&lt;code&gt;._&lt;/code&gt; files). On a Mac, this is a helpful system that makes the user experience feel seamless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem starts when you take that drive to a device that doesn&#39;t speak &amp;quot;Mac&amp;quot;—like a Windows PC, a smart TV, a digital projector, or your car&#39;s media player. To these devices, the helper files are just digital junk. They show up as unplayable files, cluttering your folders and making it hard to find what you&#39;re actually looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, cleaning them up is easy. Here are two simple, one-click solutions to tidy up your drives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Fix for Windows Users&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re on Windows and got a drive from a Mac user, this little script is your best friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download the Script:&lt;/strong&gt; Go to the GitHub repository here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/KnowOneActual/AppleCrumbs-Remover-Windows&quot;&gt;AppleCrumbs-Remover for Windows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Click on the &lt;code&gt;CleanDrive.bat&lt;/code&gt; file and then click the &amp;quot;Download raw file&amp;quot; button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Run It:&lt;/strong&gt; Find the &lt;code&gt;CleanDrive.bat&lt;/code&gt; file you downloaded and double-click it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enter the Drive Letter:&lt;/strong&gt; A command window will pop up asking for the drive letter of your flash drive (like &lt;code&gt;E:&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;F:&lt;/code&gt;). Type the correct letter and hit Enter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confirm:&lt;/strong&gt; It will give you a final warning. Press any key to continue, and the script will quickly sweep through the drive, deleting all the Mac-specific junk files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s it! Your drive is now clean and ready to use anywhere without the extra clutter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to Clean a Drive on Your Mac (Before Sharing)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re a Mac user sharing a drive, it&#39;s good practice to clean it first. The easiest method is to create a &amp;quot;Quick Action&amp;quot; that lets you clean any drive with a simple right-click. You only have to set this up once!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get the Script:&lt;/strong&gt; First, you need the script itself. You can find it here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/KnowOneActual/-AppleCrumbs-Remover-MAC&quot;&gt;AppleCrumbs-Remover for Mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Just copy the entire block of code from the &lt;code&gt;clean_drive.sh&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Automator:&lt;/strong&gt; This handy app is already on your Mac. You can find it in your &lt;code&gt;Applications&lt;/code&gt; folder or by searching with Spotlight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create the Quick Action:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Automator, choose &amp;quot;New Document&amp;quot; &amp;gt; &amp;quot;Quick Action&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the top, set the workflow to receive &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;files or folders&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;Finder&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the actions library on the left, search for &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;Run Shell Script&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; and drag it into the main workflow area on the right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the &amp;quot;Run Shell Script&amp;quot; box, delete any text that&#39;s already there and paste the code you copied from GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Save Your Action:&lt;/strong&gt; Go to &lt;strong&gt;File &amp;gt; Save&lt;/strong&gt; and name it something memorable, like &amp;quot;Clean Drive for Sharing&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, whenever you want to clean a USB drive, just right-click on its icon on your desktop, go to &lt;strong&gt;Quick Actions&lt;/strong&gt; in the menu, and select your &amp;quot;Clean Drive for Sharing&amp;quot; action. In a moment, it&#39;ll be ready to hand off, completely free of any digital crumbs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Recording a Last-Minute &#39;Voice of God&#39; in Reaper</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Last_Minute_VoG_reaper/"/>
    <updated>2025-07-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Last_Minute_VoG_reaper/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s a scenario every event audio tech knows well: the show is about to start, and a last-minute &amp;quot;Voice of God&amp;quot; (VOG) announcement needs to be recorded. All eyes are on you. It&#39;s time to work some magic with the tools you have on hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a straightforward guide to capturing a clean, professional-sounding VOG using a simple USB interface, a laptop with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reaper.fm/&quot;&gt;REAPER&lt;/a&gt;, and the trusty Shure SM58.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;First, Find Your &amp;quot;Vocal Booth&amp;quot;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you plug anything in, your top priority is finding the best possible place to record. In a bustling event space, this can be tricky, but it&#39;s essential for avoiding background noise and ugly room echo in your recording.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your goal is to find a space that is as &amp;quot;dead&amp;quot; as possible, meaning it absorbs sound instead of letting it bounce around. Look for a small, quiet room away from the main action. A storage closet, an empty office, or even a quiet corner can work in a pinch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve found your spot, build a makeshift vocal booth. Grab any soft materials you can find—coats, blankets, or event draping are perfect. Drape them over mic stands or chairs to build a small enclosure. This will help absorb vocal reflections and block out some of that distracting ambient noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Gear and Mic Technique&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With your impromptu studio ready, it&#39;s time to get your gear set up for a great take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Using the SM58&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shure SM58 is a legend for a reason. Its cardioid pickup pattern is a lifesaver in noisy environments because it’s designed to pick up sound from the front and reject sound from the sides and rear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a clear voiceover, have the speaker hold the microphone about 4-6 inches from their mouth. This gives you a full, present sound. If you get too close, the &amp;quot;proximity effect&amp;quot; will kick in and make the voice sound boomy and muffled. Make sure the speaker is talking directly into the top of the mic, not across it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The All-Important Pop Filter&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pop filter is crucial for stopping plosives—those harsh &amp;quot;p&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;b&amp;quot; sounds that can ruin a take. If you don’t have a real one, no problem. You can make an effective one with items found at almost any event:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Sock Method:&lt;/strong&gt; A clean, thin dress sock pulled over the microphone&#39;s grille works surprisingly well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Coat Hanger &amp;amp; Pantyhose:&lt;/strong&gt; Bend a wire coat hanger into a circle. Stretch a pair of pantyhose over the frame and use gaffer tape to attach it to the mic stand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Setting Up Your Reaper Session&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a New Track:&lt;/strong&gt; In your Reaper project, go to the &lt;code&gt;Track&lt;/code&gt; menu and select &lt;code&gt;Insert new track&lt;/code&gt; (or use the shortcut &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+T&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arm the Track &amp;amp; Select Your Input:&lt;/strong&gt; Click the red &lt;code&gt;Arm for recording&lt;/code&gt; button on the new track. Next, click the input box (which usually says &lt;code&gt;Input 1&lt;/code&gt;) and choose the correct input from your USB audio interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check Your Levels:&lt;/strong&gt; Have the person read a line from the announcement at the volume they&#39;ll be using. Watch the track&#39;s meter. You want the level to average around &lt;strong&gt;-12dBFS&lt;/strong&gt;, with the loudest peaks hitting about &lt;strong&gt;-6dBFS&lt;/strong&gt;. As long as the meter stays in the green and yellow, you&#39;re good. If it hits red, the signal is clipping (distorting), and you&#39;ll need to turn down the gain on your audio interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Quick and Effective FX Chain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have a good take, you can use a few of Reaper&#39;s excellent built-in plugins (ReaPlugs) to add a professional polish. Click the &lt;code&gt;FX&lt;/code&gt; button on your track to open the effects window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a simple chain that works wonders for VOG recordings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ReaEQ:&lt;/strong&gt; Start with an EQ to clean up the signal. Add a &lt;code&gt;High Pass&lt;/code&gt; filter and set the &lt;code&gt;Frequency&lt;/code&gt; to around &lt;strong&gt;80-100Hz&lt;/strong&gt;. This removes low-end rumble from things like HVAC systems. You can also use ReaEQ to tame any harsh &amp;quot;s&amp;quot; sounds (sibilance). Find the frequency where the &amp;quot;s&amp;quot; is most piercing (usually 5-8kHz) and use a narrow &lt;code&gt;Band&lt;/code&gt; to cut it by a few decibels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ReaComp:&lt;/strong&gt; Next, add a compressor to even out the volume. Think of it as an automatic volume fader. A &lt;code&gt;Ratio&lt;/code&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;3:1&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;4:1&lt;/strong&gt; is a great starting point. Lower the &lt;code&gt;Threshold&lt;/code&gt; until you see the meter showing about &lt;strong&gt;3-6dB&lt;/strong&gt; of gain reduction on the loudest words. This will make the entire announcement sound more consistent and easier to understand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JS: Master Limiter:&lt;/strong&gt; Add this JS plugin at the end of your chain to make the final recording loud and clear without clipping. It raises the overall volume and sets a hard ceiling that the audio can&#39;t go past. Simply adjust the &lt;code&gt;Threshold&lt;/code&gt; to get a strong final level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’re happy with the sound, it&#39;s time to render the file. Go to &lt;code&gt;File &amp;gt; Render&lt;/code&gt; and choose your output format (WAV is best for quality).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&#39;s it! With a little resourcefulness and these quick tips, you can turn a last-minute request into a polished, professional recording that&#39;s ready for the show.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Recording a Last-Minute &#39;Voice of God&#39;: in Logic Pro</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/last_minute_VOG_logicpro/"/>
    <updated>2025-07-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/last_minute_VOG_logicpro/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a familiar scenario for any event&#39;s audio tech: the show is about to start, and a last-minute &amp;quot;Voice of God&amp;quot; (VOG) announcement needs to be recorded. With everyone looking to you, it&#39;s time to work some magic with the tools you have on hand. Here&#39;s a straightforward guide to capturing a clean, professional-sounding VOG on-site with a USB interface, a laptop with Logic Pro, and the trusty Shure SM58.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Setting the Scene: Your Impromptu Vocal Booth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you even plug anything in, your first priority is to find the best possible recording location. In a bustling event space, this can be a challenge, but it&#39;s crucial for minimizing background noise and unwanted room reflections in your recording.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your goal is to create a space that is as &amp;quot;dead&amp;quot; as possible, meaning it absorbs sound rather than letting it bounce around. Look for a small, quiet room away from the main event floor. A storage closet, an office, or even a quiet corner can work in a pinch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&#39;ve found your spot, it&#39;s time to build a makeshift vocal booth. Grab any soft materials you can find—coats, blankets, or event draping are perfect. Drape them over mic stands, chairs, or anything else you can use to build a small enclosure where you&#39;ll be recording. This will help to absorb your voice&#39;s reflections and block out some of the ambient noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gear Up: The Essentials for a Clean Take&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With your impromptu studio ready, it&#39;s time to get your gear set up for success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Mic Technique with the SM58&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shure SM58 is a fantastic microphone for live vocals, and its cardioid pickup pattern is a lifesaver in noisy environments. This pattern means it primarily picks up sound from directly in front of it while rejecting sound from the sides and rear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a clear voiceover, have the speaker hold the microphone about 4-6 inches away from their mouth. This proximity will give you a nice, full sound without being too boomy. If you get too close, the &amp;quot;proximity effect&amp;quot; of the SM58 will kick in, adding a muddy low-end to the voice. Have the speaker talk directly into the top of the microphone, not across it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The All-Important Pop Filter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pop filter is essential for preventing &amp;quot;plosives&amp;quot;—those harsh &amp;quot;p&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;b&amp;quot; sounds that can ruin a recording. If you don&#39;t have a commercial one on hand, don&#39;t worry. You can easily make one with items likely found at any event:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Sock Method:&lt;/strong&gt; A clean, thin dress sock pulled over the microphone&#39;s grille can work wonders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Coat Hanger &amp;amp; Pantyhose:&lt;/strong&gt; Find a wire coat hanger and bend it into a circular shape. Stretch a pair of pantyhose over the wireframe, and you have a surprisingly effective pop filter. You can then attach this to the mic stand with some gaffer tape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recording and Polishing in Logic Pro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With your talent in the &amp;quot;booth&amp;quot; and your mic ready to go, it&#39;s time to launch Logic Pro and get ready to record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Setting Up Your Session&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a New Audio Track:&lt;/strong&gt; Open a new Logic Pro project and create a new audio track.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set Your Input:&lt;/strong&gt; In the channel strip on the left, make sure the input is set to your USB audio interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check Your Levels:&lt;/strong&gt; Have the person speaking do a test run of the announcement. Watch the meter on the audio track. You want the level to be consistently in the green and yellow, with the loudest peaks just barely touching the orange. You never want the meter to hit red, as this means your audio is clipping and will be distorted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Quick and Effective Effects Chain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have a good take, it&#39;s time to add a few touches to make it shine. Logic Pro&#39;s built-in plugins are more than capable of getting a professional sound quickly. A great starting point is to use one of Logic&#39;s vocal presets. In the Library, you can find a variety of vocal channel strips that will load a pre-configured chain of effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a simple and effective chain you can also build yourself for a clean VOG:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EQ (Channel EQ):&lt;/strong&gt; The first thing you&#39;ll want to do is roll off any unnecessary low-end rumble. Apply a high-pass filter and set it to around 80-100Hz. This will clean up the voice without making it sound thin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DeEsser:&lt;/strong&gt; This will tame any harsh &amp;quot;s&amp;quot; sounds. Logic&#39;s DeEsser is very effective. Start with a preset and adjust the threshold until you hear the sibilance soften.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compressor:&lt;/strong&gt; A compressor will even out the volume of the voice, making it sound more consistent and present. Logic&#39;s stock compressor has a &amp;quot;Vocal&amp;quot; preset that is a great starting point. You want to aim for just a few decibels of gain reduction on the meter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limiter:&lt;/strong&gt; To make the final recording loud and clear for playback, add a limiter at the end of your chain. This will bring up the overall volume without letting it clip.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&#39;re happy with the sound, bounce the track as a high-quality WAV or MP3 file, and your &amp;quot;Voice of God&amp;quot; is ready to be heard. With a bit of resourcefulness and these quick tips, you can deliver a polished, professional recording, even when the clock is ticking.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>From Flash Drive Frenzy to Slideshow Serenity</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Slideshow_Serenity/"/>
    <updated>2025-07-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Slideshow_Serenity/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve all been there. You&#39;re minutes away from the start of a corporate event, and someone hands you a flash drive packed with hundreds of photos. The request? &amp;quot;Can we get these looping on the big screen?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That moment of quiet panic is a rite of passage in the event world. But it doesn&#39;t have to be. Instead of manually inserting, resizing, and centering every single image, you can automate the entire process. Let&#39;s walk through two fantastic ways to turn that chaotic folder of photos into a polished, professional PowerPoint slideshow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Method 1: The Ultimate Automation with Python&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself tackling this task often, a Python script is your new best friend. It&#39;s fast, reusable, and does all the heavy lifting for you. To make this as easy as possible, I&#39;ve created a script called &lt;strong&gt;SlideWrangler&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why use a script?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&#39;s incredibly fast.&lt;/strong&gt; It processes hundreds of images in seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&#39;s smart.&lt;/strong&gt; SlideWrangler automatically fixes sideways photos, skips non-image files, and optimizes everything for screen display.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&#39;s consistent.&lt;/strong&gt; Every slideshow comes out perfectly formatted, every time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to get it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the code and step-by-step instructions are available on GitHub. Just head over to the repository to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;➡️ &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/KnowOneActual/SlideWrangler&quot;&gt;Get SlideWrangler on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The README file there will walk you through the simple setup. In just a few minutes, you&#39;ll have a powerful tool ready to handle any photo dump that comes your way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Method 2: The Quick Fix Inside PowerPoint&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re not ready to dive into scripting or just need a quick, one-time solution, PowerPoint has a great built-in feature that works wonders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why use this method?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No setup required.&lt;/strong&gt; Everything you need is already part of PowerPoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&#39;s visual and intuitive.&lt;/strong&gt; You can see what you&#39;re doing every step of the way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&#39;s surprisingly fast.&lt;/strong&gt; While not as automated as the script, it&#39;s much faster than adding photos one by one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here&#39;s how you do it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open PowerPoint and go to the &lt;strong&gt;Insert&lt;/strong&gt; tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on &lt;strong&gt;Photo Album&lt;/strong&gt; and select &lt;strong&gt;New Photo Album...&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new window will pop up. Click the &lt;strong&gt;File/Disk...&lt;/strong&gt; button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigate to the flash drive or folder with the images, select all of them (a handy shortcut is Ctrl+A), and click &lt;strong&gt;Insert&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the Photo Album window, you can make a few adjustments. For a standard look, set the &lt;strong&gt;Picture layout&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;Fit to slide&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt;, and PowerPoint will instantly generate a new presentation with one photo on each slide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Which Method is Right for You?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re an event tech or someone who handles presentations regularly, taking a few minutes to set up &lt;strong&gt;SlideWrangler&lt;/strong&gt; will pay off immensely in the long run. For a quick, one-off task, the built-in Photo Album feature is a lifesaver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, you&#39;re now equipped to handle that last-minute flash drive with confidence. No more frantic clicking—just a smooth, seamless slideshow, ready for the show.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Case for a Second Look: Why Revisiting Your Writing is a Superpower</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/the_case_for_a_second_look/"/>
    <updated>2025-07-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/the_case_for_a_second_look/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;We all know the feeling: you&#39;ve wrestled with a piece of writing, polished the sentences, and finally hit &amp;quot;publish.&amp;quot; The sense of relief is huge. It&#39;s done. It&#39;s out in the world. The last thing you want to do is open that file again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a common pressure to always be moving forward, to ship the work and start the next thing. We often feel that going back to revise something we&#39;ve already written is a step backward, an admission that we didn&#39;t get it right the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that&#39;s the wrong way to look at it. Revisiting your work isn&#39;t about fixing a failure; it&#39;s about giving your ideas the best possible chance to shine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Power of Fresh Eyes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever found an old draft of something you wrote and felt like you were reading the words of a stranger? That&#39;s a good thing. The person who wrote that draft isn&#39;t quite the same person you are today. Time gives you the one thing you can&#39;t have in the moment: perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you step away from a piece for a few days or even a few weeks, you sever the emotional attachment to the sentences you labored over. You&#39;re no longer invested in &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; you said something, only in &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; you actually said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This distance makes it easier to spot the gaps. You might realize your killer opening is buried on page two, or that your core argument is being overshadowed by a weaker, flashier point. I went through this recently with a post. A first draft had a strong, logical argument, but a later version had much better stories and examples. Separately, they were okay. When I came back later, it was obvious that the real magic would come from combining the brain of the first draft with the voice of the second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting an Outside Opinion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as valuable as your own fresh eyes is a pair from someone else. When you&#39;re deep in a topic, you can&#39;t always see the gaps in your own logic—your brain automatically fills them in. You have the curse of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An outside reader, whether it&#39;s a friend, a colleague, or even an AI assistant, doesn&#39;t have that curse. They can instantly tell you where your argument gets a little fuzzy or which examples truly land. This feedback isn&#39;t about changing your point; it&#39;s about helping you make your own point more effectively. They hold up a mirror so you can see your work clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Think &amp;quot;Director&#39;s Cut,&amp;quot; Not &amp;quot;Correction&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to frame this process is to think of it as creating a &amp;quot;director&#39;s cut&amp;quot; of your work. You&#39;re not fixing mistakes. You&#39;re taking the original material and making it richer, deeper, and more compelling with the benefit of hindsight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revisiting a piece allows you to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sharpen your argument:&lt;/strong&gt; Cut the fat and make your core message unmistakable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strengthen your evidence:&lt;/strong&gt; Swap out weaker points for more powerful examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improve the flow:&lt;/strong&gt; Restructure paragraphs and sentences so your ideas unfold naturally for the reader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the next time you hesitate to reopen a &amp;quot;finished&amp;quot; document, remember that revision is a creative act, not a corrective one. It&#39;s a sign of a writer who cares about their craft and their audience. Go look at an old post. Your best work might just be a second look away.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Okay, I Have the Hacker Mindset. Now What?</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Hacker_Mindset/"/>
    <updated>2025-07-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Hacker_Mindset/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Okay, I Have the Hacker Mindset. Now What?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the post &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/already_be_a_hacker/&quot;&gt;You Might Already Be a Hacker and Not Even Know It&lt;/a&gt;, we explored the idea that being a hacker isn&#39;t about what you see in the movies. It&#39;s a mindset—a spirit of curiosity, creative probl/Users/userx/website_BB/Blog/draft posts/Hacker_Mindset.mdem-solving, and the drive to understand how things &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you read that and thought, &amp;quot;That sounds like me,&amp;quot; you probably finished with the exact question in this title. It&#39;s exciting to identify with a new way of thinking, but it can be hard to know what to &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; with that energy. How do you go from feeling like a hacker to actually, well, hacking something?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s what this post is all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal here isn&#39;t to turn you into a master programmer or engineer overnight. The goal is to give you a playground, a few simple, low-stakes projects where you can start putting that curiosity into practice. It&#39;s time to move from theory to tinkering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s look at a few fun ways to get your hands dirty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Project 1: The Kitchen Hack — Your First System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we touch a line of code, let&#39;s start with a system most of us know: a simple recipe. A recipe is just a program for producing food. Our goal isn&#39;t just to cook, but to intentionally modify the program to get a different result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Mission:&lt;/strong&gt; Take a simple recipe and change one variable to achieve a specific, desired outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Toolkit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A simple, familiar recipe (think chocolate chip cookies, pancakes, or a basic tomato sauce).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A notebook and pen (or a notes app).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Steps:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choose Your System:&lt;/strong&gt; Pick a recipe you&#39;ve made before. For this example, let&#39;s use chocolate chip cookies. The standard recipe is our &amp;quot;known system.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Define Your Goal:&lt;/strong&gt; Be specific. Don&#39;t just aim for &amp;quot;better.&amp;quot; What does &amp;quot;better&amp;quot; mean? Let&#39;s say our goal is to make the cookies &lt;em&gt;chewier&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Form a Hypothesis:&lt;/strong&gt; This is the core of hacking. What do you &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; will make the cookies chewier? Your hypothesis is: &amp;quot;Using melted butter will increase the chewiness of the final cookie.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Run the Experiment:&lt;/strong&gt; Make two small, separate batches: the &lt;strong&gt;Control&lt;/strong&gt; (original recipe) and the &lt;strong&gt;Test&lt;/strong&gt; (with melted butter).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analyze the Data:&lt;/strong&gt; Now, for the best part —the peer review process. Taste both cookies! Was your hypothesis correct? Did it have other effects? Write down what you learned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why This is Hacking:&lt;/strong&gt; You just ran the essential hacker loop. You analyzed a system (the recipe), formed a hypothesis, ran a controlled test, and analyzed the results. You weren&#39;t just following instructions; you were actively manipulating a system to make it do what you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Project 2: The Automation Hack — A Taste of Code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you&#39;ve hacked a real-world system, let&#39;s apply the same thinking to a digital one. A common hacker activity is automating boring, repetitive tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Mission:&lt;/strong&gt; Use a few lines of simple code to solve a small, repetitive problem on your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Toolkit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A computer with Python installed (free from &lt;a href=&quot;https://python.org/&quot;&gt;python.org&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A simple text editor (like Notepad, TextEdit, or VS Code).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Steps:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find Your Repetitive Task:&lt;/strong&gt; Imagine you want to rename hundreds of photos like &lt;code&gt;IMG_4021.JPG&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;Vacation_2025_1.JPG&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Think Through the Logic:&lt;/strong&gt; Before coding, plan in plain English: Tell the program where to look, retrieve a list of files, create a new name for each, and then perform the renaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write the &amp;quot;Spell&amp;quot; (The Code):&lt;/strong&gt; This logic translates into Python. Save this as &lt;code&gt;rename_files.py&lt;/code&gt; in a folder with a &lt;em&gt;copy&lt;/em&gt; of your photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-python:rename_files.py&quot;&gt;import os

# The folder with your photos. The &amp;quot;.&amp;quot; means &amp;quot;this current folder&amp;quot;.
folder_path = &amp;quot;.&amp;quot;
# What you want the new name to be.
new_name_base = &amp;quot;Vacation_2025_&amp;quot;
# A counter to make each filename unique.
counter = 1

# Loop through every file in the folder.
for filename in os.listdir(folder_path):
    # Check if the file is a JPG image.
    if filename.endswith(&amp;quot;.JPG&amp;quot;):
        # Create the new filename.
        new_filename = f&amp;quot;{new_name_base}{counter}.JPG&amp;quot;
        # Rename the file.
        os.rename(filename, new_filename)
        # Add 1 to the counter for the next loop.
        counter += 1

print(&amp;quot;File renaming complete!&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Run the Experiment:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Important:&lt;/strong&gt; Test this on a &lt;em&gt;copy&lt;/em&gt; of your files first! Open your computer&#39;s command line or terminal, navigate to that folder, and type &lt;code&gt;python rename_files.py&lt;/code&gt;. Press Enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why This is Hacking:&lt;/strong&gt; You didn&#39;t do the work; you built a tool to do the work for you. You analyzed a tedious system, understood its rules, and wrote new, more powerful rules (your script) to get the job done instantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Project 3: The Information Hack — Look Under the Hood&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hackers need to see how things work. Let&#39;s take a common &amp;quot;black box&amp;quot;—a website—and peek under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Mission:&lt;/strong&gt; Use your browser&#39;s built-in tools to inspect and temporarily change any website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Toolkit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your web browser (Chrome, Firefox, Edge, etc.). That&#39;s it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Steps:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choose Your Subject:&lt;/strong&gt; Go to any website. A simple blog or news article is a great starting point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open the &amp;quot;Secret&amp;quot; Tools:&lt;/strong&gt; Right-click on any element on the page (a headline, a paragraph) and choose &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;Inspect&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;Inspect Element.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See the Skeleton (HTML):&lt;/strong&gt; A panel will open showing the site&#39;s code. As you move your mouse over the code, the corresponding parts of the page will highlight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Run the Experiment (Change Reality):&lt;/strong&gt; Find a headline in the code panel, double-click the text, type something new, and press Enter. You just changed the webpage on your screen! (This is temporary and only on your computer).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why This is Hacking:&lt;/strong&gt; You deconstructed a system to understand its components. This desire to peel back the layers and refuse to accept a system at face value is the essence of the hacker mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Your Turn to Play&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a cookie recipe to a folder of messy files to the website you&#39;re reading right now, you&#39;ve seen the hacker mindset in action. The common thread wasn&#39;t about being a master chef or an expert coder; it was about the process. It was about being curious enough to ask, &amp;quot;What if I tried this?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s the secret. Hacking isn&#39;t a single skill you need to master. It&#39;s a habit you can build by refusing to accept that things have to be the way they are. It&#39;s the habit of looking at a system and wanting to understand it, adapt it, and make it work better for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&#39;t need a grand plan. Your next step is simply to start looking for opportunities in your own life. The next time you face a tedious task, a frustrating process, or a &amp;quot;black box&amp;quot; you don&#39;t understand, let that little question pop into your head:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I wonder if there&#39;s a better way?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s the spark. Now go find something to tinker with. The playground is open.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>You Might Already Be a Hacker and Not Even Know It</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Already_Be_a_Hacker_v2/"/>
    <updated>2025-07-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Already_Be_a_Hacker_v2/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h3&gt;You Might Already Be a Hacker and Not Even Know It&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, the handle on my favorite coffee mug snapped off. The original handle was always a bit thin and awkward, so instead of just trying to glue it back to normal, I saw a chance to improve it. After setting the broken pieces with strong epoxy, I tightly wrapped the entire handle with thick, sturdy silicone tape. It now has a thicker, more comfortable grip that fits my hand perfectly. The mug is no longer just a generic object; it’s been customized just for me. It’s unique, and it genuinely works better than before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That small act of looking at a broken system and figuring out how to make it serve my own purpose? That’s closer to the heart of hacking than anything you’ll see in the movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forget the hoodie. Forget the glowing green code scrolling down a dark screen. The image of the &amp;quot;hacker&amp;quot; that Hollywood sold us isn&#39;t just dramatic—it misses the entire point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a hacker has very little to do with breaking into banks and everything to do with a certain kind of creative spark. At its core, it’s about one simple thing: looking at a system or a process and figuring out how to make it do what &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; want it to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Joy of the Winding Path&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of us are taught to follow instructions. We’re given a map and told that success means getting from Point A to Point B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A hacker enjoys the journey off the map. They start with a question, like &amp;quot;What if I tried this?&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;I wonder why this works this way?&amp;quot;. From there, the process is a winding path of discovery. You rarely know where you&#39;re going to end up when you start. You might begin trying to fix one small problem and stumble upon a brilliant solution for a completely different one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not about having all the answers. It’s about being curious enough to start asking the questions and patient enough to follow where they lead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Following the Recipe vs. Inventing a New Dish&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let&#39;s be clear: following a &amp;quot;recipe&amp;quot; is a valuable and necessary skill. Whether it’s running a script to test a network, using a tutorial to learn a new program, or following a guide to fix a leaky faucet, using an established process is how things get done reliably. There is absolutely nothing wrong with that; it&#39;s how we build and maintain the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the hacker is the one who invents the recipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They’re the chef who’s tired of the standard menu and starts combining new ingredients, tasting, and tweaking until they create a dish that’s uniquely theirs. They are driven by a specific goal—&amp;quot;I want a dish that tastes like a summer evening&amp;quot;—and they learn through trial and error how to make that happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a script someone else wrote is executing a known process. Figuring out how to combine three different tools in a way no one has before to solve your unique problem? That’s the hacker mindset. This philosophy is so central to the world of technology that it was famously documented in essays like Eric S. Raymond&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.catb.org/~esr/faqs/hacker-howto.html&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;How To Become A Hacker,&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; which focuses more on this spirit of creative problem-solving than on any specific technical skill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Hacking is Everywhere&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the most important part: this mindset isn’t limited to technology. It’s a way of approaching any challenge or craft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;mechanic&lt;/strong&gt; who listens to an engine and realizes the problem isn&#39;t what the diagnostic computer says it is, but is instead a clever workaround to fix a recurring issue, is a hacker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;teacher&lt;/strong&gt; who realizes the standard lesson plan isn&#39;t connecting with their students and redesigns the entire curriculum with new projects and activities is a hacker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;craft maker&lt;/strong&gt; who looks at a knitting pattern and says, &amp;quot;This is nice, but I&#39;m going to modify it to create a totally different design&amp;quot; is a hacker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They all see a system—an engine, a lesson plan, a pattern—and adapt it to better suit their needs. They are problem-solvers who aren&#39;t afraid to experiment to get the result they want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, look at how you approach your work, your hobbies, and your life. Do you ever go off-script? Do you find joy in figuring things out for yourself? Do you ever tinker with something just to see if you can make it better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If so, you’ve already got the spark. You don&#39;t need to learn to code to be a hacker. You just need to stay curious. Welcome to the club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&#39;m curious—what&#39;s a system you&#39;ve &amp;quot;hacked&amp;quot; in your own life?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>From Bright Idea to Browser: My Journey Building a Network Monitor (and What I Learned When Things Went Sideways)</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Building_a_Network_Monitor/"/>
    <updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Building_a_Network_Monitor/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered what goes on behind the scenes when you interact with a website? Let&#39;s dive into a common challenge in web development and my journey to build a useful tool, even when my initial plans hit a few snags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone! I&#39;m sharing a glimpse behind the scenes of my latest web development project. If you&#39;ve poked around my site lately, you might have noticed a shiny new &amp;quot;Network Latency Monitor&amp;quot; in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://beaubremer.com/#my_projects&quot;&gt;My Projects&lt;/a&gt;. It’s not just a tool; it’s a story about a great idea, a few head-scratching problems, and the beautiful mess of trial and error that makes development so rewarding (and occasionally, frustrating!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Spark: A Speed Test with &amp;quot;Wow Factor&amp;quot;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, I had this neat idea: a network speed test. I thought, &amp;quot;How cool would it be to have a built-in speed checker right on my site?&amp;quot; It felt like a fantastic way to showcase my developing web development skills, my understanding of network principles, and just add a little bit of that interactive &amp;quot;wow factor.&amp;quot; I drafted up a client-side version using JavaScript, complete with progress bars and even parallel connections for downloads and uploads. If you&#39;d like to check it out &lt;a href=&quot;https://beaubremer.com/speed_test&quot;&gt;Network Speed Test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial results? Well, they were... interesting. My script would report a download speed of around 4 Mbps, while a commercial service like Speedtest.net would confidently tell me I was cruising at 400 Mbps! Clearly, something was off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hitting the Wall: Why My Speed Test Wasn&#39;t Usable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some troubleshooting, I realized the core limitation: building a truly accurate speed test with purely client-side JavaScript is incredibly difficult. Commercial speed tests utilize dedicated, high-performance servers distributed globally and employ complex techniques to thoroughly test your connection&#39;s capabilities. My simple script, hitting generic public endpoints like &lt;code&gt;httpbin.org&lt;/code&gt;, just couldn&#39;t give me the results I was looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It became clear: for all its &amp;quot;wow factor,&amp;quot; if the numbers weren&#39;t accurate, the tool wasn&#39;t truly &amp;quot;usable.&amp;quot; And if a tool isn&#39;t usable, it probably shouldn&#39;t be on the front page of your site!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Pivot! From Speed to Stability: The Network Latency Monitor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I had to make a decision. Scrap the idea entirely? Or pivot? I chose to pivot. Instead of chasing elusive bandwidth numbers, I decided to build a tool that &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; be accurate and useful within my constraints: a &lt;strong&gt;Network Latency Monitor&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea was simple: instead of measuring &lt;em&gt;how fast&lt;/em&gt; data flows, let’s measure &lt;em&gt;how quickly&lt;/em&gt; it responds and if it’s available. This highlights different, but equally important, networking skills – those related to troubleshooting, availability, and responsiveness. Latency, the time it takes for a signal to travel from one point to another, is a crucial indicator of network responsiveness and a great way to assess connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Journey Continues: New Code, New Headaches (Totally Normal!)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building the latency monitor wasn’t a straight line from idea to completion, either. This is where the &amp;quot;trial and error&amp;quot; comes in – and why it&#39;s so vital in development!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Silent Startup:&lt;/strong&gt; My initial draft of the monitor wouldn&#39;t even start checking the default sites automatically. A quick dive into the console revealed a simple JavaScript error: &lt;code&gt;this.startMonitoringAll is not a function&lt;/code&gt;. A quick rearrangement of code, and it was alive!
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What I Learned:&lt;/em&gt; The browser console is your first and best friend for catching those tricky JavaScript errors right when your page loads. Always check it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Invisible Wall (CSP):&lt;/strong&gt; Once it was running, the default &lt;code&gt;https://&lt;/code&gt; sites were showing as &amp;quot;Down.&amp;quot; The console, my best friend during these times, screamed &amp;quot;Content Security Policy (CSP) blocking!&amp;quot; My &lt;code&gt;netlify.toml&lt;/code&gt; file had a &lt;code&gt;connect-src&lt;/code&gt; directive that was too strict, preventing my own site from connecting to external domains like Google or Cloudflare. This required a small but crucial tweak to my Netlify configuration, expanding the &lt;code&gt;connect-src&lt;/code&gt; to allow all &lt;code&gt;https:&lt;/code&gt; connections.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What I Learned:&lt;/em&gt; Content Security Policy is a powerful browser security feature. While essential for protection, it&#39;s also a common reason for external resource loading issues and requires careful configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Mixed-Up Protocols:&lt;/strong&gt; Next, I hit a snag with &lt;code&gt;http://&lt;/code&gt; versus &lt;code&gt;https://&lt;/code&gt; endpoints. My monitor, running on a secure &lt;code&gt;https://&lt;/code&gt; site, was correctly blocking insecure &lt;code&gt;http://&lt;/code&gt; requests (thank you, browser security!). But I also realized that if I tried to add &lt;code&gt;http://&lt;/code&gt; URLs while testing locally (where my local server was &lt;code&gt;http://&lt;/code&gt;), those &lt;code&gt;http://&lt;/code&gt; URLs worked, but &lt;code&gt;https://&lt;/code&gt; ones sometimes failed. This was a confusing dance between local environment behavior and deployed site behavior. The solution: stick firmly to &lt;code&gt;https://&lt;/code&gt; for external monitoring and be very clear with users about this limitation.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What I Learned:&lt;/em&gt; Always be mindful of protocol differences (&lt;code&gt;http&lt;/code&gt; vs. &lt;code&gt;https&lt;/code&gt;) and how they behave in both local development and deployed environments. Browser security models are designed to keep users safe, even if they occasionally make development a little trickier!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Reappearing Act:&lt;/strong&gt; Even after successfully deleting endpoints, they&#39;d pop back up on refresh. It turns out that the monitor was loading a hardcoded list of defaults every time the page loaded, overriding my changes. Implementing &lt;code&gt;localStorage&lt;/code&gt; resolved this issue, allowing the monitor to remember user-added or removed endpoints.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What I Learned:&lt;/em&gt; For persistent user preferences or data that should survive a page refresh, &lt;code&gt;localStorage&lt;/code&gt; is a super handy browser API to remember things between sessions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;My Big Takeaway: Embrace the Process!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entire experience, from the ambitious (and slightly flawed) speed test to the fully functional latency monitor, reinforced some core beliefs about development:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You don&#39;t have to be perfect from the start.&lt;/strong&gt; Ideas evolve, and initial approaches might not be the final ones. It&#39;s all part of the learning curve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trial and error is not a sign of failure; it&#39;s the path to success.&lt;/strong&gt; Every error message, every unexpected behavior, is a clue leading you closer to a robust solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debugging tools are your superpower.&lt;/strong&gt; The browser console, network tab, and HAR files were invaluable in understanding exactly &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; things weren&#39;t working.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding constraints is key.&lt;/strong&gt; Knowing the limitations of free hosting and browser security wasn&#39;t a blocker; it shaped the project into something even better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, go ahead, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://beaubremer.com/network_latency_monitor&quot;&gt;Network Latency Monitor&lt;/a&gt; on my site! Add a few of your favorite sites, and see how it performs. And remember, every &amp;quot;bug&amp;quot; is just a puzzle waiting to be solved. I&#39;m always keen to dive into new challenges and expand my understanding of web performance!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>From Ping to Fix: A Practical Guide to Basic Network Troubleshooting</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/From_Ping_to_Fix/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/From_Ping_to_Fix/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s a familiar frustration: an application can&#39;t reach its server, your connection feels sluggish, or the internet just cuts out entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you spend hours searching forums or calling for help, you can often find the root of the problem yourself with just a few tools and a clear strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide will walk you through a practical approach to network troubleshooting. You&#39;ll learn about three essential commands, a five-step framework for thinking through any problem, and a smart strategy to make your guesswork less random.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Your Core Troubleshooting Toolkit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of these three commands as your first line of defense. They are simple, powerful, and give you a quick snapshot of the network&#39;s health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. &lt;code&gt;ping&lt;/code&gt;: Is Anyone Home?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;ping&lt;/strong&gt; command is the simplest way to check if a remote device is online and reachable. It sends a small packet of data and waits for a reply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to use it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# Pinging a well-known Google server
ping 8.8.8.8
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What to look for:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Successful Replies:&lt;/strong&gt; If you see lines that include &lt;code&gt;bytes from... time=...&lt;/code&gt;, it means there&#39;s a live connection between you and the server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Request Timed Out:&lt;/strong&gt; If you get &amp;quot;Request Timed Out&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Destination Host Unreachable,&amp;quot; there&#39;s a problem somewhere between your device and the destination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example of a successful ping:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;PING 8.8.8.8 (8.8.8.8): 56 data bytes
64 bytes from 8.8.8.8: icmp_seq=0 ttl=116 time=13.523 ms
64 bytes from 8.8.8.8: icmp_seq=1 ttl=116 time=14.128 ms
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. &lt;code&gt;traceroute&lt;/code&gt;: What&#39;s the Path?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If &lt;code&gt;ping&lt;/code&gt; fails, &lt;code&gt;traceroute&lt;/code&gt; (or &lt;code&gt;tracert&lt;/code&gt; on Windows) is your next step. It shows you the specific path, or &lt;strong&gt;hops&lt;/strong&gt;, your data takes to get to a destination. This is perfect for spotting exactly where the connection breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to use it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# Tracing the route to Google&#39;s server
traceroute 8.8.8.8
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll see a list of routers your connection passes through. If the trace stops, shows &lt;code&gt;* * *&lt;/code&gt; for multiple lines, or has a sudden, massive jump in latency (e.g., from &lt;code&gt;15ms&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;200ms&lt;/code&gt;), you&#39;ve found a major clue about where the failure is occurring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Port Checking: Is the Service Listening?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the server is online (&lt;code&gt;ping&lt;/code&gt; works), but the specific service you need (like a database or a web server) isn&#39;t responding. You need to check if the &lt;strong&gt;port&lt;/strong&gt; for that service is open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Windows (using PowerShell):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-powershell&quot;&gt;# Checks if Google&#39;s web server is responding on the standard HTTPS port (443)
Test-NetConnection google.com -Port 443
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On macOS or Linux:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# The -z flag tells nc to scan without sending data, v is for verbose
nc -zv google.com 443
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &amp;quot;success&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;open&amp;quot; message means the service is listening. A failure could point to a firewall blocking the connection or the service being down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Framework for Sanity: The 5-Step &amp;quot;Fixit&amp;quot; Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commands give you data, but a framework gives you a plan. This is a systematic way to diagnose and solve a problem without getting overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Find the Problem&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goal:&lt;/strong&gt; Clearly define what&#39;s actually failing. &amp;quot;Users can&#39;t log in&amp;quot; is far more useful than &amp;quot;the network is down.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Inspect the Symptoms&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goal:&lt;/strong&gt; Look for patterns. Does it only happen at 9 AM? Is it only affecting one person, or is it everyone on the office Wi-Fi?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Exclude Possibilities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goal:&lt;/strong&gt; Rule out what&#39;s working. If you can ping the server, you can probably exclude a full physical network outage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Implement a Hypothesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goal:&lt;/strong&gt; Form a theory and test it. &amp;quot;I think the firewall is blocking the port.&amp;quot; Now, run your port check to verify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Track the Fix&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goal:&lt;/strong&gt; Once you find the solution, write it down. This simple step saves you (and your future colleagues) from having to solve the same problem all over again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key thing to remember is that this is a loop, not a straight line. If one hypothesis fails, you just form and test a new one until you find the root cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Smarter Strategy: Thinking in Layers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you have your commands and a process, but where do you even start looking? The trick is to think about the problem in layers—from the physical cables up to the software application itself. This strategy stops you from guessing randomly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are three common approaches based on this layered thinking:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom-Up (Is it plugged in?):&lt;/strong&gt; Start at the physical layer. This is the way to go when everything is down. Begin by checking if the cables are plugged in and the Wi-Fi is on before you do anything else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top-Down (Is it the app?):&lt;/strong&gt; Start at the application layer. This is best for when a single program is failing, like your email client. Begin by checking the app&#39;s settings and logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hybrid (Start in the Middle):&lt;/strong&gt; This is a powerful strategy for almost any situation. Start with a &lt;code&gt;ping&lt;/code&gt; command. If it works, you know the lower layers are fine, and you can look &amp;quot;up&amp;quot; toward the application. If it fails, you know the problem is &amp;quot;down&amp;quot; in the physical or network setup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tying It All Together&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Troubleshooting doesn&#39;t have to be a mystery. By combining the &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; (your core commands), the &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; (the Fixit framework), and the &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt; (the layered strategy), you have a complete system for tackling almost any network issue that comes your way. Now you’re equipped to stop guessing, start diagnosing problems methodically, and prove where the issue is—even if that means proving it&#39;s time to call for backup.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>More Than a Portfolio: The Story Your Personal Site Tells About You</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/More_Than_a_Portfolio/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/More_Than_a_Portfolio/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;For a long time, I had put off creating a personal website. I already had a resume and a LinkedIn profile—the professional basics. Building a whole site felt like a ton of work for something few people might ever see. Was the effort really worth it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve come to realize the answer is a definite &#39;yes,&#39; but not for the reasons I expected. The real value isn’t just in the finished product. The most powerful message your site sends has nothing to do with the portfolio pieces it hosts or the articles it contains. It’s about what the simple act of building it says about you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It Shows You&#39;re Willing to Figure Things Out&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you&#39;re a web developer, building a site means stepping into the unknown. I remember the specific, slightly delirious victory of figuring out what a &#39;serverless function&#39; was—a piece of technical jargon that sounds like it was invented just to make you quit. For a moment there, I felt like I could probably hack the mainframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That process is a perfect, small-scale prototype of professional problem-solving. It shows a curiosity and a willingness to learn—the exact traits that are valuable in any role where the tools are constantly changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perfection Isn&#39;t the Point&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the most freeing part: your personal site doesn’t have to be a technical masterpiece. My own site&#39;s design philosophy could best be described as &amp;quot;the buttons work,&amp;quot; and that&#39;s okay. It&#39;s not about proving you can code like a pro; it&#39;s about proving you won&#39;t let a skill gap stop you from getting something done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The belief that we need to be an expert before we start is the biggest thing that holds us back. It’s perfectionism disguised as prudence. Initiative isn&#39;t about having all the answers before you begin; it&#39;s about being resourceful enough to find them along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You Prove You Can Follow Through&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Launching a website is the exciting part. Maintaining it is where dedication comes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about it this way: when a customer walks into a messy, disorganized garage, they can lose their confidence. When they walk into a clean, well-lit shop, they feel like they&#39;re in good hands. Your website is your digital storefront, and it sends the same signal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding a new project, writing a short post, or just updating your bio shows consistency. It demonstrates that you don’t just start things; you see them through and take pride in your work over the long term. A hiring manager who sees a site with recent activity recognizes a person who can own a project beyond day one, just as a customer trusts a mechanic who keeps their shop in order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It Signals a Builder&#39;s Mindset&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, all these points lead to a fundamental difference between a perfectionist&#39;s mindset and a builder&#39;s mindset. A perfectionist waits for the perfect tools, the perfect idea, and the perfect time. A builder starts with what they have and makes something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your website is the perfect evidence of that builder&#39;s mindset in action. &lt;strong&gt;Think of it as a working prototype of you as a professional.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The value of a prototype isn’t in its flawless design or exhaustive features; its value lies in the fact that it &lt;em&gt;exists&lt;/em&gt;. It proves that an idea can be brought to life. It shows you can execute and that you understand the crucial concept that &amp;quot;done&amp;quot; is better than &amp;quot;perfect.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question is simple: who would we rather have on our team? The person who is still polishing a theoretical plan, or the person who has already built and shipped a working solution?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your website answers that question before you even say a word. In the end, it’s more than a link in your signature—it’s your story of how you get things done.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>WireShark to the Rescue: Unmasking Unlabeled Network Ports with CDP, LLDP, and More!</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/WireShark_to_the_Rescue_LLDP/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/WireShark_to_the_Rescue_LLDP/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Lost in the Labyrinth of Unlabeled Ports and Ethernet Cables? Wireshark to the Rescue!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone! Ever found yourself staring at a rack full of network switches, all blinking enticingly, but with not a single label in sight? You&#39;re not alone. We&#39;ve all been there – needing to track down a specific port, dreading the inevitable &#39;walk of shame&#39; back to the rack room, eyes glazing over at a sea of identical blinking lights, trying to track down a rogue cable. Imagine if you could just ask the network where you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good news! You actually can. It involves your trusty laptop and the magic of Wireshark. Today, we&#39;re going to dive into some network discovery protocols that can be your best friends when you&#39;re playing &#39;find the port&#39; in the data room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meet the Network Detectives: CDP, LLDP, EDP, and FDP&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I need to figure out what port I&#39;m plugged into, I turn to these four unsung heroes of network discovery. Each one acts like a little beacon, broadcasting information about the device it&#39;s connected to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CDP (Cisco Discovery Protocol):&lt;/strong&gt; If you&#39;re working with Cisco gear, CDP is your go-to. It&#39;s a proprietary protocol that Cisco devices use to share information about themselves directly with other Cisco devices connected to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LLDP (Link Layer Discovery Protocol):&lt;/strong&gt; This is the open standard version of CDP. It works across various vendors, making it incredibly useful in mixed-vendor environments. LLDP is like the universal translator of network discovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDP (Extreme Discovery Protocol):&lt;/strong&gt; As the name suggests, this protocol is designed for Extreme Networks equipment. Similar to CDP, it&#39;s Extreme&#39;s way of sharing information between its devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FDP (Foundry Discovery Protocol):&lt;/strong&gt; If you&#39;re dealing with Brocade (formerly Foundry Networks) switches, FDP is what you&#39;ll need to look for—another proprietary protocol, but just as helpful in its ecosystem. This is not a common one, but I&#39;ve run it enough that it&#39;s on my list.
My personal favorite, and the one I reach for most often, is &lt;strong&gt;LLDP&lt;/strong&gt;. Why LLDP, you ask? Because in today&#39;s networks, you&#39;re rarely dealing with just one vendor. LLDP gives me the best chance of getting the information I need, no matter whose hardware I&#39;m connected to. It&#39;s the most versatile tool in the box!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to Use These Filters in Wireshark&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so you&#39;ve got Wireshark open, you&#39;re capturing traffic, but how do you find these little network gems? It&#39;s super simple! Wireshark has a powerful display filter bar that lets you narrow down what you&#39;re seeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s how to apply each filter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For CDP: Type &lt;code&gt;cdp&lt;/code&gt; in the display filter bar and hit Enter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For LLDP: Type &lt;code&gt;lldp&lt;/code&gt; in the display filter bar and hit Enter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For EDP: Type &lt;code&gt;edp&lt;/code&gt; in the display filter bar and hit Enter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For FDP: Type &lt;code&gt;fdp&lt;/code&gt; in the display filter bar and hit Enter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For all: Type &lt;code&gt;cdp or lldp or edp or fdp&lt;/code&gt; in the display filter bar and hit Enter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you apply the filter, you&#39;ll start seeing packets specifically from that protocol. These protocols are designed to periodically broadcast information, so you might need to wait a few seconds for a packet to appear. In these packets, you&#39;ll often find information such as the remote device&#39;s hostname, its IP address, and, most importantly, the remote port it&#39;s connected to. This is gold when you&#39;re trying to figure out which port on that unlabeled switch you&#39;re connected to. This might take one minute or so to show, depending on the switch and message frequency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Example Output of an LLDP Packet:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s take a look at what an LLDP packet might reveal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Frame 1: 242 bytes on wire (1936 bits), 242 bytes captured (1936 bits) on interface en7, id 0

Ethernet II, Src: Ubiquiti&#92;_XX:XX:XX (68:d7:9a:XX:XX:XX), Dst: LLDP&#92;_Multicast (01:80:c2:00:00:0e)

Link Layer Discovery Protocol

Chassis Subtype = Locally assigned, Id: 68:d7:9a:XX:XX:XX

Port Subtype = MAC address, Id: 68:d7:9a:XX:XX:XX

Time To Live = 120 sec

System Name = Switch_room102_0012

System Description = Debian GNU/Linux 11 (bullseye) Linux 4.19.152-ui-alpine &#92;#4.19.152 SMP Fri Jun 7 23:26:35 CST 2024 aarch64

Capabilities

Management Address

Management Address

Port Description = eth21

IEEE 802.3 - Link Aggregation

IEEE 802.3 - MAC/PHY Configuration/Status

End of LLDPDU

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Saving Your Favorite Filters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tired of remembering &lt;code&gt;lldp&lt;/code&gt; every time? Wireshark lets you save your favorite filters so they&#39;re just a click away!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type your filter&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g., &lt;code&gt;lldp&lt;/code&gt;) into the display filter bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the &lt;strong&gt;plus sign (+)&lt;/strong&gt; next to the display filter bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small dialog box will pop up. Give your filter a descriptive &lt;strong&gt;label&lt;/strong&gt; (such as &amp;quot;LLDP Packets&amp;quot;) and, optionally, add a &lt;strong&gt;comment&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;OK&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, your saved filter will appear in the drop-down menu next to the display filter bar. No more typing, just quick access to your most used network sleuth tools!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the next time you&#39;re faced with a wall of unlabeled ports, don&#39;t despair! Fire up Wireshark, apply your favorite discovery protocol filter (I&#39;m looking at you, LLDP!), and let the network tell you exactly where you&#39;re plugged in. It&#39;s a huge time saver and a great way to avoid that awkward &amp;quot;guess and check&amp;quot; dance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Capture Smarter, Not Harder!&lt;/h4&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Building a Better Toolbox: A Simple IP Planner for Live Events</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Simple_IP_Planner/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Simple_IP_Planner/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has set up a network for a show knows the routine. You start with a list—maybe on a notepad, maybe in a spreadsheet—of all the gear that needs an IP address. The audio console, the lighting desk, the stage rack, the video switcher, the RF scanner, the system processor... the list goes on. It’s not just about avoiding conflicts; it&#39;s about creating a logical, easy-to-troubleshoot system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are plenty of powerful subnet calculators online, I&#39;ve always found they&#39;re either too complex for a quick on-site check or too generic. They&#39;ll give you the network range and broadcast address, but they won&#39;t help you map that ULX-D Rack to .101 and the DiGiCo SD12 to .50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That gap is what led to my latest little project: the &lt;strong&gt;AV IP Subnet Calculator&lt;/strong&gt;. It was a quick build, but it solves a specific problem: it’s a simple utility for live event technicians to plan out IP addresses for their gear quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;More Than a Calculator, It&#39;s a Planner&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal wasn&#39;t just to crunch the numbers on a CIDR range. The goal was to create a usable plan. The tool has two main parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Calculator:&lt;/strong&gt; You plug in a starting IP address and a subnet size (using a slider or a number input), and it immediately displays the key information: network address, broadcast address, usable host range, and the total number of available hosts. No fluff, just the facts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Device Planner:&lt;/strong&gt; This is where it becomes an &lt;em&gt;AV&lt;/em&gt; tool. Below the calculator, you can list out your equipment. Name a device (e.g., &amp;quot;Midas m32&amp;quot;), say how many IP addresses it needs, and click &amp;quot;Add.&amp;quot; The tool instantly assigns it the next available IP address from the range you defined.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can continue this for all your gear, and in seconds, you have a clean, ordered list of your entire show network. It&#39;s the digital version of that piece of paper you were going to use anyway, but it&#39;s faster and less prone to typos. When you&#39;re done, a &amp;quot;Copy List&amp;quot; button formats the whole plan so you can paste it into your show documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Tech Behind It: Keeping It Simple&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a tool like this, speed and simplicity are key. It needs to load instantly on a phone or a laptop with spotty backstage Wi-Fi. That&#39;s why I built it as a single, self-contained HTML file with no complex frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HTML:&lt;/strong&gt; The foundation is a straightforward HTML structure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tailwind CSS:&lt;/strong&gt; For styling, I pulled in Tailwind via its CDN. This allows you to build a clean, modern UI with utility classes directly in the HTML, which is ideal for small projects where you don&#39;t want a separate stylesheet or a build step.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vanilla JavaScript:&lt;/strong&gt; All the logic is handled by plain JavaScript, running right in the browser. No dependencies, no frameworks. This keeps the app incredibly lightweight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core of the calculator involves a bit of bitwise manipulation to handle the IP addresses. JavaScript doesn&#39;t have native IP address functions so that you can convert the familiar 192.168.1.100 format into a 32-bit integer. This makes all the subnet math much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a peek at the helper functions that do the conversion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
const ipToLong = (ip) =&amp;gt; { &#92;
  return ip.split(&#39;.&#39;).reduce((acc, octet) =&amp;gt; (acc &amp;amp;lt;&amp;lt; 8) + parseInt(octet, 10), 0) &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 0; &#92;
}; &#92;
 &#92;
const longToIp = (long) =&amp;gt; { &#92;
  return [(long &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 24), (long &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 16) &amp;amp; 255, (long &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 8) &amp;amp; 255, long &amp;amp; 255].join(&#39;.&#39;); &#92;
}; &#92;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the IPs are numbers, calculating the network and broadcast addresses is straightforward. The rest of the code listens for user input, runs the calculations, and updates the display in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A Tool That Works&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This wasn&#39;t a project that required weeks of development, and that&#39;s the point. It was about identifying a small, recurring friction point in a workflow and building a sharp, simple tool to solve it. It&#39;s a perfect example of how a little bit of code can go a long way in our industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can check out https://beaubremer.com/ip_subnet_calculator. I hope you find it as helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Oh No, Vim! Your Emergency Kit for Getting Unstuck</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Oh_No_Vim/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Oh_No_Vim/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h3&gt;You’ve been there. You&#39;re in your terminal, you proudly type &lt;code&gt;git commit&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hit Enter, and… what is this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The screen changes, and your cursor is blinking,
but typing text does nothing, and every key you press just beeps or moves
things around in weird ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations, you&#39;ve accidentally stumbled into Vim, the powerful but
notoriously tricky text editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t panic! You don&#39;t need to learn Vim today. You just need to know how
to get out. Here is your emergency kit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Emergency Kit: How to Exit Vim&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow these steps exactly. Vim has two main modes: &lt;strong&gt;Command mode&lt;/strong&gt; (where
you enter commands) and &lt;strong&gt;Insert mode&lt;/strong&gt; (where you type). You start in
Command mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Enter &amp;quot;Insert Mode&amp;quot; to Type&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What to do:&lt;/strong&gt; Press the &lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt; key once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it does:&lt;/strong&gt; This puts you into &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;nsert mode. You should see
&lt;code&gt;-- INSERT --&lt;/code&gt; at the bottom of the screen. Now you can type or edit your
commit message like you&#39;d expect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Make Your Edits&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What to do:&lt;/strong&gt; Type your commit message. If you don&#39;t need to change
anything, you can skip this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Exit &amp;quot;Insert Mode&amp;quot;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What to do:&lt;/strong&gt; Press the &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt; key.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it does:&lt;/strong&gt; This takes you back to &lt;strong&gt;Command mode&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;-- INSERT --&lt;/code&gt;
text at the bottom will disappear. This is where you can tell Vim what to
do next.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Save and Quit (The Most Common Exit)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What to do:&lt;/strong&gt; Type &lt;code&gt;:wq&lt;/code&gt; and press &lt;code&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it does:&lt;/strong&gt; This is two commands: &lt;code&gt;:w&lt;/code&gt; (write, i.e., save the
file) and &lt;code&gt;:q&lt;/code&gt; (quit). You&#39;ve successfully saved your commit message and
exited Vim.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Emergency Hatch: Quit Without Saving&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you made a mess and just want to start over?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What to do:&lt;/strong&gt; After pressing &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt; to get to Command mode, type &lt;code&gt;:q!&lt;/code&gt;
and press &lt;code&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it does:&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;code&gt;:q!&lt;/code&gt; command means &lt;strong&gt;q&lt;/strong&gt;uit without saving (the &lt;code&gt;!&lt;/code&gt;
forces the action). Git will abort the commit, and you can run
&lt;code&gt;git commit&lt;/code&gt; again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What Now? Your Two Paths Forward&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you&#39;ve survived, you have two choices for the next time this happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Path 1: Tame the Beast&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&#39;t have to become a Vim master, but knowing one more command can be
handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Command Mode (press &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;), type &lt;code&gt;u&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;u&lt;/strong&gt;ndo your last change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Path 2: Avoid the Beast Entirely&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d rather use an editor you already know, you can tell Git to use
something else. For example, to set VS Code as your default editor, run
this command in your terminal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;git config --global core.editor &amp;quot;code --wait&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope that helped out a bit!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>From Idea to AI: Building (and Securing) a Conversational Weather Bot</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Idea_to_AI/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Idea_to_AI/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every developer gets that itch—the need for a portfolio project that&#39;s more than just another to-do list. I wanted to build something that felt real, something that would force me to solve the kind of problems that don&#39;t come up in a simple tutorial. That&#39;s how I landed on the idea of a conversational weather bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan wasn&#39;t to execute a perfect blueprint. It was to start with a concept and embrace the real-world process of building, debugging, and learning along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Toolkit: Choosing the Right Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal was a modern, intelligent, and secure application. Instead of chasing the newest, flashiest tools, my plan was to pick a tech stack where every component solved a specific problem for &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; project. Here’s a look at the tools I decided on, and my thinking behind each one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frontend:&lt;/strong&gt; Plain HTML, JavaScript, and Tailwind CSS. I kept the frontend lightweight, flexible, and fast, avoiding framework overhead for what was a clean and simple UI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intelligence:&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;a href=&quot;https://ai.google.dev/&quot;&gt;Gemini API&lt;/a&gt; from Google. Its strength in natural language processing was perfect for turning a user&#39;s informal question into actionable data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Live Data:&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;a href=&quot;https://openweathermap.org/api&quot;&gt;OpenWeatherMap API&lt;/a&gt;. A reliable and straightforward source for real-time, structured weather data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Database:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://firebase.google.com/docs/firestore&quot;&gt;Google Firestore&lt;/a&gt;. I needed a simple way to save conversation history, and Firestore&#39;s real-time capabilities and easy setup were ideal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosting &amp;amp; Backend:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netlify.com/&quot;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt;. I opted for a &lt;strong&gt;serverless&lt;/strong&gt; approach for several key reasons:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost-Effective:&lt;/strong&gt; You only pay for what you use, avoiding the cost of an always-on server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automatic Scaling:&lt;/strong&gt; This approach provides automatic scaling. It’s about thinking ahead and building in a way that &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; handle a sudden spike in traffic without any manual work—a crucial feature for any real-world product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Security:&lt;/strong&gt; It provides a secure environment for secret API keys without server management overhead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Part 1: From Zero to a Working Prototype&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step was a rapid prototype to get a minimum viable product working. I built the chat interface using simple HTML and styled it with Tailwind CSS. The initial logic was straightforward and all lived in a single client-side JavaScript file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this was great for proving the concept, it had a critical security flaw that I knew I&#39;d need to address after getting the basic functionality running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Part 2: The Real-World Hurdles (and &#39;Aha!&#39; Moments)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting the prototype off my local machine and onto a live website is where the real problem-solving began.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Debugging Challenge #1: The Silence of a Deployed App&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app worked perfectly on my machine, but when I deployed it, it was stuck on &amp;quot;Connecting...&amp;quot; My first instinct was to hunt for a typo, but the browser console was completely clean. That’s the moment every developer dreads! It led me to my first educated guess: the problem wasn&#39;t in the code itself, but in the difference between my local setup and the live production environment. And I was right—I had forgotten to configure the production Firebase project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Debugging Challenge #2: The App Blocked Itself&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting the database connected felt like a win, but it immediately unlocked a new set of errors. At first, they were confusing—a &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;Content Security Policy&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot; block and an &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;auth/admin-restricted-operation&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot; error. After some digging, I realized what was happening: my app was now so secure, it was blocking &lt;em&gt;itself&lt;/em&gt; from talking to the database! The solution was to explicitly allow the connection in my Netlify settings and enable anonymous sign-in in Firebase so visitors could have a secure session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Part 3: The Pro-Level Step: Securing API Keys&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most critical issue remained: my API keys for Gemini and OpenWeatherMap were sitting in my public JavaScript file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To explain why this is a major security flaw, here&#39;s an analogy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leaving API keys in your client-side code is like leaving the key to your office under the front doormat. It’s convenient, but anyone who knows where to look can get in and cause serious damage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only acceptable solution was to refactor the architecture, introducing a &lt;strong&gt;serverless function&lt;/strong&gt; to act as a secure proxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Gemini API (Key Exposed!)] &amp;amp; [OpenWeatherMap API (Key Exposed!)] --&amp;gt;
[Netlify Function] ---&amp;gt; [Gemini API (Key Secure)] &amp;amp; [OpenWeatherMap API (Key Secure)] --&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created a Netlify Function that is the only part of the system that can access the secret keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;
// netlify/functions/weather.js

// Using node-fetch for making API calls in the Node.js environment
const fetch = require(&#39;node-fetch&#39;);

exports.handler = async function (event) {
  // Best practice: Ensure the function only responds to POST requests.
  if (event.httpMethod !== &#39;POST&#39;) {
    return { statusCode: 405, body: &#39;Method Not Allowed&#39; };
  }

  try {
    const { userQuery } = JSON.parse(event.body);

    // API keys are pulled from Netlify&#39;s secure environment variables.
    // They are never exposed to the user&#39;s browser.
    const { WEATHER_API_KEY, GEMINI_API_KEY } = process.env;

    // ... (Secure logic to call Gemini and OpenWeatherMap APIs) ...

    const botResponse = await getConversationalReply(userQuery);

    return {
      statusCode: 200,
      body: JSON.stringify({ reply: botResponse }),
    };

  } catch (error) {
    // It&#39;s good practice to log errors for easier debugging.
    console.error(&amp;quot;Netlify Function Error:&amp;quot;, error);
    return { statusCode: 500, body: JSON.stringify({ error: &#39;An internal server error occurred.&#39; }) };
  }
};
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This serverless architecture completely mitigates the risk of exposing API keys while maintaining the exact same user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Final Result and Key Takeaways&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, this project was a reminder that you don&#39;t need to have all the answers before you start. The most valuable skills I used weren&#39;t from a perfect plan, but from the process of hitting a wall, making an educated guess, and figuring out the next right step. That&#39;s the real work of building things, and I hope this story encourages you to start your own project, even if you don&#39;t know exactly how it&#39;ll finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to dive into the code yourself, you can find the complete project on my GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Good, The Bad, and The Markdown</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Good_The_Bad_and_Markdown/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Good_The_Bad_and_Markdown/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve ever written a &lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt; file on GitHub, commented on Reddit,
or used a static site generator (like Eleventy, which powers this blog),
you&#39;ve used Markdown. It&#39;s the simple, plain-text syntax that has quietly
become the standard for writing on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But like any tool, it has its strengths and weaknesses. In this post, we&#39;ll
take a practical look at the pros and cons of using Markdown, some common
mistakes to watch out for, and a few tips to help you write it effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Pros: Why Markdown is Great&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown&#39;s popularity isn&#39;t an accident. It offers several key advantages,
especially for technical writers and bloggers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&#39;s Simple and Readable&lt;/strong&gt;: The core design goal of Markdown is to be as
readable as possible, even in its raw, plain-text form. You don&#39;t need
to be a developer to understand what &lt;code&gt;**bold**&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;*italic*&lt;/code&gt; means.
This low learning curve means you can focus on the content, not the
formatting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&#39;s Platform-Independent&lt;/strong&gt;: A Markdown file is just a plain text file.
You can open and edit it on any device or operating system with any text
editor. This prevents your content from being locked into a proprietary
format, like a &lt;code&gt;.docx&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&#39;s Version Control-Friendly&lt;/strong&gt;: Because it&#39;s just text, Markdown works
beautifully with version control systems like Git. You can track changes,
compare versions, and collaborate with others on documents just like you
would with source code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&#39;s Fast&lt;/strong&gt;: With no buttons to click or menus to navigate, your hands
never have to leave the keyboard. This creates a faster, more streamlined
writing workflow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Cons: Where Markdown Falls Short&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite its benefits, Markdown isn&#39;t perfect, and it&#39;s important to
understand its limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lack of Standardization&lt;/strong&gt;: This is Markdown&#39;s biggest drawback. There is
no single, official standard, which has led to dozens of &amp;quot;flavors&amp;quot; like
GitHub-Flavored Markdown (GFM), CommonMark, and others. A feature that
works in one place might not work in another, causing frustration
inconsistencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limited Features&lt;/strong&gt;: Markdown was designed for simplicity, which means it
lacks features for creating complex layouts. Things like tables,
footnotes, and diagrams are not part of the original spec and are
handled differently (or not at all) across flavors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Built-in Styling&lt;/strong&gt;: By design, Markdown separates content from
presentation. This is a good thing, but it means you can&#39;t control the
fine details of your document&#39;s appearance (like fonts, colors, or page
layout) from the Markdown file itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Common Mistakes to Avoid&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most &amp;quot;errors&amp;quot; in Markdown come from minor syntax slip-ups. Here are a few
to watch for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forgetting Blank Lines&lt;/strong&gt;: Markdown uses blank lines to separate distinct
blocks of content, like paragraphs, lists, or code blocks. Forgetting
to add an empty line between them is one of the most common mistakes
and can cause things to render incorrectly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Broken Links and Images&lt;/strong&gt;: The syntax &lt;code&gt;[text](url)&lt;/code&gt; is simple, but it&#39;s
easy to mix up the brackets and parentheses or use a broken URL. Always
double-check your links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unformatted Code Blocks&lt;/strong&gt;: To get proper syntax highlighting, you need to
add a language identifier after the opening backticks (e.g.,
&lt;code&gt;```javascript&lt;/code&gt;). Forgetting this will usually result in plain,
uncolored text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inconsistent List Indentation&lt;/strong&gt;: When creating nested lists, you must
indent correctly (usually by four spaces). Inconsistent indentation can
break the list&#39;s structure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tips for Better Markdown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use a Linter&lt;/strong&gt;: Tools like &lt;code&gt;markdownlint&lt;/code&gt; can automatically check your
files for common errors and enforce a consistent style. This is a
lifesaver, especially when collaborating with others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn Your &amp;quot;Flavor&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;: Since you&#39;re likely writing for a specific
platform (like a blog, GitHub, or a particular app), take a few minutes
to learn the specifics of its Markdown flavor. This will help you take
full advantage of its features and avoid surprises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep Tables Simple&lt;/strong&gt;: While many Markdown flavors support tables, they
can be challenging to write and maintain in plain text. For complex data,
consider whether a simple list or even an image of a table might be a
better option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use HTML When Necessary&lt;/strong&gt;: Remember, Markdown is a superset of HTML. For
those rare cases where you absolutely need a feature that Markdown doesn&#39;t
offer, you can almost always fall back on raw HTML.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown is a powerful tool that strikes a great balance between simplicity
and functionality. By understanding its pros, cons, and common quirks, you
can make it a seamless part of your writing workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Definitive Guide to a Stable Sonos and Eero Network</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Eero_Sonos_config/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Eero_Sonos_config/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve invested in a Sonos sound system and an Eero mesh Wi-Fi network, you were probably expecting a seamless, high-end experience. Instead, you might be pulling your hair out dealing with intermittent audio dropouts, speakers that randomly disappear from the app, or music that refuses to play in grouped rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re not alone, and the good news is your gear isn&#39;t faulty. While Sonos and Eero are officially compatible, they don&#39;t always play nicely without some specific configuration. The problem isn&#39;t a fundamental flaw, but a conflict between two sophisticated mesh systems that can be solved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide will walk you through the solutions, from foundational fixes that address 90% of issues to advanced tweaks for complex setups. Let&#39;s get your system running reliably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start Here: The 4 Non-Negotiable Rules for Stability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you do anything else, you need to establish a solid foundation for your network. These four steps address the most common and disruptive sources of conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eliminate Double NAT (The #1 Culprit):&lt;/strong&gt; Most issues where the Sonos app can&#39;t find your system are caused by &amp;quot;Double NAT.&amp;quot; This happens when your ISP&#39;s modem/router and your Eero system are both trying to manage your network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fix:&lt;/strong&gt; Log into your ISP&#39;s modem/router and enable &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;Bridge Mode.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; This turns off its routing functions and lets your Eero act as the single, true router for your home. This creates a &amp;quot;flat&amp;quot; network where all your devices can see each other properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reserve IP Addresses:&lt;/strong&gt; Your router assigns temporary (&amp;quot;dynamic&amp;quot;) IP addresses to your devices. If these change, your Sonos app can lose track of a speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fix:&lt;/strong&gt; In the Eero app, go to each of your Sonos devices and set a &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;DHCP Reservation&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;Reserve IP.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; This makes its IP address permanent, eliminating a common cause of disappearing speakers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disable Eero Labs:&lt;/strong&gt; The experimental features in &amp;quot;Eero Labs&amp;quot; can be unstable and are known to cause conflicts with Sonos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fix:&lt;/strong&gt; In the Eero app, navigate to &lt;code&gt;Discover &amp;gt; Eero Labs&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;turn off everything&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obey the &amp;quot;Golden Rule&amp;quot; of Wiring:&lt;/strong&gt; If you connect more than one Sonos product to your network with an Ethernet cable, they &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; all connect back to the &lt;em&gt;same&lt;/em&gt; Eero node or the &lt;em&gt;same&lt;/em&gt; network switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning:&lt;/strong&gt; Never wire Sonos products into different satellite Eero nodes. This can create a &amp;quot;broadcast storm&amp;quot; that crashes your entire network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Great Debate: Eero Wi-Fi (WM:1) vs. SonosNet (WM:0)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After setting the foundation, you face a core choice: should your Sonos speakers connect directly to your Eero Wi-Fi, or should they use Sonos&#39;s own mesh network, SonosNet? You can see which mode your system is in by checking the &amp;quot;About My System&amp;quot; section of the Sonos app. &lt;code&gt;WM:1&lt;/code&gt; is Wi-Fi, &lt;code&gt;WM:0&lt;/code&gt; is SonosNet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case for Eero Wi-Fi (WM:1 - The Modern Approach)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the default, all-wireless setup, where every Sonos speaker connects to your Eero network, just like a laptop or phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why use it?&lt;/strong&gt; Modern Eero systems (especially Wi-Fi 6/6E) are incredibly fast and efficient, potentially offering better performance than the older SonosNet protocol. This is also the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; way to connect modern speakers like the Roam, Move, and the Era series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best for:&lt;/strong&gt; Users with new Eero and Sonos hardware in homes with low Wi-Fi congestion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case for SonosNet (WM:0 - The Classic Fix)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This setup is created by connecting &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; Sonos product to your gateway Eero with an Ethernet cable. This device then creates a separate, private 2.4GHz wireless network exclusively for your other Sonos speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why use it?&lt;/strong&gt; SonosNet isolates your sensitive audio traffic from all the other Wi-Fi noise in your house. It&#39;s the most proven and effective fix for dropouts and issues with grouped speakers, especially in busy network environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best for:&lt;/strong&gt; Users with older hardware, high Wi-Fi interference, or anyone experiencing stubborn dropouts and stereo pair failures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;SonosNet (Wired Setup - WM:0)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Eero Wi-Fi (Wireless Setup - WM:1)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How it Works&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;One Sonos product is wired to the network, creating a dedicated, private mesh for other Sonos speakers.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;All Sonos speakers connect to the Eero mesh network as individual clients.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primary Advantage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Isolates audio traffic from general network congestion, dramatically improving stability in most cases.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Leverages the superior speed and features of the modern Eero mesh.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primary Disadvantage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Slower, legacy protocol. It can cause network loops if wired incorrectly.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Performance is susceptible to general Wi-Fi interference and router settings.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Consideration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Incompatible with Sonos Move, Roam, and Era speakers, forcing a &amp;quot;mixed mode.&amp;quot;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left&quot;&gt;Requires a robust and healthy Eero network to work reliably.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation:&lt;/strong&gt; Start with the modern Eero Wi-Fi (WM:1) setup. If you experience any instability, switching to SonosNet (WM:0) is the most reliable next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Quick Troubleshooting Guide&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve followed the rules above and still have issues, here’s how to tackle specific symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptom: Intermittent Audio Dropouts or Disappearing Speakers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cause:&lt;/strong&gt; Usually Wi-Fi interference, IP conflicts, or incorrect wiring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Solution:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Double-check the &amp;quot;Golden Rule&amp;quot; of wiring.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure you&#39;ve reserved IP addresses for all Sonos devices.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Switch your setup.&lt;/strong&gt; If you&#39;re on Wi-Fi (WM:1), switch to SonosNet (WM:0) by wiring one speaker to your main Eero. If you&#39;re already on an unstable SonosNet, try going fully wireless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a test,&lt;/strong&gt; temporarily disable &amp;quot;Client Steering&amp;quot; in your Eero&#39;s advanced settings. This can sometimes help older 2.4GHz-only Sonos devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptom: Sonos App Cannot Find the System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cause:&lt;/strong&gt; Almost always Double NAT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Solution:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Put your ISP modem/router in Bridge Mode.&lt;/strong&gt; This is the definitive fix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure your phone is on your main Eero Wi-Fi, not a guest network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On iOS, check that the Sonos app has &amp;quot;Local Network&amp;quot; permission and that &amp;quot;Private Wi-Fi Address&amp;quot; is disabled for your Eero network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptom: Grouped Rooms or Stereo Pairs Fail&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cause:&lt;/strong&gt; Speakers in a group need to communicate directly with each other. On a mesh network, Eero might place them on different Wi-Fi bands or nodes, breaking this link.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Solution:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Switch to SonosNet (WM:0).&lt;/strong&gt; This is the most reliable fix for this specific problem. It consolidates all your speakers onto a single, dedicated network layer, ensuring they can communicate seamlessly for perfect synchronization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting Eero and Sonos to work in perfect harmony is less about luck and more about deliberate, informed configuration. By establishing a clean network foundation and making a conscious choice between a pure Wi-Fi or SonosNet setup, you can build a system that&#39;s powerful, stable, and delivers the premium experience you paid for.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The  Unknown  Art Of  Freestyle  Mic  Checking</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/the_Unknown_Art%20of_Freestyle_Mic_Checking/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/the_Unknown_Art%20of_Freestyle_Mic_Checking/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h3&gt;The Unknown Art of Freestyle Mic Checking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ve heard it a million times at events: &amp;quot;Check, one, two... check, one, two...&amp;quot; It&#39;s the universal signal that sound is being tested, a little sonic ritual before the show kicks off. For those of us behind the mixer, that simple phrase is often just the opening act for an elaborate, unscripted performance known as the &amp;quot;freestyle mic check.&amp;quot; And let me tell you, it&#39;s an unknown art form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Beyond &amp;quot;One, Two&amp;quot;: The Creative Pressure Cooker&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, we could say &amp;quot;check, check&amp;quot; repeatedly. But where&#39;s the fun in that? And more importantly, how do you really &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; a microphone sounds good until someone says something a little more, well, human? This is where the magic (and sometimes mild panic) happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine this: The venue is quiet. The client is milling about. Maybe the band is watching. The pressure is on to make sure that the mic sounds perfect. And you, the intrepid sound engineer, have to conjure something – anything – to say into it. It’s not just about level and clarity; it&#39;s about making sure it sounds good when someone is actually &lt;em&gt;talking&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, you start. &amp;quot;Testing, testing, one, two, three, testing.&amp;quot; Okay, standard. However, you then need to stretch it out. You need to hit different vocal ranges, project a little, maybe even whisper. This is where the improv kicks in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Unwritten Rules of Mic Check Improv&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no official classes for this, no textbooks on &amp;quot;Advanced Mic Check Banter.&amp;quot; It’s learned on the job, a quiet rite of passage. Here&#39;s a peek into the unwritten rules and common tactics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Weather Report:&lt;/strong&gt; A classic for a reason. &amp;quot;Looks like it&#39;s going to be a beautiful day here in Chicago, folks. A little humidity, but nothing we can&#39;t handle.&amp;quot; Reliable, relatable, and gets enough varied sounds out of your voice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Counting Past Ten (Creatively):&lt;/strong&gt; Beyond the basics, you might hear things like, &amp;quot;One thousand one, one thousand two... are we sure this thing is on?&amp;quot; Or counting in another language if you&#39;re feeling fancy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reciting Nonsense:&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes, sheer desperation leads to poetry. Or, you know, just listing off groceries. &amp;quot;Milk, bread, eggs, slightly bruised bananas for the crew...&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fake Announcements:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;quot;Ladies and gentlemen, please remember to silence your cell phones, unless, of course, you&#39;re expecting an incredibly important call about a winning lottery ticket.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Existential Question:&lt;/strong&gt; For the more philosophical engineer. &amp;quot;What &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; sound, really? Is it just vibrations? Or is it a feeling... a connection?&amp;quot; (Best delivered with a straight face.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-Commentary:&lt;/strong&gt; This is where the tongue-in-cheek really shines. &amp;quot;Man, I really need some coffee. Is this thing making my voice sound deeper, or is that just me?&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key is to keep it going without drawing too much attention. You&#39;re trying to make the mic sound good, not launch a stand-up comedy career. It’s a delicate balance of projecting confidence while subtly making up words on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Payoff: Seamless Sound&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this impromptu chattering, this vocal gymnastics, serves a crucial purpose: it helps us fine-tune the audio system. We listen for feedback, adjust equalization for different voices, and ensure that when the actual presenter steps up, their message comes through crystal clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the next time you hear that &amp;quot;check, one, two,&amp;quot; remember the unsung heroes of the sound world. We’re not just plugging things in; we&#39;re also quietly, creatively, and sometimes awkwardly, ensuring every word sounds perfect. It&#39;s truly an unknown art.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Stop Worrying and Start Branching: A Guide to Safer Development with Git</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Stop_worrying_and_Start_Branching/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Stop_worrying_and_Start_Branching/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re deep in concentration, adding a new feature to your website, when you suddenly realize... you&#39;ve broken everything. The page won&#39;t load, styles are a mess, and that familiar panic sets in. I&#39;ve definitely been there. For too long, I did all my work directly on the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch—the one my live site was built from. Every change was a high-stakes gamble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I embraced a professional workflow that brought a new level of safety and confidence to my work: &lt;strong&gt;Git branching&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of your &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch as the &amp;quot;golden copy&amp;quot; of your project. It&#39;s the version that is live, working, and stable. A branch is a parallel copy of your project where you can experiment freely. If your new idea works, you merge it into the golden copy. If it&#39;s a disaster, you delete the branch, and &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; remains untouched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.beaubremer.com/images/blog/git-branching-diagram.svg&quot; alt=&quot;A diagram showing feature branches splitting off from the main Git branch and merging back in.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It brings peace of mind to the development process. Here’s why you should be using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why Bother with Branches?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might seem like a few extra steps, but the benefits are enormous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protect Your Live Site:&lt;/strong&gt; Your &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch is always protected. You can be confident that it&#39;s in a deployable, working state at all times. No more &amp;quot;I just broke the live site!&amp;quot; panic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experiment Freely:&lt;/strong&gt; Want to try a new layout or a wild idea? Create a branch! You can make a mess, try things out, and break whatever you want without any risk to your core project. If it doesn&#39;t work out, there&#39;s no harm done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay Organized:&lt;/strong&gt; Create a separate branch for each new feature or bug fix. This keeps your work isolated and easy to track. For example, &lt;code&gt;feature/new-contact-form&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;fix/mobile-menu-bug&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easier Collaboration and Code Reviews:&lt;/strong&gt; If you work on a team, branches are essential. Even for solo developers, they allow you to use Pull Requests on GitHub to review your work before merging. It&#39;s a great way to catch your own mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My 5-Step Branching Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make this concrete, let me walk you through a real-world example. I recently wanted to change the main header link on my blog. On the homepage, it should point to my main portfolio, but on individual posts, it should point back to the blog&#39;s index. This was a perfect use case for a feature branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the exact workflow I followed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start from a Clean Slate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before starting anything new, I always make sure my local project is in sync with the latest version on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# First, switch to your main branch
git checkout main

# Then, pull the latest changes from GitHub (your remote &#39;origin&#39;)
git pull origin main
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create Your New Branch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I created a new branch and immediately switched to it. I gave it a descriptive name so I&#39;d know its purpose. The &lt;code&gt;-b&lt;/code&gt; flag handles both creating the branch and checking it out in one step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# The -b flag creates a new branch and switches to it
git checkout -b feature/contextual-header-link
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do the Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this new, safe branch, I edited my layout file (&lt;code&gt;_includes/layouts/base.njk&lt;/code&gt;) to add the logic for the contextual link. I made a few small, focused commits along the way to save my progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# Stage all modified files for the commit
git add .

# Commit your changes with a clear, descriptive message
git commit -m &amp;quot;feat: Make header link contextual&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open a Pull Request&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I was happy with how it worked on my local machine, I pushed the new branch up to my GitHub repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# Push the new branch to your remote repo named &#39;origin&#39;
# The -u flag sets the upstream branch for future pushes
git push -u origin feature/contextual-header-link
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I went to my project on the GitHub website and opened a Pull Request (PR). A PR is a formal way of proposing your changes. It’s a request to pull your new code from the &lt;code&gt;feature/contextual-header-link&lt;/code&gt; branch into the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merge and Clean Up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pull Request page on GitHub showed me a summary of all my changes, which I could review one last time. Everything looked good, so I clicked the &amp;quot;Merge pull request&amp;quot; button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This safely merged my work into &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; and, in my case, automatically triggered a new deployment to Netlify. After merging, I deleted the feature branch to keep my repository tidy and signal that the work on that specific feature was complete. The work is now safely part of the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole process might seem like extra work at first, but it&#39;ll quickly become a natural part of your routine. It provides a structure for safer, more organized development. Give it a try on your very next task, no matter how small!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>More Than Just Plugging In</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/More_Than_Just_Plugging_In/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/More_Than_Just_Plugging_In/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h3&gt;More Than Just Plugging In: What a Live Production Team Really Does Before the Doors Open&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you attend a fantastic gala or a smooth corporate event, everything just seems to flow. The lighting perfectly sets the mood, the sound is crystal clear whether it&#39;s a keynote speaker or a band, and the visuals on screen are sharp and engaging. It all looks effortless, almost like magic. But here&#39;s a little secret: that &amp;quot;magic&amp;quot; isn&#39;t accidental. It&#39;s the meticulous result of a dedicated live production team working tirelessly behind the scenes, long before the first guest even steps through the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people only see the polished final product, unaware of the weeks, sometimes months, of intricate planning and the intense hours of setup and programming behind it. Ever wonder how that seamless experience truly comes to life? Let&#39;s pull back the curtain and show you what really goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Blueprint: Pre-Production Planning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before a single piece of equipment is even loaded onto a truck, the groundwork is laid. This is the strategic phase where visions turn into detailed plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial Consultations &amp;amp; Needs Assessment:&lt;/strong&gt; Our first step is always to understand the client&#39;s vision thoroughly. What&#39;s the core message of the event? What&#39;s the desired mood? Who is the audience? What are the key goals, and, of course, what&#39;s the budget we&#39;re working with?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Site Visits &amp;amp; Venue Scouting:&lt;/strong&gt; We physically visit the venue to assess everything from power availability and rigging points for lights and speakers, to room acoustics, sightlines for screens, and even the logistics of getting gear in and out via loading docks. This helps us identify and plan around any potential challenges, like low ceilings or strict venue rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Design &amp;amp; System Architecture:&lt;/strong&gt; This is where the engineers get to work. We create detailed blueprints – including CAD drawings that show equipment placement and signal flow diagrams that map out every cable connection for audio, video, and lighting. We specify the exact equipment needed, from the type of microphones and projectors to the specific lighting fixtures and camera packages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content Development &amp;amp; Integration:&lt;/strong&gt; We often work closely with clients to ensure all their video playback, presentation slides, and custom graphics are ready. This means making sure everything from speaker slides to custom intro videos is in the correct format, resolution, and aspect ratio for the chosen display systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Permitting &amp;amp; Logistics:&lt;/strong&gt; There&#39;s a lot of paperwork involved, too! We manage venue regulations, ensure compliance with fire marshal requirements, and navigate union rules if applicable. We also coordinate precise loading and unloading schedules to minimize disruptions and ensure seamless operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Build: Load-in &amp;amp; Setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the planning is locked, it&#39;s time for the physical transformation of the space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Early Birds: Rigging &amp;amp; Power:&lt;/strong&gt; Often, the rigging team is the first on site, safely hanging speaker arrays and lighting trusses from the ceiling. Simultaneously, the power team is running heavy-duty cables to establish the main power distribution for all the equipment. Safety is paramount here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equipment Unload &amp;amp; Prep:&lt;/strong&gt; Hundreds, often thousands, of pounds of gear arrive in meticulously packed cases. Each piece is carefully unloaded, unpacked, inventoried, and double-checked to ensure it&#39;s in perfect working order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System Deployment &amp;amp; Cabling:&lt;/strong&gt; This is where the space begins to take shape, coming together like a puzzle. Miles of cables for audio, video, data, and power are meticulously run – always neatly, safely, and out of sight, transforming an empty space into a functional event environment. Speakers are hoisted, screens are built, projectors are mounted, cameras are positioned, and the complex control consoles are set up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stage &amp;amp; Set Construction:&lt;/strong&gt; While the tech goes in, the physical environment of the show also takes shape. Staging is built, backdrops are put into place, and scenic elements that define the event&#39;s look are assembled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Polish: Programming &amp;amp; Testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where the artistry and the technical precision truly merge, often for hours on end, refining every detail before the doors open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lighting Programming:&lt;/strong&gt; Lighting designers spend hours, sometimes days, programming cues for every moment of the event. They craft looks for guest arrival, dramatic entrances, awards presentations, musical performances, and speeches, using light to set the mood, highlight key individuals, and create immersive environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audio Tuning &amp;amp; Sound Checks: The Unseen Foundation of Clarity&lt;/strong&gt; This is far more than just turning on a microphone and hoping for the best. It&#39;s about meticulously shaping the sound to suit the room&#39;s unique acoustics and the specific needs of the event.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker Optimization:&lt;/strong&gt; Our audio engineers use specialized software and measurement microphones to analyze how the speakers interact with the room. This helps eliminate harsh frequencies and prevents echoes, ensuring even sound distribution so every guest hears clearly, regardless of their seating position. It’s about making sure the sound system itself is performing optimally in that space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microphone Management:&lt;/strong&gt; Each microphone – whether for a CEO, a panelist, or a singer – undergoes individual testing. We set appropriate gain levels, check for potential feedback (that dreaded squeal!), and apply equalization (EQ) to ensure voices are warm, clear, and cut through any background noise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System Integrity:&lt;/strong&gt; This critical phase also catches any loose cables, faulty equipment, or unexpected hums and buzzes that could completely derail a presentation or a musical act. It&#39;s about creating a robust and pristine sonic environment where every sound element can shine without distraction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video Playback &amp;amp; Switching Tests:&lt;/strong&gt; We thoroughly test all video sources, including pre-recorded content, live camera feeds, and speaker presentations. Every transition is practiced, ensuring seamless switching between different inputs during the show.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Show File Creation &amp;amp; Backup:&lt;/strong&gt; All the painstaking programming for lighting, audio, and video is saved as &amp;quot;show files.&amp;quot; Crucially, multiple redundant backups are created to protect against any unforeseen technical glitches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rehearsals with Talent/Presenters: The Critical Dry Run&lt;/strong&gt;
This is perhaps the most underestimated phase, and yet, it&#39;s absolutely crucial for a smooth show. Many outside of production might see it as an unnecessary added step, but it&#39;s where theoretical planning meets real-world execution.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cue-to-Cue (C2C):&lt;/strong&gt; This is where the entire technical team practices every single lighting change, video playback, sound cue, and camera shot in precise sequence. It&#39;s about perfecting the timing and flow of the show, ensuring everyone on the team is perfectly synchronized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working with Presenters:&lt;/strong&gt; For speakers, performers, and hosts, rehearsals are vital. They get comfortable with the stage layout, the lectern, the microphone technique, and how to advance their slides. This practice helps them feel confident and allows the production team to anticipate their needs – like when they might move to a different part of the stage or need a specific video cued up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Troubleshooting Live:&lt;/strong&gt; Crucially, rehearsals are the ideal time to identify and address potential issues before the audience arrives. A speaker might realize their remote isn&#39;t working from where they stand, or a video might not play correctly – all these potential pitfalls can be identified and fixed in a rehearsal, preventing awkward pauses, technical glitches, or embarrassing moments during the actual event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building Confidence:&lt;/strong&gt; For both the production team and the talent on stage, rehearsals build immense confidence. Everyone knows their role, the timing is locked in, and the performance can be delivered flawlessly, allowing the presenters to focus on their message and the audience to enjoy the experience without interruption.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ready for Showtime!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the goal of a live production team is simple yet profound: to seamlessly transform a client&#39;s vision into an unforgettable reality for every single attendee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the next time you&#39;re at an event and find yourself marveling at how perfectly everything runs, take a moment to remember the dedicated team behind the scenes. They’re the ones who made that &amp;quot;magic&amp;quot; happen, meticulously planning and executing long before you ever took your seat. It truly is &amp;quot;more than just plugging in.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keep Calm and Troubleshoot On</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Keep_Calm_and_Troubleshoot%20On/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Keep_Calm_and_Troubleshoot%20On/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s 3:17 A.M., and the third phone call in a row just shattered your peaceful sleep. A critical system is down, and you can already feel the panic starting to bubble up. In these moments, it’s easy to think that the solution lies in typing faster or knowing more obscure commands. But what if the most powerful tool you have is simply a calm, focused mind?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that staying cool under pressure isn&#39;t just a personality trait; it&#39;s a skill you can learn. Let&#39;s break down how to handle the heat without getting burned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Why Your Brain Shuts Down When the Server Does&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever notice how it’s suddenly impossible to remember a simple command when your boss is standing over your shoulder? That&#39;s not a personal failure; it&#39;s a biological phenomenon. When you get stressed, your body goes into &amp;quot;fight or flight&amp;quot; mode, flooding your system with hormones like cortisol and adrenaline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This response is fantastic if you need to outrun a saber-toothed tiger, but it&#39;s terrible for debugging a complex system. These stress hormones actively sabotage the parts of your brain responsible for problem-solving, memory, and decision-making. In other words, the pressure that&#39;s meant to speed you up actually makes you less effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Your Mental Emergency Brake: The STOP Skill&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how do you fight back against your biology? You can start with a simple but powerful tool called the DBT STOP skill. The next time you feel overwhelmed, just run through these four steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;S - Stop&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously, just stop. Don&#39;t type another command. Don’t say another word. Just freeze for a second to break the cycle of panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;T - Take a Breath&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take one deliberate, deep breath. This is a direct physiological intervention that tells your nervous system it’s time to chill out by activating the parasympathetic nervous system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;O - Observe&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a quick, non-judgmental look at what’s going on. What are you thinking? What are you feeling? What&#39;s the reality of the situation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;P - Proceed Mindfully&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you&#39;ve interrupted the panic, you can choose your next move intentionally instead of just reacting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Don&#39;t Just Do Something, Stand There!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a crisis, the pressure to &amp;quot;do something&amp;quot; is immense, and every minute of downtime feels like an hour. It’s tempting to take a shortcut that looks like it will save time, but that shortcut is a real risk. A single, panicked action—like randomly restarting a service or tweaking a config file without a clear reason—can create a new problem on top of the old one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where you have to remember the paradox of troubleshooting: &lt;strong&gt;the fastest path to a solution is often the most deliberate one.&lt;/strong&gt; Sticking to your plan might feel slower in the moment, but it prevents the kind of hasty mistakes that can make the total fix time much, much longer. You risk digging the hole deeper and spending the next hour just trying to get back to where you started. Taking a moment to breathe and observe isn&#39;t wasting time; it&#39;s what ensures you&#39;re moving toward a resolution, not just creating more chaos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Find the Root Cause with the &amp;quot;5 Whys&amp;quot; Method&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panic loves chaos, but a structured process brings order. One of the simplest and most effective methods for getting to the heart of an issue is the &amp;quot;5 Whys&amp;quot; technique. It’s exactly what it sounds like: you just keep asking &amp;quot;Why?&amp;quot; until you move past the symptoms and find the real source of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a website is down:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is it down?&lt;/strong&gt; Because the web servers are unhealthy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why are they unhealthy?&lt;/strong&gt; Because the web server process crashed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did it crash?&lt;/strong&gt; Because the server ran out of memory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did it run out of memory?&lt;/strong&gt; Because a log file grew until it filled up all the disk space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did the log file get so big?&lt;/strong&gt; Because a recent code change accidentally left verbose debugging on in the live environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without this process, you might have just restarted the server at step #2, only for it to crash again. The &amp;quot;5 Whys&amp;quot; guides you straight to the root cause, which was actually a procedural failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Managing the Humans&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technical problems always involve people, and people have anxieties. A considerable part of your job during a crisis is managing their stress so you can focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key is proactive communication. Send out regular updates, even if the update is just, &amp;quot;We&#39;re still investigating.&amp;quot; This fills the information vacuum and shows you&#39;re in control. When someone demands a time for the fix, it’s better to explain your process than to give a deadline you can&#39;t guarantee. Try something like, &amp;quot;Right now, our focus is on analyzing the logs to find the source. I&#39;ll have another update in 15 minutes.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mastering these skills—managing your panic, sticking to a method, and communicating clearly—is what separates the pros from the rest. It helps you not only survive the fire but also emerge as a more resilient and respected professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you can&#39;t figure it out after all that? Well, how many programmers does it take to change a light bulb? &lt;em&gt;None&lt;/em&gt;, that&#39;s a hardware problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dive into QLab</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/dive_Qlab/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/dive_Qlab/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Dive into QLab: Your New Best Friend for Show Control!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone! Ever wondered how those amazing live shows, plays, or even presentations manage to switch between music, video, and lights flawlessly? Often, the seamless magic behind the scenes is all thanks to a fantastic piece of software called QLab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QLab is a powerful tool for show control, used by professionals and hobbyists alike to create incredibly precise and complex cue lists. But don&#39;t let &amp;quot;powerful&amp;quot; scare you off – especially since you can download a feature-rich free version! It&#39;s also incredibly intuitive once you get the hang of it, and it can elevate your projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we&#39;re going to take a super quick look at QLab and then dive into one of its most common uses: adding music cues. Get ready to make your audio playback smooth as silk!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Getting Started with QLab&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First things first, if you don&#39;t have QLab, you can download it for free from the Figure 53 website. The free version, called QLab Free, offers a wide range of features, particularly for audio playback, making it ideal for getting started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you open QLab, you&#39;ll see a clean workspace. This is where you&#39;ll build your &amp;quot;cue list,&amp;quot; which is essentially a chronological list of everything you want to happen during your show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Quick Tutorial: Adding Music Cues in QLab&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s get straight to it and add some music!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Open Your Workspace&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you open QLab, you&#39;ll usually be presented with a new, blank workspace. This is your canvas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Drag and Drop Your Audio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to get music into QLab is to drag an audio file (like an MP3, WAV, or AIFF) directly from your computer&#39;s folders into the QLab window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip:&lt;/strong&gt; Use uncompressed audio files with Qlab (like WAV or AIFF) for the best quality and performance, but MP3s work just fine for many applications, especially for getting started.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Meet Your First Cue&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you drag in an audio file, QLab automatically creates an &amp;quot;Audio Cue&amp;quot; for it. You&#39;ll see it appear in your cue list. Each cue has a &amp;quot;Q Number&amp;quot; (its position in the list) and a &amp;quot;Q Name&amp;quot; (usually the file name by default).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. The Inspector – Your Control Panel&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below your cue list, you&#39;ll see the &amp;quot;Inspector&amp;quot; panel. This is your control hub, where all the magic happens! When you select a cue, the Inspector dynamically updates to show you all the properties and settings for that specific cue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For an audio cue, you&#39;ll see tabs like &amp;quot;Levels&amp;quot; (for volume), &amp;quot;Time &amp;amp; Loops&amp;quot; (for start/end times and looping), and &amp;quot;Audio&amp;quot; (for routing to different outputs).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Setting Playback&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; Go to the &amp;quot;Levels&amp;quot; tab in the Inspector. You can adjust the overall volume of your music cue here using the fader. (And yes, you can create smooth fades in and out later, but for now, just set a static level!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start and End Times:&lt;/strong&gt; In the &amp;quot;Time &amp;amp; Loops&amp;quot; tab, you can set exactly when your audio starts and ends within the file. This is super handy if you only want to play a specific section of a song. Just drag the start and end markers on the waveform, or type in specific times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;6. Playing Your Cue&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;Go&amp;quot; Button:&lt;/strong&gt; The big &amp;quot;Go&amp;quot; button at the bottom of the QLab window is your best friend. Click it (or press the Spacebar, which is the default hotkey) to trigger the selected cue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop Button:&lt;/strong&gt; Need to stop a cue? Click the &amp;quot;Stop&amp;quot; button next to &amp;quot;Go.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What&#39;s Next?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just the tip of the iceberg with QLab, but understanding how to add and control basic audio cues is a huge first step. From here, you can explore:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fades:&lt;/strong&gt; Make your music fade in and out smoothly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cue Triggers:&lt;/strong&gt; How to automatically trigger cues, or link them to other cues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hotkeys:&lt;/strong&gt; Assigning keyboard shortcuts for quick playback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Groups:&lt;/strong&gt; Organizing multiple cues together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While QLab might seem a little intimidating at first glance, I promise you, once you start playing around with it, you&#39;ll quickly discover how powerful and genuinely &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt; it is. It truly opens up a world of possibilities for controlling your live events with precision and creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy cueing!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Essential Git: Part 2: Safely Undoing Changes with git revert</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Essential_Git_Revert/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Essential_Git_Revert/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Working with Git is fantastic for managing your code, but sometimes, you push changes you later realize aren&#39;t quite right.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe a feature introduced a bug, or a configuration change is causing problems. When this happens, &lt;code&gt;git revert&lt;/code&gt; comes to the rescue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a super important tool, especially when you&#39;ve already shared your work (like pushing to a remote repository or deploying to a service like Vercel).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;git revert&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, &lt;code&gt;git revert&lt;/code&gt; creates new commits that undo the changes from previous commits. It&#39;s like writing an &amp;quot;undo&amp;quot; commit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key difference from other Git commands like &lt;code&gt;git reset&lt;/code&gt; is that &lt;code&gt;git revert&lt;/code&gt; does not rewrite your project&#39;s history. Instead, it adds new history that cancels out the old. This makes it a much safer option when:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&#39;ve already pushed your commits to a shared remote repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&#39;re working on a public branch (like &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to maintain a clear, linear history of changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When to Use &lt;code&gt;git revert&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of &lt;code&gt;git revert&lt;/code&gt; as your go-to for &amp;quot;undoing&amp;quot; when:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&#39;ve pushed a bad commit:&lt;/strong&gt; This is exactly what we just experienced. If you have a commit causing issues on your live Vercel site, reverting it safely brings you back without erasing the fact that the commit ever existed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You want to undo specific commits in your history:&lt;/strong&gt; You can pick and choose which commits to undo, even if they&#39;re not the very last ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You need to collaborate:&lt;/strong&gt; Since it doesn&#39;t rewrite history, &lt;code&gt;git revert&lt;/code&gt; is polite to your teammates&#39; repositories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step-by-Step Tutorial: Reverting a Commit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s walk through how to use &lt;code&gt;git revert&lt;/code&gt; to undo a specific commit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 1: Identify the Commit to Revert&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, you need to find the commit hash (the unique ID) of the commit you want to undo. This should be the commit that introduced the changes you want to reverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open your terminal or Git Bash in your project&#39;s root directory and run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;git log


This command shows you your project&#39;s commit history, with the most recent commits at the top. Scroll down until you find the commit you want to undo. The commit hash is the long string of characters next to commit (e.g., 71a224ee41eec4599329bb65c893de855d441f62).
Once you&#39;ve found it, copy its full hash.



```markdown
#### Step 2: Perform the Revert

Now, use the `git revert` command with the commit hash you copied.

```bash
git revert &amp;lt;commit-hash&amp;gt;


Replace &amp;lt;commit-hash&amp;gt; with the actual hash.
What happens next?
Git will attempt to reverse the changes introduced by that commit.
If the revert is straightforward (no conflicts), Git will automatically prepare a new commit for you.
Step 3: Handle the Commit Message
When git revert prepares a new commit, it will automatically open your default Git editor (like Vim or Nano in the terminal, or potentially VS Code if configured) with a pre-filled commit message. This message typically starts with &amp;quot;Revert&amp;quot; and includes information about the commit you&#39;re undoing.
You can accept the default message as is.
You can add your own notes to explain why you&#39;re reverting.
To save and exit the commit message:
If it&#39;s Vim: Press the Esc key, then type :wq and press Enter.
If it&#39;s Nano, press Ctrl+X, then Y to confirm saving, and then press Enter.
Once you save and exit, Git will create the new &amp;quot;revert&amp;quot; commit.
Step 4: Push Your Reverted Changes
Finally, push your new revert commit to your remote repository (e.g., GitHub, GitLab, or Vercel).

Bash


git push


This will update your remote branch, and if you&#39;re using Vercel, it will trigger a new deployment with the reverted code.
Troubleshooting Common git revert Issues
Sometimes, git revert isn&#39;t a smooth ride. Here are the most common bumps you might hit and how to fix them:
Issue 1: Merge Conflicts (CONFLICT (content): Merge conflict in &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;)
This is what we faced! It means Git found changes in the commit you&#39;re reverting that overlap with other changes made since that commit. Git doesn&#39;t know which version to keep, so it asks you to decide.
How to fix it:
Identify the Conflict: Git will tell you which files have conflicts (e.g., script.js). Open these files in your code editor.
Look for Conflict Markers: Inside the conflicted file, you&#39;ll see special markers like this:
&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; HEAD
// Code from your current branch (your latest work)
=======
// Code from the commit you are trying to revert (the older version)
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;commit-hash-of-reverted-commit&amp;gt;





```markdown
    * **Manually Resolve:**
        * Delete the Git conflict markers (`&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;`, `=======`, `&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;`).
        * Edit the code within that section. Since you&#39;re trying to undo, you&#39;ll typically want to delete the code that was introduced by the commit you&#39;re reverting (the part between `=======` and `&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;`) and keep the `HEAD` version, or combine them as needed to achieve the desired state of the file without the problematic changes.
        * Save the file.

    * **Stage the Resolved File:** After fixing the file and saving it, you must tell Git that you&#39;ve resolved the conflict:

        ```bash
        git add &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;
        ```
        Example: `git add script.js`

    * **Complete the Revert Commit:** Now that the conflict is staged, you can finalize the revert:

        ```bash
        git commit
        ```
        This will open the commit message editor. Save and exit as in Step 3 of the main tutorial.



Markdown


#### Issue 2: &amp;quot;Nothing to commit&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;empty revert&amp;quot;

This message appears if the commit you&#39;re trying to revert doesn&#39;t actually introduce any new changes, or if those changes have already been undone by a subsequent commit. Git determines there&#39;s nothing to revert.

* **What to do:**
    * If you&#39;re sure there were changes, double-check your `git log` to ensure you picked the correct commit hash.
    * If the changes truly vanished or were undone, you might not need to do anything.

#### Issue 3: Reverting a Range of Commits

If you want to undo several commits in a sequence, you can specify a range:

```bash
git revert &amp;lt;FIRST_COMMIT_HASH&amp;gt;..&amp;lt;LAST_COMMIT_HASH&amp;gt;


This will revert each commit one by one. You might be prompted for a commit message for each revert, or you might hit merge conflicts for each.
You can add --no-edit to use the default message for each revert without opening the editor:
Bash
git revert --no-edit &amp;lt;FIRST_COMMIT_HASH&amp;gt;..&amp;lt;LAST_COMMIT_HASH&amp;gt;


Or --no-commit to stage all reverts as one single new commit, which is often cleaner:
Bash
git revert --no-commit &amp;lt;FIRST_COMMIT_HASH&amp;gt;..&amp;lt;LAST_COMMIT_HASH&amp;gt;
followed by a single git commit.



```markdown
#### Issue 4: You Need to Go Back to an Exact Past State, Not Just Undo Specific Commits

Sometimes, you don&#39;t just want to undo specific commits, but instead completely reset your branch to how it looked at a previous point in history, discarding everything that came after. This is where `git reset --hard` comes in.

**WARNING:** `git reset --hard` rewrites history. If you&#39;ve pushed these commits, using `git reset --hard` followed by `git push --force` will cause problems for collaborators who have the older history. Only use this if you are absolutely sure you are the sole contributor or can coordinate with your team.

* **How to do it (use with extreme caution):**
    * **Find the desired commit hash:** Use `git log` to find the commit hash of the exact state you want your branch to be in.
    * **Reset locally:**
        ```bash
        git reset --hard &amp;lt;commit-hash&amp;gt;
        ```
    * **Force Push:**
        ```bash
        git push --force
        ```

`git revert` is a powerful and safe way to manage your project&#39;s history. Understanding how to use it, especially for handling conflicts, will save you a lot of headaches in your development journey!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Essential Git: Part 1</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Essential_Git%20part_1/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Essential_Git%20part_1/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Your Essential Git Toolkit: A Friendly Guide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git can seem a bit intimidating at first, but it&#39;s just a system to help you keep track of changes in your code (or any files, for that matter) and collaborate smoothly. Think of it as a super-powered save button with a memory of every single change you&#39;ve ever made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s dive into the commands you&#39;ll use most often:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. &lt;code&gt;git status&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you use it:&lt;/strong&gt; Before you do anything else, you&#39;ll want to know what&#39;s going on. &lt;code&gt;git status&lt;/code&gt; tells you which files you&#39;ve changed, which ones are new, and whether anything is ready to be saved. It&#39;s your quick check-in to see the current state of your working directory compared to your last saved version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How you use it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# Check the current status of your Git repository
git status
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
This command will give you a clear rundown of your changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. &lt;code&gt;git add .&lt;/code&gt; (or &lt;code&gt;git add &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you use it:&lt;/strong&gt; When you make changes to your files, Git doesn&#39;t automatically track them for your next save. You need to explicitly tell Git which changes you want to include in your next &amp;quot;snapshot&amp;quot; (called a commit). Using &lt;code&gt;git add .&lt;/code&gt; is a common shortcut to add all modified and new files in your current directory and its subdirectories to the &amp;quot;staging area.&amp;quot; If you only want to add a specific file, you&#39;d use &lt;code&gt;git add &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How you use it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# To stage all modified and new files in the current directory and subdirectories
git add .

# To stage only a specific file
git add my-new-feature.js
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
You&#39;ll often run &lt;code&gt;git status&lt;/code&gt; right after this to confirm what you&#39;ve staged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. &lt;code&gt;git commit -m &amp;quot;Your descriptive message here&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you use it:&lt;/strong&gt; A commit is a snapshot of your project at a specific point in time. It&#39;s like taking a picture of your entire project&#39;s state. The &lt;code&gt;-m&lt;/code&gt; flag lets you add a short, descriptive message about what changes you made in that commit. Good commit messages are essential – they help you (and others) understand the history of your project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How you use it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# Create a new commit with a descriptive message
git commit -m &amp;quot;Add user login functionality and fix button styling&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Make sure your message is clear and concise!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. &lt;code&gt;git push origin main&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you use it:&lt;/strong&gt; After you&#39;ve committed your changes locally, they&#39;re only on your computer. To share them with others or to back them up on a remote server (like GitHub, GitLab, or Bitbucket), you use &lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code&gt;origin&lt;/code&gt; typically refers to the default remote repository where your project lives online, and &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; is the name of the branch you&#39;re pushing to (it used to be called &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;, but &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; is the new standard).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How you use it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;# Push your committed changes from your local &#39;main&#39; branch to the &#39;origin&#39; remote
git push origin main
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
If you&#39;re working on a different branch, you&#39;d replace &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; with your branch name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Few Extra Tips!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Branches are your friends:&lt;/strong&gt; While we focused on the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch today, Git is fantastic because you can create &amp;quot;branches&amp;quot; for new features or bug fixes. This lets you work on something new without messing up the main, stable version of your project. Once your work is ready, you can merge it back into the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&#39;t be afraid to experiment:&lt;/strong&gt; Git is designed to be undo-friendly. If you make a mistake, there&#39;s usually a way to fix it. That&#39;s why it&#39;s so great!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practice makes perfect:&lt;/strong&gt; The more you use these commands, the more natural they&#39;ll feel. Try creating a small test project and just playing around with making changes, adding, committing, and pushing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps you feel more comfortable jumping into the world of Git! It&#39;s an incredibly valuable tool for anyone working with code. Happy coding!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Welcome to the Blog</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/my_first_post/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/my_first_post/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Welcome! I&#39;m New Here (And I Have No Idea What I&#39;m Doing)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I did it. I finally have a new online home. Welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, this space is a bit like me on a Monday morning: a work in progress, slightly confused, but full of potential. I&#39;m busy behind the scenes, untangling the technical knots and figuring out how all this stuff works. (If you hear faint screaming, it&#39;s just me trying to center an image.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be adding all my previously posted articles here soon, they will show up eventually. More importantly, I&#39;ve got some new ideas I&#39;m excited to share with you once I&#39;m sure I won&#39;t accidentally delete the entire internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, have a look around, don&#39;t mind the occasional digital pothole, and thanks for being here at the very beginning. Let&#39;s get this show on the road!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Case of the Persistent Contact Form: A Debugging Odyssey</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/contact_form/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/contact_form/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h3&gt;The Case of the Persistent Contact Form: A Debugging Odyssey&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey tech enthusiasts and fellow web wranglers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever stared at a seemingly simple feature – like a contact ofrm – and wondered why it&#39;s putting up such a fight? Well, I recently went on an epic debugging adventure with my own website&#39;s contact form, and let me tell you, it was a journey filled with unexpected twists, a few head-scratching moments, and ultimately, a satisfying victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re currently wrestling with a stubborn form, a missing CAPTCHA,. Email notifications that just won&#39;t trigger, you might find some solace (and hopefully some solutions!) in my tale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**The Initial Setup (Seemed Simple Enough!) **&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal was straightforward: a clean, effective contact form on my personal site, protected by a CAPTCHA to ward off those pesky bots, and set up to send me an email whenever someone reached out. I opted for Netlify to host my static site, Cloudflare Turnstile for a user-friendly CAPTCHA, and Resend for reliable email delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial setup involved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crafting the HTML form. * Writing a Netlify serverless function in JavaScript to handle the form submission, CAPTCHA verification, and email sending via Resend. * Adding a sprinkle of client-side JavaScript for form validation and submission handling. * Configuring environment variables in Netlify for API keys and secrets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds reasonable, right? That&#39;s what I thought too...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Signs of Trouble (and the Rabbit Hole)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, the site looked great (thanks to Tailwind CSS. A cool three.js background animation – another story for another time!). But the contact form? Radio silence. No CAPTCHA widget, and definitely no emails landing in my inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where the debugging adventure truly began. What followed was a deep idve into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Browser Developer Tools (My Best Friend!) **: Console logs became my daily bread, and network requests my guiding stars. We meticulously checked for JavaScript errors, failed API calls, and Content Security Policy violations. * &lt;strong&gt;Netlify Deployment Logs&lt;/strong&gt;: Scrutinizing every stage of the build and deployment process became crucial to ensure our serverless function was being included correctly. * &lt;strong&gt;Cloudflare Turnstile Dashboard&lt;/strong&gt;: Double-checking site keys, secret kyes, and even experimenting with different settings. * &lt;strong&gt;Resend Logs&lt;/strong&gt;: Monitoring email sending attempts to see if the requests were even reaching the service. What the responses were. * &lt;strong&gt;HTTP Headers (The Silent Guardians)&lt;/strong&gt;: We spent a surprising amount of time wrestling with the &lt;code&gt;netlify.toml&lt;/code&gt; file and its security headers, learning firsthand how a misconfigured policy can block essential resources. * &lt;strong&gt;Environment Variables (The Keepers of Secrets)&lt;/strong&gt;: Ensuring API keys were correctly stored and accessed by our Netlify function. * &lt;strong&gt;Branching and Deployment Contexts&lt;/strong&gt;: Briefly suspected we might be working on the wrong version of the site!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Learnings and Aha! Moments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this process, several key learnings emerged:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Order Matters&lt;/strong&gt;: In our &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt;, the order in which scripts were loaded (especially Three.js and our main &lt;code&gt;script.js&lt;/code&gt;) had a significant impact on whether the page rendered correctly. * **Security is Paramount (and Tricky!) **: Content Security Policy is a powerful tool, but it requires careful configuration to avoid unintentionally blocking legitimate resources like third-party CAPTCHA scripts and analytics. * &lt;strong&gt;Serverless Functions Can Be Elusive&lt;/strong&gt;: Debugging server-side code running in a cloud environment requires a different mindset than local development. Netlify&#39;s function logs and the ability to download deployed functions became invaluable. * &lt;strong&gt;Deployment Consistency is Key&lt;/strong&gt;: We encountered situations where local code wasn&#39;t making its way to the deployed site as expected, highlighting the importance of proper Git practices. * &lt;strong&gt;Every Error Message is a Breadcrumb&lt;/strong&gt;: Even cryptic error messages in the browser console or network logs provide valuable clues if you know where to look and how to interpret them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**The Sweet Taste of Success (Finally!) **&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After what felt like countless iterations, meticulous log analysis, and a few moments of pure frustration, we finally cracked the code! The issues ranged from a missing Three.js script tag, overly restrictive security policies, and even ensuring the correct version of our Netlify function was being deployed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moment the CAPTCHA widget appeared, the form started submitting correctly, and those email notifications began landing in my inbox was incredibly rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tips for Your Own Debugging Adventures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re facing similar challenges with your contact form or website features, here are a few takeaways from my experience:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be Patient and Systematic&lt;/strong&gt;: Debugging often involves trial and error, but a systematic approach of checking logs, isolating variables, and making small, incremental changes is crucial. * &lt;strong&gt;Leverage Your Browser&#39;s Developer Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Become comfortable with the Console, Network, and Security tabs. They provide a wealth of information. * **Read the Documentation (Carefully!) **: The documentation for services like Netlify, Cloudflare Turnstile, and Resend is your best friend. Pay close attention to configuration instructions and common troubleshooting steps. * &lt;strong&gt;Don&#39;t Be Afraid to Ask for Help&lt;/strong&gt;: Online communities and forums can be incredibly valuable resources when you&#39;re stuck. Clearly explaining your problem and what you&#39;ve tried so far will help others assist you. * &lt;strong&gt;Celebrate the Small Victories&lt;/strong&gt;: Debugging can be mentally taxing. Acknowldege and celberate each step forward, no matter how small.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Journey Continues...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this particular debugging odyssey has reached its conclusion, the world of web development is constantly evolving. There will always be new challenges to overcome and new things to learn. And that, in itself, is part of the adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why I Chose Eleventy for My Blog (And How I Secured It)</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Eleventy_for_My_Blog/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Eleventy_for_My_Blog/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h4&gt;After getting my main portfolio site into a stable, secure state, I decided it was time to add a blog.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My core requirements were simple but non-negotiable: it had to be modern, straightforward to maintain, and—most importantly—built in a way that couldn&#39;t possibly break my main portfolio site during development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This led me down the path of creating a completely separate, standalone blog site. Here’s a look at the &amp;quot;why&amp;quot; behind the tools I chose and the security precautions we took along the way. Why Eleventy? The &amp;quot;Keep It Simple&amp;quot; Philosophy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today&#39;s landscape of complex JavaScript frameworks, I was looking for something simpler. After some research, I landed on Eleventy (11ty), a modern Static Site Generator (SSG).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the perfect choice for a few key reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simplicity and Flexibility: Eleventy doesn&#39;t lock you into a heavy framework like React or Vue. It&#39;s incredibly flexible and un-opinionated, letting you work with simple templates and data. This felt perfect for a straightforward, content-focused blog. JavaScript-Based: The entire configuration is done in plain JavaScript (.eleventy.js), which felt comfortable and accessible. There was no need to learn a new programming language just to build a blog. Peak Performance &amp;amp; Security: By default, Eleventy generates pre-built, static HTML files. This means there&#39;s no database to hack and no complex server-side code running on every page view. The result is a site that is incredibly fast and secure right out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A Security-First Approach&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A static site is secure by default, but I wanted to take it a step further and ensure it was hardened against modern web vulnerabilities. The main tool for this was Netlify.toml file placed at the root of the project, which allowed me to define custom HTTP security headers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the key security layers we implemented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Content Security Policy (CSP): The Digital Bouncer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important header we added was a strong Content Security Policy. Think of a CSP as a bouncer for your website—it maintains a strict guest list of all the resources (scripts, styles, fonts, etc.) that are allowed to load on the page. Anything not on the list gets blocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My policy explicitly whitelists trusted sources for each type of content:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;script-src: Only allows scripts from my domain and the trusted Tailwind CSS CDN.
style-src: Only allows stylesheets from my domain and Google Fonts.
font-src: Only allows fonts to be downloaded from Google&#39;s font servers (fonts.gstatic.com).
object-src &#39;none&#39;: Completely blocks older, insecure plugins like Flash from ever running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &#39;unsafe-inline&#39; Caveat: The one necessary compromise was allowing &#39;unsafe-inline&#39; for styles. This was required for the Tailwind CSS CDN script to work, as it dynamically injects styles into the page. However, the risk is heavily mitigated because the rest of the policy still locks down the overall source of any scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Other Essential Headers:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the CSP, we added several other headers for a layered defense:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strict-Transport-Security (HSTS): Ensures that browsers only ever communicate with my site over a secure HTTPS connection. X-Frame-Options: Set to DENY, this completely prevents my site from being embedded in an iframe on another website, which is the primary defense against &amp;quot;clickjacking&amp;quot; attacks. Permissions Policy: This is a modern header that allows me to lock down browser features that my blog has no reason to use, such as the microphone, camera, USB devices, and payment APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Result:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The outcome is exactly what I was hoping for: a fast, modern blog with an A+ security rating that is completely decoupled from my main portfolio. The workflow is simple—I write a post in a Markdown file, push it to GitHub, and Netlify handles the rest. It’s a setup I can trust while I focus on writing content and my job search.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Tell-Tale Cliché: Why &#39;Chess, Not Checkers&#39; Misses the Mark</title>
    <link href="https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Are_You_Playing_Chess_V2/"/>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://blog.beaubremer.com/posts/Are_You_Playing_Chess_V2/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;p&gt;You know the moment. You’re in a meeting or just scrolling online, and someone drops the line to signal they&#39;re operating on a higher strategic plane: &amp;quot;I&#39;m playing chess, not checkers&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s meant to be a mic drop, a declaration of unseen genius. But the phrase has two problems: it’s a borrowed line, and more importantly, it’s based on a fundamental misunderstanding of checkers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Game You&#39;re Insulting&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The popular view treats chess as the undisputed king of strategy while dismissing checkers as a simple child&#39;s game. This gets it wrong. While the rules of checkers are straightforward, the strategic depth is immense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key rule, which &lt;strong&gt;forces a player to make a capture if one is available&lt;/strong&gt;, creates profound tactical possibilities not seen in chess. Skilled players use this to set intricate traps, sacrificing pieces to manipulate an opponent into a losing position many moves down the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game’s complexity is staggering. The number of possible board positions is estimated to be around &lt;strong&gt;500 billion billion&lt;/strong&gt;. That&#39;s 5 x 10^20, a number so huge it&#39;s hard to wrap my head around it. When computer scientists famously &amp;quot;solved&amp;quot; the game in 2007, the computational power required was monumental. Their proof that perfect play from both sides results in a draw is a testament to the game&#39;s vastness, not its simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A Master of a Complex World&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the domain of legends like Dr. Marion Tinsley, a mathematics professor and arguably the greatest checkers player who ever lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over a 45-year career, Tinsley lost a total of seven games and once notably defeated a top computer program. He was a quiet genius who demonstrated a level of strategic mastery that few could comprehend. If anyone was playing a game of cosmic complexity, it was the man who achieved near-perfection in checkers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Irony of a Borrowed Boast&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings us to the irony of the person using the cliché.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They’re using a hand-me-down line&lt;/strong&gt; to claim originality, often channeling Denzel Washington in &lt;em&gt;Training Day&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They&#39;re trying to sound smart&lt;/strong&gt; by punching down on a game of incredible depth they clearly don&#39;t understand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Real strategic thinking doesn’t need a catchphrase. It’s understated, deliberate, and proven through action and clarity, not announcement. The smartest people in the room don&#39;t have to tell you they&#39;re playing a different game; you can see it in their results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let your work and ideas do the talking. Play your own game, and leave the stale clichés to the parrots.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>